<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Special_Coverage </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/102775</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Behold this futuristic and gorgeous Library in Tianjin ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288606</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288606.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 16:45:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/11/3/f6af08b0-be5e-43ef-8015-4ddbcda5767a.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1103/FOREIGN201711031639000146894379062.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 455px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Behold this futuristic and gorgeous Library in Tianjin</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ A new era for China is here and why it matters ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287993</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287993.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 13:55:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/11/2/5ede80fe-9e05-47ab-a31f-c7ead6fede74.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p> Xi Jinping delivered an important report to the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on October 18, which will guide the Party and the nation for the next five years and beyond. One thing that stood out was that China had entered a “new era.” Socialism with Chinese characteristics has crossed the threshold into a new era, Xi said.</p> <p> The reason why this is a new era is because China has made remarkable achievements. China has become a global leader in terms of economic and technological strength, defense capabilities, and comprehensive national strength. China has lifted more than 700 million people out of poverty since the launch of reform and opening up some 40 years ago, and the goal of building a moderately prosperous society is well within reach. In less than 70 years, the People’s Republic of China has stood up, grown rich, and become strong.</p> <p> The start of a new era indicates that a more confident and aspirant China will begin to embark on a new journey from a fresh starting point. But the judgment is also grounded on the evolution of the main contradiction facing Chinese society. In this new era, the Party aims to solve the contradiction between unbalanced and inadequate development and the people’s ever-growing needs for a better life by adopting a more comprehensive and balanced development approach.</p> <p> Xi outlined two stages for national modernization. In the first stage from 2020 to 2035, the Party will build on the foundation created by the moderately prosperous society with a further 15 years of hard work to basically realize socialist modernization. In the second stage from 2035 to the middle of the 21st century, the Party will work hard for a further 15 years and develop China into a great modern socialist country that is prosperous, strong, democratic, culturally advanced, harmonious, and beautiful.</p> <p> China’s entry into a new era is also why all eyes are on Beijing. As Xi pointed out, “No country can alone address the challenges facing the world today.” To build a new type of international relations with win-win cooperation at the core, Xi said that China will hold high the banner of peace, development, and win-win cooperation, maintain world peace and promote common development, and develop friendly cooperation with all countries on the basis of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence.</p> <p> China's rise should be seen as a huge opportunity rather than a challenge. China is committed to promoting an open economy and free trade, and in the process, the world will be introduced to more Chinese solutions for global problems. China is a rising tide that is lifting all boats. In many ways, China's future is the world's future.</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711021338000127404690262.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 454px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> A new era for China is here and why it matters</p> <p> &nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Unveil China Outside China: How does China move closer to the world center? ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287979</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287979.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 13:32:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/11/2/32cc98d5-4f7a-421e-be96-62109ab8d4f9.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p> As a Chinese diplomat with rich experience of almost 40 years, Luo Linquan, Consul General of People’s Republic of China in San Francisco, has witnessed how China steps closer to center stage in the world. From the evacuation of Chinese nationals after the outbreak of the civil war in Libya to China’s presidential visits to the United States, Luo shares his story in 4 minutes.</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711021331000131285274355.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 439px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> Unveil China Outside China: How does China move closer to the world center?</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Op-Ed: Yep, the world has a new role model for political and economic development ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287973</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287973.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 12:53:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711021249000300510371643.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 601px;" /></p> <p> Is America still the world’s role model? More people are making the argument that America is no longer the world’s role model. But others such as Martin Dempsey, a retired US general who served as the 18th Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff, still hold onto the belief that the US, and only the US, can light the world: “Heard China claims to be ‘role model’ for the world. Nope. The world has a role model. Unless we talk ourselves out of it,” he recently wrote on Twitter.</p> <p> Judging by the responses, many are skeptical about this claim. “Psst: We’re not currently the world role-model,” one user commented. “We are a laughing stock,” a different user wrote. “To this observer America looks like a role model for a deeply corrupt democracy descending into civil war,” Margo Kingston, a retired political journalist, commented. “Pretty sure the rest of the world is striving NOT to be anything like US,” another user wrote.</p> <p> The largely negative responses are not necessarily an accurate reflection of overall public opinion, but they do point to a larger truth, one that is becoming increasingly clear in this new era of world politics. That is, whether or not the US actually remains a good role model for the world, people increasingly believe that the US is, at the very least, no longer the world’s only role model. This is in part because of the decline of the US and, in part, because of the rise of China.</p> <p> While the US still has an important role to play in this new era, some people are not exactly echoing Dempsey’s position. Fareed Zakaria, who writes a foreign affairs column for The Washington Post, said that the Chinese model has become an “alternative” model. And John Kelly, the current White House Chief of Staff for US President Donald Trump, recently acknowledged in an interview that China is “another world power.” From online comments to the highest levels of the US government, a coherent message is forming: the world does not just revolve around the West anymore.</p> <p> And it is not hard to see why. China’s ruling party has lifted hundreds of millions of people out of poverty and created a thriving middle class, transforming the world’s most populous country into one of the world’s most powerful in record time. At the same time, China is helping other countries rise with game-changing initiatives such as the Belt and Road. The reality is that China is moving forward and closer to center stage. Meanwhile, the US appears to be turning toward isolationism and protectionism.</p> <p> All of which, of course, means that China can light the world too. At the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China, President Xi Jinping said that the path, the theory, the system, and the culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics have kept developing, blazing a new trail for other developing countries to achieve modernization. It offers a new option for other countries and nations who want to speed up their development while preserving their independence; and it offers Chinese wisdom and a Chinese approach to solving the problems facing mankind.</p> <p> Also as stated in the 19th CPC National Congress report, China remains firmly committed to building a new type of international relations featuring mutual respect, fairness, justice, and win-win cooperation.</p> <p> China does not need to claim to be a role model for the world, because the advantages of the Chinese model are being increasingly recognized around the world – and at a time when the disadvantages of the American model are being highlighted. So whether one wants to admit it or not, a new role model is in town.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's report to the 19th CPC National Congress published ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285959</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1028/c90000-9285959.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 09:44:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- The report delivered by Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, to the 19th CPC National Congress on Oct.18, has been published by People's Publishing House. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- The report delivered by Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, to the 19th CPC National Congress on Oct.18, has been published by People's Publishing House.</p> <p> The report, "Secure a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects and strive for the great success of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era," was available at Xinhua Bookstores across the country from Friday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Top CPC leadership hailed as Dream Team for China’s New Era ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285324</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285324.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 15:40:00 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1026/FOREIGN201710261415000171824381200.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 607px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng arrive to meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Ma Zhancheng)</em></p> <p> China’s top leaders are elected for their experience and ability to lead. As socialism with Chinese characteristics enters a new era, the Chinese people know they are in good hands, and their support for the new leadership shows that the Communist Party of China is doing what the people hope for: helping the people achieve a better life and leading them to realize the Chinese dream of national rejuvenation. This is why the new top leadership of the CPC is now being called the Dream Team for China’s New Era.</p> <p> The Dream Team for the New Era is made up of high-quality, experienced leaders who put the people first. They are: <strong><a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9285018.html" target="_blank">Xi Jinping</a></strong>, President of China, General Secretary of the CPC Central Committee, and Chairman of the CPC Central Military Commission; <strong><a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9285020.html" target="_blank">Li Keqiang</a></strong>, currently Premier of the State Council; <a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285198.html" target="_blank"><strong>Li Zhanshu</strong></a>, currently Director of the General Office of the CPC Central Committee;<a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285193.html" target="_blank"><strong> Wang Yang</strong></a>, currently Vice-Premier of China; <a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285194.html" target="_blank"><strong>Wang Huning</strong></a>, currently Director of the Policy Research Office of the CPC Central Committee;<a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285196.html" target="_blank"><strong> Zhao Leji</strong></a>, currently Head of the Organization Department of the CPC Central Committee; and <a href="http://en.people.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285197.html" target="_blank"><strong>Han Zheng</strong></a>, currently Secretary of the CPC Shanghai Municipal Committee.<em> [Click the name of each leader for their biographical sketch]</em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1026/FOREIGN201710261416000043433310206.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 599px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping(C), general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang (3rd R), Li Zhanshu (3rd L), Wang Yang (2nd R), Wang Huning (2nd L), Zhao Leji (1st R) and Han Zheng, meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p> In addition to the quality and dedication of those elected, the goals and plans set at and the message from the 19th National Congress of the CPC resonates with the larger interests of the people, and Chinese are more confident than ever that a better future is on the horizon. “I love you because of what you do for China,” wrote one netizen.</p> <p> A lot of this excitement and confidence is reflected online, and this shows that the Chinese people appreciate and support the Party’s efforts. On the Chinese-language version of the WeChat account of the People’s Daily, some comments received thousands of upvotes. In an article that announced the new top leadership, one comment received some 13,000 upvotes in just a few minutes: “The world’s strongest team,” it said. Other comments received thousands of upvotes too: “Day one of China’s team,” 6,800 likes. “New era, new journey,” 3,900 likes. “The most awesome team,” 3,500 likes. “The world’s greatest super team! My motherland is incredible,” a netizen wrote on the Weibo account of the People’s Daily. A similar article on the People’s Daily Overseas Edition social media account Xiakedao got more than 100,000 views in just eight minutes.</p> <p> In response to an article on the English-language website of the People’s Daily Online, one reader wrote that the high percentage of UN member countries sending messages of congratulation to the Communist Party of China speaks well of China in the international arena. “This is due mainly to the credit of President Xi Jinping and his team for their outstanding performance,” the reader wrote.</p> <p> The Dream Team for the New Era has excited people in China and around the world. Raza Khan, a correspondent of Dawn News in Pakistan who covered the debut of the new leadership at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, said Xi Jinping has clear targets, a roadmap, and a way forward. Even US President Donald Trump congratulated Xi on being re-elected the general secretary of the CPC Central Committee. All of which is evidence that support for the Party and its mission is strong. “This ‘Dream Team’, which is leading hundreds of millions of people to national rejuvenation, has opened a new chapter for a new era, and started a new journey of dream revival,” the People’s Daily wrote in a Chinese-language report.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Central Commission for Discipline Inspection of CPC holds first plenary session ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285189</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285189.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:05:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1026/FOREIGN201710260907000039325745901.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 545px;" /></p> <p> The Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) of the Communist Party of China (CPC) elected at the 19th CPC National Congress holds its first plenary session in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Yao Dawei)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China Focus: New CPC leadership for new era ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285080</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285080.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 08:31:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The Communist Party of China (CPC) unveiled a new leadership line-up Wednesday to lead the world's most populous nation toward a great modern socialist country. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1026/FOREIGN201710260829000127836429287.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 599px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping(C), general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang (3rd R), Li Zhanshu (3rd L), Wang Yang (2nd R), Wang Huning (2nd L), Zhao Leji (1st R) and Han Zheng, meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, Oct. 25 -- The Communist Party of China (CPC) unveiled a new leadership line-up Wednesday to lead the world's most populous nation toward a great modern socialist country.</p> <p> Xi Jinping was again elected general secretary of the CPC Central Committee, leading its seven-seat Political Bureau Standing Committee.</p> <p> The other six members of the top leadership are Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng.</p> <p> They were elected at the first plenum of the 19th CPC Central Committee following the 19th CPC National Congress, a new historic starting point for the Party to realize its ambitious blueprint for the nation's great revival.</p> <p> During the twice-a-decade congress which concluded Tuesday, the CPC declared a "new era" of socialism with Chinese characteristics. It enshrined Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era into the CPC Constitution as a new component of the Party's action guide.</p> <p> Xi was elected general secretary of the CPC Central Committee for the first time at the first plenum of the 18th CPC Central Committee in late 2012.</p> <p> At a key plenum of the CPC Central Committee in 2016, Xi's status as the Party's core was endorsed.</p> <p> Before him, Mao Zedong, Deng Xiaoping and Jiang Zemin had been given the core status.</p> <p> The new CPC leaders who took the stage Wednesday are the helmsmen leading the Chinese toward the country's new era goals of basically realizing socialist modernization by 2035 and building a great modern socialist country by the middle of this century.</p> <p> "The leadership reshuffle of the CPC, the world's biggest political party, is an answer to the needs of the Party and the nation for the development of their causes," said Yang Fengcheng, professor at Renmin University of China and a researcher on CPC history.</p> <p> "The new CPC leaders are good at learning and bold in practice," said Yang, who is also chief editor of the book "Keys to the Success of the Communist Party of China."</p> <p> For the first time, all Standing Committee members of the Political Bureau were born after the founding of the People's Republic of China in 1949.</p> <p> They began their political careers around the time of the launch of reform and opening up in 1978, which imprinted them with the mark of the era when China's economy began to take off, following a decade of turmoil during the Cultural Revolution (1966-1976).</p> <p> As a staunch reformist, Xi has launched more than 1,500 reform measures over the past five years -- unprecedented in their coverage and depth.</p> <p> The other six Standing Committee members have also been active practitioners of reform and opening up policies.</p> <p> Either at the central government or the local level, all members have driven an array of major reforms, explored theories, and solved deep-rooted problems with open minds, foresight and innovative thinking.</p> <p> The new leaders are widely seen as having firm ideals and convictions, strong loyalty to the Party and deep love for the country.</p> <p> All of them have received higher education and demonstrated in-depth understanding of philosophy and strategic thinking, with a relatively high level of theoretical thinking. Many have published academic papers, or even books, during their careers.</p> <p> The seven leaders have accumulated rich experience in practice. They are viewed as having a good sense of the times and caring about the people.</p> <p> Xi, for example, started his political career 44 years ago. Over the past five years, he has spent 151 days on 50 local inspection tours around the country.</p> <p> Other leaders also have extensive experience working at the grassroots level and have been promoted to senior posts due to their excellent performance and good reputations.</p> <p> Most of the seven leaders have worked in both well-off coastal areas in the east and less-developed central and western regions.</p> <p> A number of them have played pivotal roles in the fight against poverty and successfully tackled difficult and risky issues in the fields of economic development, people's welfare, urban management, the anti-corruption campaign and industrial transformation.</p> <p> Moreover, the new leaders have a deeper understanding of opening up and win-win development, with broader global vision and abundant experience in dealing with international issues.</p> <p> For the past five years, the CPC leadership has been seen as a major driving force behind economic globalization.</p> <p> "The new CPC leadership is a strong, goal-oriented team with acute awareness of problems and the ability to stand firm in practice," said Han Qingxiang, a professor at the Party School of the CPC Central Committee.</p> <p> "They have been flexible and at the same time principled when dealing with problems. They have never forgotten why they started and have always pressed forward in the face of challenges at home and abroad," he noted.</p> <p> Chen Yiwei, a delegate to the congress, is full of hope.</p> <p> "The new leaders have rich experience and a strong sense of responsibility," he said. "I believe that with the guidance of the latest achievement in adapting Marxism to the Chinese context, they can lead the Party and the nation to blaze new trails, overcome difficulties and accomplish the glorious missions in the new era."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Op-ed: World seeks clues on China’s future path from 19th CPC National Congress ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284851</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284851.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 15:15:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The rest of the world began a new round of speculation when the Communist Party of China (CPC) opened its 19th National Congress last week, which seemed to fit a comment from President Xi Jinping about China being like a big guy in a crowd, with others around him wondering just what the big guy will do next. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251513000526533515900.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 616px;" /></p> <p> The rest of the world began a new round of speculation when the Communist Party of China (CPC) opened its 19th National Congress last week, which seemed to fit a comment from President Xi Jinping about China being like a big guy in a crowd, with others around him wondering just what the big guy will do next.</p> <p> “Why is China’s governing system functioning well? The interesting part is the congress itself rather than its results. It is a key factor of the governance system of this exceptional power,” was how an article from the Russian news agency RIA Novosti saw it on Oct. 17, a day ahead of the opening of the 19th CPC National Congress.</p> <p> The headline of the article was “CPC National Congress--the Reason China Achieved Soviet Union’s Unfulfilled Goal.”</p> <p> Further proof that the 19th CPC National Congress was a global, historical event was a record number of overseas journalists -- 1,818 – in Beijing reporting on the congress and the continuous coverage by foreign media of the agenda, and the “simultaneous” discussions by overseas and domestic media on reports from the Congress.</p> <p> Now, even China’s cultural, ecological, and social policies, seemingly only domestic matters, have at the same time become the focus of international media -- a reflection of China’s position in the international system.</p> <p> The world was also looking for clues on how China will relate to the world in the future by following economic signals sent by the congress closely, with people seeming to believe that a more open Chinese economy means benefits for the globe.</p> <p> Not to be left out, foreign diplomats joined the choir, forecasting China’s future moves and the global order by analyzing such concepts as the new type of international relations and a community with shared future for mankind that Xi emphasized.</p> <p> Even though the ideas may differ, most countries seemed to share the same feeling that China is in a historical moment, “growing stronger” while the world expects this “stronger” to play a role in bringing them gain and justice.</p> <p> Foreign media outlets such as Bloomberg and CNN, noted that the report made on the National Congress emphasized that China would not replicate the systems of other countries since it has had such a huge success with socialism with Chinese characteristics.</p> <p> From a historical point of view, what makes the China experience special is that it develops by sticking to its own path. At the same time, that success has given confidence to more developing countries.</p> <p> Xi said in his report that socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era means that the path, the theory, the system, and the culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics have kept developing, blazing a new trail for other developing countries to achieve modernization. It offers a new option for other countries and nations who want to speed up their development while preserving their independence; and it offers Chinese wisdom and a Chinese approach to solving the problems facing mankind.</p> <p> Discovery Channel aired a three-part documentary, titled China: Time of Xi, ahead of the 19th CPC National Congress. Vikram Channa, its producer, noted that “in the dialogue on a new vision for the world, China’s perspective is more important than ever because of its unique journey, transformation and impact over the last 40 years.”</p> <p> This new era of socialism with Chinese characteristics will be one that sees China moving closer to the world’s center stage and making a greater contribution to mankind and, as a result, the world has every reason to look forward to a new era.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi: CPC to build mighty nationwide force driving China's development ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284801</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284801.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 14:28:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Communist Party of China (CPC) will generate waves of positive energy which can build into a mighty and nationwide force driving China's development and progress, said Xi Jinping, general secretary of the CPC Central Committee, on Wednesday.</p> <p> Xi made the remarks as he led other members of the Standing Committee of the 19th CPC Central Committee Political Bureau to meet the press at the Great Hall of the People.</p> <p> "We must continue to rid ourselves of any virus that erodes the Party's fabric, make great efforts to foster a healthy political environment of integrity, and generate waves of positive energy throughout our Party," Xi said.</p> <p> The CPC will mark its centenary in 2021.</p> <p> "For a party which fights for the eternal wellbeing of the Chinese nation, the centenary only ushers in the prime of life," Xi said. "As the world's largest political party, the CPC must behave in a way commensurate with this status."</p> <p> "Its history makes it abundantly clear that the CPC is capable of not only spearheading a great social revolution, but also imposing a great reform on itself," he said. "We, as its members, must always have a youthful spirit, and forever be the servants of the people, the vanguard of the times and the backbone of our nation."</p> <p> "Exercising full and rigorous governance over the Party is a journey to which there is no end. We should never entertain the idea of taking a breather or halting our steps," he said.</p> <p> Xi stressed the significant role of the people.</p> <p> "The people are the creators of history. It is to them that we owe all our achievements," he said. "As long as we firmly align ourselves with the people and rely on them, we can and will have boundless energy to forge ahead, come rain or shine."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi presents new CPC central leadership ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284692</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284692.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 14:09:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251309000133507026054.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 451px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), speaks when meeting the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. Xi Jinping and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng met the press on Wednesday. (Xinhua/Xie Huanchi)</em></p> <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), presented the Party's new central leadership when meeting the press Wednesday at the Great Hall of the People.</p> <p> "I was re-elected general secretary of the CPC Central Committee. I see this as not just approval of my work, but also encouragement that will spur me on," Xi told journalists.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251335000487897760221.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping(C), general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang (3rd R), Li Zhanshu (3rd L), Wang Yang (2nd R), Wang Huning (2nd L), Zhao Leji (1st R) and Han Zheng, meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p> He presented the other six newly elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee: Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng.</p> <p> Li Keqiang served on the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 18th CPC Central Committee, while all the others were members of the Political Bureau of the 18th CPC Central Committee, Xi said.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251336000336578774246.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 405px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng arrive to meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Ma Zhancheng)</em></p> <p> "Here, on behalf of the newly elected central leadership, I wish to express our heartfelt thanks to all other members of the Party for the trust they have placed in us," he said.</p> <p> "We will work diligently to meet our duty, fulfill our mission and be worthy of their trust," Xi said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi presents new CPC central leadership ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284726</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284726.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 14:08:23 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251319000013863849344.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 676px;" /></p> <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), speaks when meeting the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. Xi Jinping and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng met the press on Wednesday. (Xinhua/Xie Huanchi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251319000168377291836.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 599px;" /></p> <p> Xi Jinping(C), general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang (3rd R), Li Zhanshu (3rd L), Wang Yang (2nd R), Wang Huning (2nd L), Zhao Leji (1st R) and Han Zheng, meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251320000012655263570.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 607px;" /></p> <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng arrive to meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Ma Zhancheng)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Egypt launches largest trade fair for Chinese investors ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284734</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284734.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:36:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251325000106670164790.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p> <em>Egyptian and Chinese traders discuss business during the China trade fair at the Cairo International Convention Center in Cairo, Egypt, Aug. 25, 2016. [File Photo: Xinhua]</em></p> <p> Egypt launched Tuesday the largest trade fair for Chinese investors, as Chinese companies in Egypt showcased their products and services to local consumers.</p> <p> The inauguration ceremony of the China Trade and Investment Exhibition held at the Cairo International Fair Ground was attended by a number of Egyptian and Chinese businessmen as well as officials from both countries.</p> <p> The participant Chinese companies and manufacturers displayed various products such as textile and garments, furniture, home electronics, building materials and cars.</p> <p> "China ranks 21st among foreign countries investing in Egypt and we are targeting to have China among top 10 investors in Egypt," Mona Zobaa, chairman of Egyptian General Authority for Investment, told Xinhua.</p> <p> She added that China and Egypt are currently strengthening cooperation in trade and economic spheres through improving investment climate, creating investment opportunities and furnishing investment map in Egypt.</p> <p> China is Egypt's largest trading partner with a trade volume of about 11 billion U.S. dollars in 2016 and about 5.2 billion dollars in the first half of 2017.</p> <p> Xie Manding, managing director of China COSCO shipping company in Egypt, said his company, which opened a branch in Egypt about two decades ago, hopes to increase its operations in Egypt under the framework of the Belt and Road Initiative proposed by China.</p> <p> China COSCO provides various services ranging from container shipping, customs clearance to logistics for Chinese enterprises exporting goods to Egypt.</p> <p> Xie said his company is "now mulling new regional shipping routes, including an Egypt-Ukraine-Russia-Turkey route and a route linking Egypt to Northern European countries through Morocco."</p> <p> This will facilitate Egypt's efforts to sell its products to more countries, as China has promised to share development opportunities with other countries under the Belt and Road Initiative, he added.</p> <p> The initiative, proposed in 2013, aims to build a trade and infrastucture network that connects Asia with Africa and Europe along the ancient Silk Road trade routes to seek common development and prosperity.</p> <p> The three-day exhibition is co-organized by the Egyptian Chinese Trading Center in Egypt, Chinese Chamber of Commerce in Egypt, the China Development Bank, Egyptian Chamber of Commerce, China-Egypt Friendship Association, and the Al-Ahram Foundation.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ List of secretary, deputy secretaries, Standing Committee members of CPC discipline commission ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284721</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284721.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:20:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The following is a list of secretary, deputy secretaries and Standing Committee members of the 19th Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) of the Communist Party of China (CPC):</p> <p> Secretary: Zhao Leji</p> <p> Deputy secretaries: Yang Xiaodu, Zhang Shengmin, Liu Jinguo, Yang Xiaochao, Li Shulei, Xu Lingyi, Xiao Pei, Chen Xiaojiang</p> <p> Standing Committee members (listed in the order of the number of strokes in their surnames): Wang Hongjin, Bai Shaokang, Liu Jinguo, Li Shulei, Yang Xiaochao, Yang Xiaodu, Xiao Pei, Zou Jiayi (f.), Zhang Shengmin, Zhang Chunsheng, Chen Xiaojiang, Chen Chaoying, Zhao Leji, Hou Kai, Jiang Xinzhi, Luo Yuan, Xu Lingyi, Ling Ji, Cui Peng</p> <p> They were elected on Wednesday morning at the first plenary session of the 19th CCDI, and then approved at the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi: CPC to build mighty nationwide force driving China's development ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284717</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284717.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:16:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Communist Party of China (CPC) will generate waves of positive energy which can build into a mighty and nationwide force driving China's development and progress, said Xi Jinping, general secretary of the CPC Central Committee on Wednesday.</p> <p> "We must continue to rid ourselves of any virus that erodes the Party's fabric, make great efforts to foster a healthy political environment of integrity, and generate waves of positive energy throughout our Party," Xi said while meeting the press at the Great Hall of the People.</p> <p> The CPC will mark its centenary in 2021.</p> <p> "For a party which fights for the eternal wellbeing of the Chinese nation, the centenary only ushers in the prime of life," Xi said. "As the world's largest political party, the CPC must behave in a way commensurate with this status."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ New CPC Central Committee holds first plenary session ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284688</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284688.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:15:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251315000154816174310.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> <em>Xi Jinping(C), general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), and the other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central CommitteeLi Keqiang(3rd R), Li Zhanshu (3rd L), Wang Yang (2nd R), Wang Huning (2nd L), Zhao Leji (1st R) and Han Zheng, meet the press at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 25, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Tao)</em></p> <p> The 19th Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee held its first plenary session on Wednesday morning and elected Xi Jinping as general secretary of the CPC Central Committee.</p> <p> Xi presided over the plenum attended by 204 members and 172 alternate members of the CPC Central Committee.</p> <p> The plenum elected members of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee and its Standing Committee.</p> <p> Based on the nomination of the Political Bureau Standing Committee, it endorsed members of the Secretariat of the CPC Central Committee, and decided on members of the CPC Central Military Commission.</p> <p> It also approved the election of the secretary, deputy secretaries and members of the Standing Committee of the 19th Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI).</p> <p> &nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Bangladesh approves China-funded elevated expressway project ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284707</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284707.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:00:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Bangladesh's highest economic policy-making body has approved a China-funded elevated expressway project.</p> <p> The project was approved at a meeting of the Executive Committee of the National Economic Council (ECNEC) chaired by Prime Minister Sheikh Hasina on Tuesday.</p> <p> After the ECNEC meeting, Planning Minister AHM Mustafa Kamal told reporters that the project, involving an estimated cost of 169.01 billion taka (2 billion U.S. dollars), was approved in a bid to enable quick entry and exit of vehicles to and from Dhaka and facilitate transit trade with regional countires.</p> <p> Bangladesh's Bridges Division has already inked a memorandum of understanding with the China National Machinery IMP &amp; EXP Corp (CMC) to construct the elevated expressway from Hazrat Shahjalal International Aiport in Dhaka to Ashulia on the outskirts of the norther part of the capital.</p> <p> The project will be implemented with Chinese financial assistance on government-to-government basis, for which the Bangladeshi Economic Relations Division (ERD) has already sent a letter of interest to the Chinese government.</p> <p> China will provide 1.39 billion U.S dollars or nearly 109.50 billion taka in loans to the project, of which 15 percent will be concessional loans and 85 percent will be preferential buyer's credit.</p> <p> The Bangladesh government will bear 59.51 billion taka of the estimated project cost of 169.01 billion taka.</p> <p> A proposal for signing a commercial contract with CMC after negotiation was approved in principle at a meeting of the Cabinet Committee on economic affairs in April.</p> <p> The plans for constructing a 10.84-km ramp and improving 14.28-km road, construction of 1.92-km Nabinagar flyover, bridge overpass and drainage system have also been included in the elevated expressway project, which will be implemented by June 2022. (1 U.S. dollar equals about 82 taka)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi says China welcomes constructive suggestions ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284710</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284710.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:59:10 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), told reporters worldwide on Wednesday that China welcomes objective reporting and constructive suggestions.</p> <p> Xi made the remarks as he led other members of the Standing Committee of the 19th CPC Central Committee Political Bureau to meet the press at the Great Hall of the People.</p> <p> "We do not need lavish praise from others, however, we do welcome objective reporting and constructive suggestions, for this is our motto: 'Not angling for compliments, I would be content that my integrity fills the universe,'" Xi said.</p> <p> He encouraged members of the press to visit and see more of China, citing a Chinese saying that "it is better to see once that to hear a hundred times."</p> <p> "We hope that after the Party Congress, you will continue to follow China's development and progress, and learn about and report on more dimensions of China," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi promises further reform, opening China wider to the world ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284708</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284708.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:59:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, promised further reform and opening-up while meeting the press here on Wednesday.</p> <p> "We will review our experience and build on the good momentum to continue modernizing China's system and capacity for governance, and make determined efforts to comprehensively deepen reform and open China still wider to the world," Xi said.</p> <p> The next year marks the 40th anniversary of the launch of reform and opening-up, Xi said. The drive started in 1978.</p> <p> Reform and opening-up is a crucial move that is shaping China's future. Forty years of reform and opening-up has made it possible for the Chinese people to lead decent and even comfortable lives, Xi said.</p> <p> "We will see that the reform and opening-up complement and reinforce each other. It is my conviction that the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation will become a reality in the course of reform and opening-up," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi promises realizing common prosperity for everyone ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284704</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284704.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:59:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, said Wednesday the Party must remain committed to a people-centered philosophy of development and make steady progress toward enhancing people's sense of fulfillment and realizing common prosperity for everyone.</p> <p> "The aspirations of the people to live a better life must always be the focus of our efforts," said Xi when he and other members of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the CPC Central Committee met reporters.</p> <p> "I have no doubt in my mind that our people's lives will see further improvement year after year," he said.</p> <p> He reiterated the resolve to establish a moderately prosperous society across all metrics in 2020.</p> <p> "This is a society to be enjoyed by each and every one of us; on the march toward common prosperity, on one must be left behind," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi vows greater contributions to peace, development for humanity ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284702</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284702.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:58:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC), said Wednesday China will make new and greater contributions to peace and development for all humanity.</p> <p> The CPC and the Chinese people have gone through trials and tribulations, said Xi, when leading a new top CPC leadership to meet the press.</p> <p> "These experiences have taught us that peace is precious and development must be valued," he told reporters.</p> <p> "With confidence and pride, the Chinese people will be steadfast in upholding our country's sovereignty, security and development interests," he said.</p> <p> Xi said China will work with other nations to build a global community with a shared future, and make new and greater contributions to the noble cause of peace and development for all humanity.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi eyes sustained, healthy growth of Chinese economy in 2019 ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284700</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284700.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:58:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the 19th Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, said China will strive for sustained and healthy economic growth in 2019 which marks the 70th anniversary of the founding of the People's Republic of China.</p> <p> Xi made the remarks when meeting the press after the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee closed on Wednesday.</p> <p> "We will act on the new vision for development, and strive for sustained and healthy economic growth that benefits people in China and around the world," Xi said.</p> <p> "We will continue our efforts to accomplish all the tasks laid down in the 13th Five-Year Plan, develop new blueprints for China's future, and see the flourishing of all our endeavors," he said.</p> <p> These efforts will contribute toward a more prosperous and strong People's Republic, he added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi leads top CPC leadership to meet press ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284690</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284690.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:31:44 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping led the other members of the Standing Committee of the 19th Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee Political Bureau to meet the press Wednesday at the Great Hall of the People.</p> <p> The other members are Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng.</p> <p> Xi said the 19th Party Congress has received extensive and detailed reporting and the media coverage has captured the attention of the world.</p> <p> "Thank you so much for your hard work!" Xi said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Coming 5 years a period of several important junctures: Xi ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284691</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284691.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:31:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee, said Wednesday that the coming five years will see several important junctures and signposts.</p> <p> "As I look ahead to the next five years, I see several important junctures and signposts," Xi made the remarks while leading other members of the Standing Committee of the 19th CPC Central Committee Political Bureau to meet the press.</p> <p> Stating that the coming five years between the 19th and the 20th Party Congress is the period in which the timeframes of the Two Centenary Goals will converge, Xi said that "not only must we deliver the first centenary goal, we must also embark on the journey toward the second centenary goal."</p> <p> "With decades of hard work, socialism with Chinese characteristics has entered a new era. In this new context, we must get a new look and, more importantly, make new accomplishments," he said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 452 major political parties worldwide congratulate CPC congress ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284689</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284689.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:31:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> A total of 452 major political parties in 165 countries have sent 855 messages of congratulation to the Communist Party of China (CPC) since the opening of the 19th CPC National Congress, Xi Jinping said Wednesday.</p> <p> Xi, who was just re-elected as general secretary of the CPC Central Committee, made the remarks when meeting the press at the Great Hall of the People together with other newly-elected members of the Standing Committee of the 19th CPC Central Committee Political Bureau.</p> <p> Of these congratulatory messages, 814 came from heads of state or government, or the leaders of political parties or important organizations, Xi said.</p> <p> "On behalf of the CPC Central Committee, I wish to convey our sincere appreciation to them all," Xi said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ List of chairman, vice chairmen, members of CPC Central Military Commission ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284686</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284686.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:26:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The following is a list of chairman, vice chairmen and members of the Central Military Commission of the Communist Party of China (CPC):</p> <p> Chairman: Xi Jinping</p> <p> Vice Chairmen: Xu Qiliang, Zhang Youxia</p> <p> Members: Wei Fenghe, Li Zuocheng, Miao Hua, Zhang Shengmin</p> <p> The decision was made at the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee on Wednesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ List of Political Bureau members of 19th CPC Central Committee ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284681</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284681.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:26:18 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The following is the list of the Political Bureau members of the 19th Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee (listed in the order of the number of strokes in their surnames):</p> <p> Ding Xuexiang, Xi Jinping, Wang Chen, Wang Huning, Liu He, Xu Qiliang, Sun Chunlan (female), Li Xi, Li Qiang, Li Keqiang, Li Hongzhong, Yang Jiechi, Yang Xiaodu, Wang Yang, Zhang Youxia, Chen Xi, Chen Quanguo, Chen Min'er, Zhao Leji, Hu Chunhua, Li Zhanshu, Guo Shengkun, Huang Kunming, Han Zheng and Cai Qi.</p> <p> They were elected at the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee on Wednesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi leads top CPC leadership to meet press ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284683</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284683.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:26:08 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping led the other members of the Standing Committee of the 19th Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee Political Bureau to meet the press Wednesday at the Great Hall of the People.</p> <p> The other members are Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Zhao Leji elected head of CPC anti-graft commission ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284685</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284685.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:25:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Zhao Leji was elected secretary of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) of the Communist Party of China (CPC) on Wednesday.</p> <p> Zhao was elected at a plenary session of the CCDI, at which the CCDI also elected its deputy secretaries and Standing Committee members.</p> <p> The first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee approved the elections Wednesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ List of members of 19th CPC Central Committee Secretariat ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284684</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284684.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 12:25:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The following is a list of members of the Secretariat of the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC):</p> <p> Wang Huning, Ding Xuexiang, Yang Xiaodu, Chen Xi, Guo Shengkun, Huang Kunming, and You Quan.</p> <p> They were nominated by the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee and approved at the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee on Wednesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi Jinping elected general secretary of CPC Central Committee ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284666</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284666.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 11:54:49 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251154000108540108816.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 703px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Xi Jinping presides over the closing session of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 24, 2017. (Xinhua/Lan Hongguang)</em></p> <p> Xi Jinping was elected general secretary of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Central Committee for the second term at the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee on Wednesday.</p> <p> Members of the newly elected Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 19th CPC Central Committee are Xi Jinping, Li Keqiang, Li Zhanshu, Wang Yang, Wang Huning, Zhao Leji and Han Zheng.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ LIVECAST: CPC top leadership meets the media on Wednesday ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284588</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284588.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 11:50:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <embed allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="sameDomain" height="700" quality="high" src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/2010tv_flash/liveplayer.swf?liveInfo=5,cctven" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="933"></embed></p> <p> Members of the Standing Committee of the 19th CPC Central Committee Political Bureau meet Chinese and foreign journalists at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Full text of resolution on CCDI work report ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284561</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284561.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 09:21:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Following is the full text of the Resolution of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on the Report on the Work of the 18th Central Commission for Discipline Inspection adopted Tuesday at the 19th National Congress of the CPC.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <strong>Resolution of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on the Report on the Work of the 18th Central Commission for Discipline Inspection</strong></p> <p style="text-align: right;"> <strong>October 24, 2017</strong></p> <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China has reviewed and approved the Report on the Work of the 18th Central Commission for Discipline Inspection. The Congress fully endorses its work.</p> <p> The Congress holds that since the 18th National Congress of the Party, under the strong leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core, the central and local commissions for discipline inspection have strengthened their consciousness of the need to maintain political integrity, think in big-picture terms, follow the leadership core, and keep in alignment, and enhanced their confidence in the path, theory, system, and culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics. They have closely aligned themselves with the Party Central Committee and held the Party Constitution in great esteem as they performed their duties faithfully. Further steps have been taken to ensure full and strict governance over the Party, and the anti-corruption campaign has built into a crushing tide, is being consolidated, and continues to develop. They have upheld the authority and centralized, unified leadership of the Central Committee, helped foster a strong political underpinning for the Party's governance, and developed a contingent of discipline inspection and supervision officials who are loyal to the Party, have moral integrity, and demonstrate a keen sense of responsibility. In doing so, they have delivered excellent performance to the satisfaction of the Party and the people.</p> <p> The Congress calls on the central and local commissions for discipline inspection to hold high the banner of socialism with Chinese characteristics and follow the guidance of Marxism-Leninism, Mao Zedong Thought, Deng Xiaoping Theory, the Theory of Three Represents, the Scientific Outlook on Development, and Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. It urges them to act in complete accord with the strategic plans made at the Congress, do their part in ensuring coordinated implementation of the five-sphere integrated plan (1) and the four-pronged comprehensive strategy, (2) develop still greater consciousness of the need to maintain political integrity, think in big-picture terms, follow the leadership core, and keep in alignment, and foster stronger confidence in the path, theory, system, and culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics. They are also urged to remain true to the Party's original aspiration and keep the Party's mission firmly in mind; work toward a fundamental improvement in the political ecosystem of the Party, with the focus on its leadership, capacity building, full and strict self-governance, conduct and integrity, and anti-corruption endeavor; and fulfill their duties to exercise oversight, enforce discipline, and ensure accountability as required by the Party Constitution. With this, they shall provide a strong underpinning for China's endeavor toward a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects and great success of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era, and contribute to realizing the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation.</p> <p> (1) The five-sphere integrated plan is to promote coordinated economic, political, cultural, social, and ecological advancement.</p> <p> (2) The four-pronged comprehensive strategy is to make comprehensive moves to finish building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, deepen reform, advance law-based governance, and strengthen Party self-governance.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Full text of resolution on amendment to CPC Constitution ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284538</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284538.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 09:21:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Following is the full text of the Resolution of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on the Revised Constitution of the Communist Party of China adopted Tuesday at the 19th National Congress of the CPC.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <strong>Resolution of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on the Revised Constitution of the Communist Party of China</strong></p> <p style="text-align: right;"> <strong>October 24, 2017</strong></p> <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China deliberated on and unanimously adopted the revised Constitution of the Communist Party of China proposed by the 18th Party Central Committee and decided that it shall come into effect as of the date of adoption.</p> <p> The Congress notes that since the Party's 18th National Congress, Chinese Communists, with Comrade Xi Jinping as their chief representative, in response to contemporary developments and by integrating theory with practice, have systematically addressed the major question of our times-what kind of socialism with Chinese characteristics the new era requires us to uphold and develop and how we should uphold and develop it, thus giving shape to Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. The Thought is a continuation and development of Marxism-Leninism, Mao Zedong Thought, Deng Xiaoping Theory, the Theory of Three Represents, and the Scientific Outlook on Development. It is the latest achievement in adapting Marxism to the Chinese context, a crystallization of the practical experience and collective wisdom of the Party and the people, an important component of the theoretical system of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and a guide to action for the entire Party and all the Chinese people to strive for the great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation, and must be upheld long term and constantly developed. Under the guidance of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, the Communist Party of China has led the Chinese people of all ethnic groups in a concerted effort to carry out a great struggle, develop a great project, advance a great cause, and realize a great dream, ushering in a new era of socialism with Chinese characteristics.</p> <p> The Congress unanimously agrees that, Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, in addition to Marxism-Leninism, Mao Zedong Thought, Deng Xiaoping Theory, the Theory of Three Represents, and the Scientific Outlook on Development, shall constitute the guides to action of the Party in the Party Constitution. The Congress urges all Party members to use the Thought to achieve unity in thinking and action, be more purposeful and determined in studying and applying it, and put the Thought into action throughout the drive toward China's socialist modernization and in every dimension of Party building.</p> <p> The Congress affirms that the culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics is a key part of socialism with Chinese characteristics and a powerful source of strength that inspires the entire Party and the Chinese people of all ethnic groups to forge ahead courageously. The Congress approves the incorporation of the culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics into the Party Constitution, along with the path of socialism with Chinese characteristics, the theoretical system of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and the system of socialism with Chinese characteristics. This addition will help all Party members deepen their understanding of socialism with Chinese characteristics and fully grasp its implications. The Congress stresses that all Party members must cherish deeply, uphold long term, and continue to develop this path, this theoretical system, this socialist system, and this culture, which the Party has developed through great hardship; hold high the great banner of socialism with Chinese characteristics; have firm confidence in the path, theory, system, and culture of socialism with Chinese characteristics; and implement the Party's basic theory, basic line, and basic policy.</p> <p> The Congress holds that national rejuvenation has been the greatest dream of the Chinese people since modern times began, and that it is a solemn commitment our Party has made to our people and to history. The Congress endorses the inclusion of the two centenary goals and the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation into the Party Constitution.</p> <p> The Congress holds that a major political conclusion is drawn in the political report to the 19th Party Congress that the principal contradiction facing Chinese society has evolved and is now that between the people's ever-growing needs for a better life and unbalanced and inadequate development; it reflects the realities of the development of Chinese society, and serves as an important basis on which we formulate major policies and long-term strategies for the Party and the country. The Party Constitution is revised accordingly to provide important guidance for us to better understand the new historic juncture in China's development and its particular features in the current stage and to further advance the cause of the Party and the country.</p> <p> The Congress holds that statements on our people-centered philosophy of development; on innovative, coordinated, green, and open development that is for everyone; on coordinated efforts to finish building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, comprehensively deepen reform, fully advance law-based governance, and strengthen Party self-governance in every respect; and on all-out efforts to build a great modern socialist country, represent the ultimate purpose, vision, overall strategy, and overarching goal of the Party in upholding and developing socialism with Chinese characteristics.</p> <p> Also incorporated into the Party Constitution are statements on the need to achieve better quality and more efficient, equitable, and sustainable development, to improve and develop the system of socialism with Chinese characteristics, to modernize China's system and capacity for governance, and to pursue reform in a more systematic, holistic, and coordinated way. This will help all Party members closely follow, in both thinking and action, the well-conceived assessment and strategic plans of the Central Committee, uphold and put into practice the new development philosophy, and continue to break new ground in reform and development.</p> <p> The Congress holds that since our 18th National Congress, the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core has developed new ideas, new thinking, and new strategies for promoting economic, political, cultural, social, and ecological advancement. The Congress agrees to add to the Party Constitution the following statements: we shall give play to the decisive role of market forces in resource allocation and ensure the government plays its role better; advance supply-side structural reform; establish a system of socialist rule of law with Chinese characteristics; advance extensive, multilevel, and institutionalized development of consultative democracy; nurture and practice core socialist values; promote the creative evolution and development of fine traditional Chinese culture; carry forward our revolutionary culture; develop an advanced socialist culture; enhance our country's cultural soft power; hold firmly the leading position in ideological work; help our people gain an increasingly stronger sense of fulfillment; strengthen and develop new approaches to social governance; pursue a holistic approach to national security; and fully understand that lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets.</p> <p> These statements are of great importance in helping all Party members more consciously and determinedly implement the Party's basic theory, basic line, and basic policy, and coordinate the implementation of the five-sphere integrated plan.</p> <p> The Congress notes that since the Party's 18th National Congress, Comrade Xi Jinping has set forth a series of important ideas and viewpoints on strengthening national defense and the armed forces, ethnic unity, "one country, two systems" and national reunification, the united front, and foreign affairs, charting the course for staying committed to the path of building strong armed forces with Chinese characteristics; for safeguarding and developing socialist ethnic relations featuring equality, unity, mutual assistance, and harmony; for promoting national reunification; and for building a community with a shared future for mankind.</p> <p> The Congress agrees to include into the Party Constitution the following statements: The Communist Party of China shall uphold its absolute leadership over the People's Liberation Army and other people's armed forces; implement Xi Jinping's thinking on strengthening the military; strengthen the development of the People's Liberation Army by enhancing its political loyalty, strengthening it through reform and technology, and running it in accordance with the law; build people's forces that obey the Party's command, can fight and win, and maintain excellent conduct; ensure that the People's Liberation Army accomplishes its missions and tasks in the new era; foster a strong sense of community for the Chinese nation; uphold justice while pursuing shared interests; work to build a community with a shared future for mankind; follow the principle of achieving shared growth through discussion and collaboration; and pursue the Belt and Road Initiative.</p> <p> The inclusion of these statements will help ensure the Party's absolute leadership over the people's armed forces, modernize national defense and the military, promote ethnic unity, and develop an open economy of higher standards.</p> <p> The Congress holds that since its 18th National Congress, the Party has made steady progress in exercising full and rigorous governance over the Party, taken all-around measures to explore the strengthening of Party building, and gained abundant successful experience and achieved major outcomes, which must be included into the Party Constitution in a timely manner and therefore become the common will and rule of the whole Party.</p> <p> It is affirmed at the Party's 19th National Congress that the Party must firmly exercise self-supervision and practice strict self-governance in every respect; strengthen the Party's long-term governance capacity and its advanced nature and purity; and take enhancing its political building as the overarching principle and make comprehensive efforts to ensure that the Party's political work is stressed, ideology is strengthened, organizations are consolidated, conduct is improved, discipline is maintained, institutional development is always emphasized, and the fight against corruption keeps going. The Congress agrees to add the above statements to the Party Constitution.</p> <p> Also included into the Party Constitution are: The Party must constantly strengthen its ability to purify, improve, reform, and excel itself; use Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era to achieve unity in thinking and action; keep firmly in mind the need to maintain political integrity, think in big-picture terms, uphold the leadership core, and keep in alignment, and firmly uphold the authority and centralized, unified leadership of the Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core; strengthen and regulate political activities within the Party; make intraparty political activities more politically oriented, up-to-date, principled, and effective; cultivate a positive and healthy intraparty political culture; and foster a sound political ecosystem featuring honesty and integrity within the Party. Firmness in exercising strict self-supervision and self-governance is included into the Party Constitution as a fundamental requirement the Party must work with firm resolve to meet in building itself.</p> <p> The incorporation of these statements will ensure the Party has a clearer goal and a more complete plan for building itself. They will help the whole Party advance Party building with more well-conceived ways of thinking and more effective measures, so as to continuously improve the quality of Party building and ensure the Party is always full of vigor and vitality.</p> <p> The Congress holds that the leadership of the Communist Party of China is the most essential attribute of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and the greatest strength of this system; the Party exercises overall leadership over all areas of endeavor in every part of the country. The Congress agrees to add this major political principle to the Party Constitution, which will help heighten the Party consciousness of every Party member, and ensure unity of thinking, political solidarity and concerted action of the whole Party. It will also help enhance the Party's ability to innovate, power to unite, and energy to fight; ensure the Party always provides overall leadership and coordinates the efforts of all involved; and offer the fundamental political guarantee for all areas of work of the Party and the country.</p> <p> The Congress notes that in view of the successful experience gained in Party work and Party building since the 18th Party Congress and in compliance with the revisions to the General Program, appropriate revisions to some articles of the Party Constitution are necessary.</p> <p> To conscientiously study Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, to consciously observe the Party's political discipline and rules, to have the courage to reveal and correct any statements and actions violating the Party's principles, to lead the way in practicing core socialist values, and to advocate traditional virtues of the Chinese nation, are obligations of Party members. Upholding political integrity as the primary criterion is the major principle that must be adhered to in admitting new Party members.</p> <p> To ensure the full coverage of discipline inspection and carry out inspections at central, city (prefecture), and county levels is practical experience gained in the Party's discipline inspection work; it must be upheld and developed.</p> <p> To clarify that Chairperson of the Central Military Commission assumes overall responsibility over the work of the Commission and that the Central Military Commission is responsible for Party work and political work in the armed forces, complies with the realistic requirement to ensure the Central Military Commission fulfills its responsibility for Party self-supervision and self-governance after the military reform.</p> <p> To fully reflect the achievements of Party work and Party building since the 18th Party Congress, revisions are made to: adjust the term of office of general Party branch committees and Party branch committees; regularize and institutionalize the requirement for all Party members to study the Party Constitution, Party regulations, and General Secretary Xi Jinping's major policy addresses and to meet Party standards; define the status and role of Party organizations in state-owned enterprises; elaborate on the functions and responsibilities of primary-level Party organizations in social organizations; explicate the responsibilities of primary-level Party organizations in offices of the Party or the state at every level; demonstrate the position and functions of Party branches; set out new criteria and requirements for selecting officials; and adjust and elaborate on provisions related to the Party discipline and Party organs for discipline inspection.</p> <p> These revisions will help all Party members grasp the guiding ideology of the Party and keep up with the times, align themselves with Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era and use it to guide practice and advance work, see primary-level Party organizations become politically stronger, and move further forward with the full and rigorous governance over the Party.</p> <p> The Congress urges Party organizations at all levels and all Party members to, under the firm leadership of the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at the core, hold high the great banner of socialism with Chinese characteristics, follow the guidance of Marxism-Leninism, Mao Zedong Thought, Deng Xiaoping Theory, the Theory of Three Represents, the Scientific Outlook on Development, and Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, and more purposefully study, observe, apply, and uphold the Party Constitution. The Congress urges the entire Party to uphold and strengthen the overall leadership of the Party, ensure the Party's strict self-supervision and strict self-governance in every respect, and keep working to secure a decisive victory in finishing building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, to strive for the great success of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era, to realize the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation, and to see our people fulfill their aspirations for a better life.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Full text of resolution on CPC Central Committee report ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284523</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284523.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 09:21:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Following is the full text of the Resolution of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on the Report of the 18th Central Committee adopted Tuesday at the just-ended 19th National Congress of the CPC.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <strong>Resolution of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China on the Report of the 18th Central Committee</strong></p> <p style="text-align: right;"> <strong>October 24, 2017</strong></p> <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China approves the report delivered by Comrade Xi Jinping on behalf of the Party's 18th Central Committee. The Congress holds high the banner of socialism with Chinese characteristics and is guided by Marxism-Leninism, Mao Zedong Thought, Deng Xiaoping Theory, the Theory of Three Represents, the Scientific Outlook on Development, and Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. On the basis of an analysis of the developments in the international and domestic environments and a review of the Party's work and the historic change over the past five years, the Congress forms the major political judgments that socialism with Chinese characteristics has entered a new era and the principal contradiction in Chinese society has evolved into one between unbalanced and inadequate development and the people's ever-growing needs for a better life. The Congress elaborates on the Party's historic mission in the new era and establishes the historical position of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. It sets forth the basic policy for upholding and developing socialism with Chinese characteristics in the new era, and establishes the goal of securing a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects and then embarking on a journey to fully build a modern socialist China. The Congress also sets out an overall plan for advancing the great cause of socialism with Chinese characteristics and the great new project of Party building in the new era.</p> <p> The report of the 18th Central Committee approved by the Congress sketches out an impressive blueprint for securing a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects and striving for the great success of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era, thus charting the course for continued progress in the cause of the Party and the country. The report is a crystallization of the wisdom of the whole Party and the Chinese people of all ethnic groups. It is a political declaration and a program of action for the Party to unite the Chinese people and lead them in upholding and developing socialism with Chinese characteristics in the new era. It is a guiding Marxist document.</p> <p> The Congress believes that the theme expounded on in the report is of enormous importance to the Party leading the people toward a stronger China through tireless and groundbreaking efforts. Every one of us in the Party must remain true to our original aspiration and keep our mission firmly in mind, hold high the banner of socialism with Chinese characteristics, secure a decisive victory in building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, strive for the great success of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era, and work tirelessly to realize the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation.</p> <p> The Congress applauds the work of the 18th Central Committee. The five years since the 18th National Congress have been a truly remarkable five years in the course of the development of the Party and the country, with historic achievements made in reform, opening up, and socialist modernization. Over these five years, the Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core has demonstrated tremendous political courage and a powerful sense of mission as it has developed new ideas, new thinking, and new strategies, adopted a raft of major principles and policies, launched a host of major initiatives, and pushed ahead with many major tasks. It has thus solved many tough problems that were long on the agenda but never resolved, accomplished many things that were wanted but never got done, and prompted historic shifts in the cause of the Party and the country.</p> <p> The Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core has acted with courage to confront major risks and tests facing the Party and to address prominent problems within the Party itself. With firm resolve, it has tightened discipline and improved Party conduct, fought corruption, and punished wrongdoing, and removed serious potential dangers in the Party and the country. As a result, both the intraparty political atmosphere and the political ecosystem of the Party have improved markedly. The Party's ability to create, power to unite, and energy to fight have all been significantly strengthened; Party solidarity and unity have been reinforced, and our engagement with the people has been greatly improved. Revolutionary tempering has made our Party stronger and it now radiates with great vitality. With this, efforts to develop the cause of the Party and the country have gained a strong political underpinning.</p> <p> The achievements of the past five years have touched every area and broken new ground; the changes in China over the past five years have been profound and fundamental.</p> <p> The Congress stresses that, with decades of hard work, socialism with Chinese characteristics has crossed the threshold into a new era. This is a new historic juncture in China's development. As socialism with Chinese characteristics has entered a new era, the principal contradiction facing Chinese society has evolved into one between unbalanced and inadequate development and the people's ever-growing needs for a better life. This represents a historic shift that affects the whole landscape and that creates many new demands for the work of the Party and the country. Building on continued efforts to sustain development, we must devote great energy to addressing development's imbalances and inadequacies, and push hard to improve the quality and effect of development. With this, we can be better placed to meet the ever-growing economic, political, cultural, social, and ecological needs of our people, and to promote well-rounded human development and all-round social progress.</p> <p> The Congress stresses that the Party has been presented with the profound question of what kind of socialism with Chinese characteristics the new era requires it to uphold and develop, and how it should go about doing it. In answering this question of an era, our Party has adopted an entirely new perspective to deepen its understanding of the laws that underlie governance by the Communist party, the development of socialism, and the evolution of human society. It has worked hard to undertake theoretical explorations, and has achieved major theoretical innovations, ultimately giving shape to Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era.</p> <p> Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era builds on and further enriches Marxism-Leninism, Mao Zedong Thought, Deng Xiaoping Theory, the Theory of Three Represents, and the Scientific Outlook on Development. It represents the latest achievement in adapting Marxism to the Chinese context, and encapsulates the practical experience and collective wisdom of our Party and the people. It is an important component of the theory of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and a guide to action for all our members and all the Chinese people as we strive to achieve national rejuvenation. This Thought must be adhered to and steadily developed on a long-term basis.</p> <p> The Congress highlights the 14 points that form the basic policy underpinning our endeavors to uphold and develop socialism with Chinese characteristics in the new era. They are: Ensure Party leadership over all work; commit to a people-centered approach; continue to comprehensively deepen reform; adopt a new vision for development; see that the people run the country; ensure every dimension of governance is law-based; uphold core socialist values; ensure and improve living standards through development; ensure harmony between human and nature; pursue a holistic approach to national security; uphold absolute Party leadership over the people's forces; uphold the principle of "one country, two systems" and promote national reunification; promote the building of a community with a shared future for mankind; and exercise full and rigorous governance over the Party. All our members must fully implement the Party's basic theory, line, and policy so as to better steer the development of the Party and people's cause.</p> <p> The Congress points out that the period between now and 2020 will be decisive in finishing the building of a moderately prosperous society in all respects. We must follow the requirements on building this society set out at our 16th, 17th, and 18th National Congresses; focus on priorities, address inadequacies, and shore up points of weakness. We must take tough steps to forestall and defuse major risks, carry out targeted poverty alleviation, and prevent and control pollution, so that the moderately prosperous society we build earns the people's approval and stands the test of time.</p> <p> The Congress believes that the period between the 19th and the 20th National Congress is the period in which the timeframes of the two centenary goals converge. In this period, not only must we finish building a moderately prosperous society in all respects and achieve the first centenary goal; we must also build on this achievement to embark on a new journey toward the second centenary goal of fully building a modern socialist country.</p> <p> Based on a comprehensive analysis of the international and domestic environments and the conditions for China's development, we have drawn up a two-stage development plan for the period from 2020 to the middle of this century. In the first stage from 2020 to 2035, we will build on the foundation created by the moderately prosperous society with a further 15 years of hard work to see that socialist modernization is basically realized. In the second stage from 2035 to the middle of the 21st century, we will, building on having basically achieved modernization, work hard for a further 15 years and develop China into a great modern socialist country that is prosperous, strong, democratic, culturally advanced, harmonious, and beautiful.</p> <p> The Congress endorses the report's plans for promoting socialist economic, political, cultural, social, and ecological advancement in China. It stresses that we must apply a new vision of development and develop a modernized economy. We should put quality first and give priority to performance, pursue supply-side structural reform as our main task, and work hard for better quality, higher efficiency, and more robust drivers of economic growth through reform. We should accelerate the building of an industrial system that promotes coordinated development of the real economy with technological innovation, modern finance, and human resources, and endeavor to develop an economy with more effective market mechanisms, dynamic micro-entities, and sound macro-regulation. With this we can steadily strengthen the innovation capacity and competitiveness of China's economy. We should further supply-side structural reform, move faster to make China a country of innovators, pursue a rural vitalization strategy and the strategy for coordinated regional development, accelerate efforts to improve the socialist market economy, make new ground in pursuing opening up on all fronts, and strive to achieve better quality, more efficient, fairer, and more sustainable development.</p> <p> We should improve the system of institutions through which the people run the country and develop socialist democracy. We should uphold the unity of Party leadership, the people running the country, and law-based governance. This requires us to strengthen institutional guarantees to ensure the people run the country, give play to the important role of socialist consultative democracy, and advance law-based governance. We should deepen reform of Party and government institutions and the system of government administration, consolidate and develop the patriotic united front, and consolidate and enhance political stability, unity, and vitality.</p> <p> We should build stronger cultural confidence and help socialist culture to flourish. We must hold firmly the leading position in ideological work, cultivate and observe core socialist values, and raise intellectual and moral standards. We should work to see socialist literature and art thrive, promote the development of cultural programs and industries, and inspire the cultural creativity of our whole nation.</p> <p> We should grow better at ensuring and improving people's wellbeing and strengthen and develop new approaches to social governance. We must focus on the most pressing, most immediate issues that concern the people the most. We should give priority to developing education, improve the quality of employment and raise incomes, strengthen the social security system, win the battle against poverty, carry out the Healthy China initiative, establish a social governance model based on collaboration, participation, and common interests, and effectively safeguard national security. With this we should see that our people always have a strong sense of fulfillment, happiness, and security.</p> <p> We should speed up reform to develop sound systems for building an ecological civilization, and build a Beautiful China. We should promote green development, solve prominent environmental problems, intensify the protection of ecosystems, reform the environmental regulation system, and work to develop a new model of modernization with humans developing in harmony with nature.</p> <p> The Congress stresses that, confronted with profound changes in our national security environment and responding to the demands of the day for a strong country with a strong military, we must stay committed to the Chinese path of building strong armed forces, fully implement Xi Jinping's thinking on strengthening the military, adapt military strategy to new conditions, build a powerful and modernized army, navy, air force, rocket force, and strategic support force, develop strong and efficient joint operations commanding institutions for theater commands, and create a modern combat system with distinctive Chinese characteristics. With this we can fully advance the modernization of national defense and the military and transform our people's armed forces into world-class forces.</p> <p> The Congress stresses that, to maintain long-term prosperity and stability in Hong Kong and Macao, it is imperative to fully and faithfully implement the policies of "one country, two systems," "the people of Hong Kong governing Hong Kong," "the people of Macao governing Macao," and a high degree of autonomy for both regions, and to act in strict compliance with China's Constitution and the basic laws of the two special administrative regions. We shall see that our compatriots in Hong Kong and Macao share both the historic responsibility of national rejuvenation and the pride of a strong and prosperous China. We must uphold the principles of "peaceful reunification" and "one country, two systems," expand economic and cultural exchanges and cooperation between the two sides of the Taiwan Straits, encourage people from both sides to work together to promote Chinese culture, work for the peaceful development of cross-Straits relations, and advance the process toward the peaceful reunification of China. We will never allow anyone, any organization, or any political party, at any time or in any form, to separate any part of Chinese territory from China.</p> <p> The Congress endorses the report's analysis of the international situation and the guiding principles it sets out for China's foreign affairs. The Congress stresses that China will keep to the path of peaceful development, hold high the banner of peace, development, cooperation, and mutual benefit, and uphold its fundamental foreign policy goal of preserving world peace and promoting common development. China remains firm in its commitment to strengthening friendship and cooperation with other countries on the basis of the Five Principles of Peaceful Coexistence. It will actively promote international cooperation through the Belt and Road Initiative, and continue to take an active part in reforming and developing the global governance system. It will work toward a new form of international relations featuring mutual respect, fairness, justice, and win-win cooperation and a community with a shared future for mankind, and work together with the people of all countries to build an open, inclusive, clean, and beautiful world that enjoys lasting peace, universal security, and common prosperity.</p> <p> The Congress stresses that it takes a good blacksmith to make good steel. For the Party to unite the people and lead them in carrying out our great struggle, advancing our great cause, and realizing our great dream, we must unwaveringly uphold and improve Party leadership and make the Party still stronger. The general requirements for Party building for the new era are: Uphold and strengthen overall Party leadership and ensure that the Party exercises effective self-supervision and practices strict self-governance in every respect; take strengthening the Party's long-term governance capacity and its advanced nature and purity as the main thrust, take enhancing the Party's political building as the overarching principle, take holding dear the Party's ideals, convictions, and purpose as the underpinning, and take harnessing the whole Party's enthusiasm, initiative, and creativity as the focus of efforts; make all-round efforts to see the Party's political building enhanced, its theory strengthened, its organizations consolidated, its conduct improved, and its discipline enforced, with institution building incorporated into every aspect of Party building; step up efforts to combat corruption and continue to improve the efficacy of Party building; and build the Party into a vibrant Marxist governing party that is always at the forefront of the times, enjoys the wholehearted support of the people, has the courage to reform itself, and is able to withstand all tests.</p> <p> The Congress stresses that we must put the Party's political building first. All of us in the Party must strengthen our consciousness of the need to maintain political integrity, think in big-picture terms, follow the leadership core, and keep in alignment. We must uphold the authority and centralized, unified leadership of the Party Central Committee, closely follow the Party's political line, strictly observe its political discipline and rules, and closely align ourselves with the Central Committee in terms of political stance, direction, principle, and path.</p> <p> The Congress calls on the entire Party and the Chinese people of all ethnic groups to rally closely around the Party Central Committee with Comrade Xi Jinping at its core, hold high the banner of socialism with Chinese characteristics, and earnestly study and put into practice Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era. We will keep on working with great determination to accomplish the three historic tasks of advancing modernization, realizing China's reunification, and preserving world peace and promoting common development, and make continued efforts to secure a decisive victory in finishing the building of a moderately prosperous society in all respects, strive for the great success of socialism with Chinese characteristics for a new era, realize the Chinese Dream of national rejuvenation, and see that our people realize their aspirations for a better life.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ List of members of the 19th CPC Central Committee ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284390</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284390.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 21:10:33 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 24 (Xinhua) -- The following is a list of the 204 members of the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC) elected at the 19th CPC National Congress here Tuesday (listed in the order of the number of strokes in their surnames): ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 24 (Xinhua) -- The following is a list of the 204 members of the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC) elected at the 19th CPC National Congress here Tuesday (listed in the order of the number of strokes in their surnames):</p> <p> Yi Xiaoguang Ding Laihang Ding Xuedong</p> <p> Ding Xuexiang Yu Weiguo Yu Zhongfu</p> <p> Wan Lijun Xi Jinping Ma Biao (Zhuang)</p> <p> Ma Xingrui Wang Ning Wang Jun</p> <p> Wang Yong Wang Chen Wang Yi</p> <p> Wang Xiaohong Wang Yupu Wang Zhengwei (Hui)</p> <p> Wang Dongming Wang Dongfeng Wang Ercheng</p> <p> Wang Zhimin Wang Zhigang Wang Huning</p> <p> Wang Guosheng Wang Jianjun Wang Jianwu</p> <p> Wang Xiaodong Wang Xiaohui Wang Jiasheng</p> <p> Wang Menghui You Quan Che Jun</p> <p> Yin Li Bayanqolu (Mongolian) Bater (Mongolian)</p> <p> Arken Imirbaki (Uygur) Shi Taifeng Buxiaolin (f. Mongolian)</p> <p> Lu Zhangong Bai Chunli (Manchu) Ji Bingxuan</p> <p> Bi Jingquan Qu Qingshan Zhu Shengling</p> <p> Liu Qi Liu Lei Liu He</p> <p> Liu Shiyu Liu Wanlong Liu Qibao</p> <p> Liu Guozhong Liu Guozhi Liu Jinguo</p> <p> Liu Jieyi Liu Zhenli Liu Jiayi</p> <p> Liu Cigui Liu Yuejun Che Zala (Tibetan)</p> <p> An Zhaoqing (Xibe) Xu Qin Xu Yousheng</p> <p> Xu Dazhe Xu Qiliang Ruan Chengfa</p> <p> Sun Zhigang Sun Jinlong Sun Shaocheng</p> <p> Sun Chunlan (f.) Du Jiahao Li Yi</p> <p> Li Xi Li Bin (f.) Li Qiang</p> <p> Li Ganjie Li Xiaopeng Li Fengbiao</p> <p> Li Yufu Li Chuanguang Li Jiheng</p> <p> Li Keqiang Li Zuocheng Li Shangfu</p> <p> Li Guoying Li Qiaoming Li Xiaohong</p> <p> Li Hongzhong Li Jinbin Yang Xuejun</p> <p> Yang Jiechi Yang Zhenwu Yang Xiaodu</p> <p> Xiao Jie Xiao Yaqing Wu Shezhou</p> <p> Wu Yingjie Wu Zhenglong Qiu Xueqiang</p> <p> He Ping (PLA) He Lifeng Ying Yong</p> <p> Leng Rong Wang Yang Wang Yongqing</p> <p> Shen Jinlong Shen Xiaoming Shen Yueyue (f.)</p> <p> Shen Deyong Huai Jinpeng Song Dan</p> <p> Song Tao Song Xiuyan (f.) Zhang Jun</p> <p> Zhang Youxia Zhang Shengmin Zhang Qingwei</p> <p> Zhang Qingli Zhang Jinan Zhang Guoqing</p> <p> Zhang Chunxian Zhang Xiaoming Zhang Yijiong</p> <p> Lu Hao Chen Xi Chen Wu (Zhuang)</p> <p> Chen Hao Chen Wenqing Chen Jining</p> <p> Chen Quanguo Chen Qiufa (Miao) Chen Baosheng</p> <p> Chen Run'er Chen Min'er Nurlan Abelmanjen (Kazakh)</p> <p> Miao Wei Miao Hua Gou Zhongwen</p> <p> Fan Xiaojun Lin Duo Shang Hong</p> <p> Jin Zhuanglong Zhou Qiang Zhou Yaning</p> <p> Zheng He Zheng Weiping Zheng Xiaosong</p> <p> Meng Xiangfeng Zhao Leji Zhao Kezhi</p> <p> Zhao Zongqi Hao Peng Hu Heping</p> <p> Hu Zejun (f.) Hu Chunhua Xian Hui (f. Hui)</p> <p> Zhong Shan Xin Chunying (f.) Hou Jianguo</p> <p> Lou Qinjian Losang Jamcan (Tibetan) Luo Huining</p> <p> Qin Shengxiang Yuan Jiajun Yuan Yubai</p> <p> Yuan Shuhong Nie Chenxi Li Zhanshu</p> <p> Qian Xiaoqian Tie Ning (f.) Ni Yuefeng</p> <p> Xu Lin Xu Lejiang Xu Anxiang</p> <p> Gao Jin Guo Shengkun Guo Shuqing</p> <p> Tang Renjian Huang Ming Huang Shouhong</p> <p> Huang Kunming Huang Shuxian Cao Jianming</p> <p> Gong Zheng Sheng Bin Shohrat Zakir (Uygur)</p> <p> E Jingping Lu Xinshe Shen Yiqin (f. Bai)</p> <p> Peng Qinghua Jiang Chaoliang Han Zheng</p> <p> Han Weiguo Han Changfu Fu Zhenghua</p> <p> Xie Fuzhan Lou Yangsheng Cai Qi</p> <p> Cai Mingzhao Luo Shugang Li Huohui</p> <p> Pan Ligang Mu Hong Wei Fenghe</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC congress establishes historical position of Xi's thought: resolution ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284138</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284138.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:46:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China establishes the historical position of Xi Jinping Thought on Socialism with Chinese Characteristics for a New Era, according to a resolution approved by the congress Tuesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi's military thinking, Party's "absolute" leadership over army written into CPC Constitution ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284137</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284137.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:46:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Communist Party of China (CPC) has included Xi Jinping's military thinking and the Party's "absolute" leadership over the armed forces into its Constitution, according to a resolution approved by the 19th CPC National Congress on Tuesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC congress concludes, new Central Committee elected ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284136</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284136.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:46:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) concluded here Tuesday, after a new CPC Central Committee and a new Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) were elected.</p> <p> Delegates to the congress also passed resolutions on a report of the 18th CPC Central Committee, a work report of the CCDI and an amendment to the CPC Constitution.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC congress passes resolutions on Central Committee report, CCDI work report, Constitution amendment ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284127</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284127.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:46:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 24 (Xinhua) -- Delegates to the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Tuesday passed resolutions on a report of the 18th CPC Central Committee, a work report of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) and an amendment to the CPC Constitution, at the closing session of the congress.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Xi Jinping elected into new CPC Central Committee ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284143</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284143.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:45:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Xi Jinping was elected into the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC) at the closing session of the 19th CPC National Congress here on Tuesday.</p> <p> Xi, 64, was a member of the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau of the 18th CPC Central Committee.</p> <p> Wang Huning, Liu Qibao, Xu Qiliang, Sun Chunlan, Li Keqiang, Wang Yang, Zhang Chunxian, Zhao Leji, Hu Chunhua, Li Zhanshu and Han Zheng were elected into the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC) Tuesday at the closing of the 19th CPC National Congress in Beijing.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Li Keqiang, other Party officials in new CPC Central Committee ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284141</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284141.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:45:48 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Wang Huning, Liu Qibao, Xu Qiliang, Sun Chunlan, Li Keqiang, Wang Yang, Zhang Chunxian, Zhao Leji, Hu Chunhua, Li Zhanshu and Han Zheng were elected into the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC) here Tuesday at the closing of the 19th CPC National Congress.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC Constitution says "fight against corruption keeps going" ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284140</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284140.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:45:44 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Communist Party of China (CPC) says in its revised Constitution that the Party must "make comprehensive efforts" to ensure that "the fight against corruption keeps going", according to a resolution approved by the 19th CPC National Congress on Tuesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC elects new Central Committee in leadership transition ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284139</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284139.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 16:45:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Communist Party of China (CPC) on Tuesday unveiled a new leadership, electing the 19th CPC Central Committee to lead the Party for the coming five years.</p> <p> The 19th CPC Central Committee will in turn elect the Political Bureau, the Standing Committee of the Political Bureau and the General Secretary at its first plenary session on Wednesday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Seeing a better China through “Delegates passage” ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284161</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284161.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 13:43:48 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) set up a “delegates’ passage” on where delegates could answer questions from the press. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241323000311922899013.jpg" style="width: 586px; height: 387px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>A delegate of the 19th CPC National Congress is answering questions from medias at the delegates’ passage. (Photo by Lei Sheng from People’s Daily)</em></p> <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) set up a “delegates’ passage” on where delegates could answer questions from the press.</p> <p> The passage can help improving the transparency of the CPC and display a “three-dimensional” China, said Anil Sigdel, a political scientist and columnist from the US.</p> <p> Thanks to the passage, both officials and “grass roots” are free to express their viewpoints on specific agendas and respond to topics concerned by domestic and international societies, Sigdels said, pointing out such voices are more convincing.</p> <p> The voices from those delegates can deliver the concerns of people from different walks of life comprehensively, said the columnist, adding that this was a reflection of democracy.</p> <p> Describing the new passage as a kind of progress, Hans Hendrischke, professor of Chinese business and management at the University of Sydney Business School, told People’s Daily that it allows Western society to learn more about the CPC National Congress through a more open and transparent information releasing mechanism.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241323000499214558486.jpg" style="width: 618px; height: 412px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Foreign journalists report on the 19th CPC National Congress in the Great Hall of the People in Beijing. (Photo by Lei Sheng from People’s Daily)</em></p> <p> Chinese President Xi Jinping, in his report to the 19th National Congress of the CPC, stressed the importance of exercising strict governance over the Party and improving the Party’s ability to govern and lead.</p> <p> Yuri Tavrovskiy, a professor with Russia-based RUDN University, said he was touched by Xi’s pledge and also agreed with comments on party governance by Ling Jiefang, a Chinese writer and a five-time delegate to the Congress.</p> <p> Ling said, "If we look back on the history of China, there has never been a time that such amount of effort was made to fight against corruption like we've been doing in recent years. There has never been a CPC-led people's war against corruption like we are having now."</p> <p> The tough battle against corruption launched by the CPC in recent years is not a temporary move, but a continued endeavor to solve the problems in a fundamental way, the writer said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Live: Closing session of 19th CPC National Congress ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284047</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284047.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 09:49:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <embed allowfullscreen="true" allowscriptaccess="sameDomain" height="500" quality="high" src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/2010tv_flash/liveplayer.swf?liveInfo=5,cctven" type="application/x-shockwave-flash" width="900"></embed></p> <p> The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) started its closing session Tuesday morning, at which a new CPC Central Committee and a new Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) will be elected.</p> <p> Delegates are also expected to pass resolutions on the report of the 18th CPC Central Committee, a work report of the CCDI and an amendment to the CPC Constitution.</p> <p> The five-yearly congress, which opened on Oct. 18, was held during the decisive stage when China is building a moderately prosperous society in all respects and at a critical moment as socialism with Chinese characteristics has entered a new era.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Unveil China Outside China: US Economists Decode China’s Economy ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284034</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284034.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 09:40:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> American economists are paying close attention to how China’s economy grows. Richard Cooper, former Under Secretary of State for Economic Affairs, first went to China in 1979 and personally witnessed China’s leap-forward development.</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/10/24/51c60a00-0f0c-4c71-8b33-6653be75814c.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p> How has the nation changed in the past decades? How do American economists decode the world’s second largest economy? What aspects of China’s economic policies are they looking at?</p> <p> Watch this video to find out.</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710240923000557678918221.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 414px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Unveil China Outside China: US Economists Decode China’s Economy</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ CPC top leadership to meet press on Wednesday ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284006</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284006.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 09:14:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710240913000465620350304.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 477px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Xi Jinping presides over the fourth meeting of the presidium of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 23, 2017. (Xinhua/Lan Hongguang)</em></p> <p> Top leaders of the Communist Party of China (CPC) will meet the press Wednesday morning.</p> <p> Members of the Standing Committee of the 19th CPC Central Committee Political Bureau, who will be elected at the first plenary session of the 19th CPC Central Committee, are scheduled to meet Chinese and foreign journalists at the Great Hall of the People at about 11:45 a.m. Wednesday.</p> <p> The meeting will be broadcast live on Chinese television and radio as well as online.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ At least 8 pct of CPC Central Committee nominees voted off ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283955</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9283955.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 08:51:41 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710240849000542010933406.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 392px;" /></p> <p> <em>The presidium of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) holds its fourth meeting at the Great Hall of the People in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 23, 2017. Xi Jinping, Li Keqiang, Zhang Dejiang, Yu Zhengsheng, Liu Yunshan, Wang Qishan and Zhang Gaoli attended the meeting. (Xinhua/Lan Hongguang)</em></p> <p> At least 8 percent of nominees for candidates for members and alternate members of the 19th Central Committee of the Communist Party of China (CPC) and candidates for members of the Central Commission for Discipline Inspection (CCDI) have been voted off in preliminary elections in the past days.</p> <p> The draft name lists of candidates for members and alternate members of the new CPC Central Committee and candidates for members of the new CCDI were approved at the third and fourth meetings of the presidium of the 19th CPC National Congress on Sunday evening and Monday morning.</p> <p> At the presidium meetings presided over by Xi Jinping, a decision was made to submit the draft name lists to the delegations to the Party congress for consideration.</p> <p> Delegates held that the name lists were formed on the basis of full intra-Party democracy. The overall structure of the lists is reasonable and the candidates have fine ethical and political quality, outstanding work performance and high public support.</p> <p> The preliminary elections were conducted under the supervision of scrutineers in accordance with the election methods adopted at the congress. The results of the preliminary elections are valid, according to the presidium.</p> <p> Members and alternate members of the new CPC Central Committee and members of the new CCDI will be elected at the closing meeting of the Party congress Tuesday morning.</p> <p> The CPC adopted a preliminary election system at its eighth national congress in 1956. At the 13th national congress in 1987, it began to follow a competitive election system at preliminary elections.</p> <p> The elimination margins at preliminary elections for candidates for members of the 16th Central Committee and the 16th CCDI, conducted in 2002, were about 5 percent. The ratios exceeded 8 percent at the 17th congress in 2007 and the 18th congress in 2012.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Backgrounder: How is CPC Central Committee elected? ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283808</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1023/c90000-9283808.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 20:21:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 23 (Xinhua) -- The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) will elect a new Central Committee before the congress concludes Tuesday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 23 (Xinhua) -- The 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) will elect a new Central Committee before the congress concludes Tuesday.</p> <p> The National Congress and the Central Committee it elects represent the highest leading body of the Party, according to the CPC Constitution.</p> <p> When the National Congress is not in session, the Central Committee carries out its resolutions, directs the entire work of the Party and represents the Party in its external relations.</p> <p> The Central Committee meets in plenary session at least once a year, and such sessions are convened by its Political Bureau. The Political Bureau reports its work to these sessions and accepts their oversight.</p> <p> The Central Committee is elected for a term of five years.</p> <p> The Party Constitution stipulates that members and alternate members of the Central Committee must have a Party standing of five years or more.</p> <p> According to the Party Constitution, the election shall be held by secret ballot.</p> <p> The number of members and alternate members of the Central Committee shall be determined by the National Congress.</p> <p> Tuo Zhen, spokesman for the 19th CPC congress, said the method of multi-candidate competitive election will be applied.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>