<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Business </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90778</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China expected to complete first sea launch for commercial payloads in 2018 ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288601</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288601.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 16:58:55 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ China is expected to complete its first sea launch for commercial payloads in 2018, said Yang Baohua, vice general manager of China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASTC). ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1103/FOREIGN201711031658000131043947572.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 336px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>SpaceX Falcon 9 rocket lands on a drone ship at sea. (File photo)</em></p> <p> China is expected to complete its first sea launch for commercial payloads in 2018, said Yang Baohua, vice general manager of China Aerospace Science and Technology Corporation (CASTC).</p> <p> Yang made the remarks at an annual academic conference on space science held from November 1 to 2 in Beijing.</p> <p> The service will also be provided in other regions in addition to its four major sites in Jiuquan, Taiyuan, Xichang, and Wenchang, Yang noted.</p> <p> At the conference, Yang introduced the company’s experience, competence, and advantages, as well as its on-going commercial aerospace programs, and also evaluated the prospects of the commercial space industry.</p> <p> “CASTC is dedicated to offering various commercial launching solutions to meet the market demands of low cost and fast preparation,” Yang said.</p> <p> Key technological tests will be conducted for the sea launch of the Long-march rocket family this year, according to Tang Yagang, deputy director of carrier rocket development at the China Academy of Launch Vehicle Technology.</p> <p> The commercial service is expected to be available for international users in 2018. By then, the Long-march rockets will be able to send 500-kilogram satellites to an altitude of 500 kilometers above Earth, at an inclination of 0-10 degrees.</p> <p> In recent years, with the growing demand for launching near-equatorial and low-inclination satellites from countries near the equator, sea launch service has become an area of fierce competition among space powers.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s papermaking industry experiences make-over, becomes more environmentally friendly ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288616</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288616.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 16:54:01 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ China’s papermaking industry has become more environmentally friendly after years of efforts, Jia Feng, director of the Center of Environmental Education and Communications of Ministry of Environmental Protection, said in Beijing on Nov. 3. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1103/FOREIGN201711031652000527293530089.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 267px;" /></p> <p> China’s papermaking industry has become more environmentally friendly after years of efforts, Jia Feng, director of the Center of Environmental Education and Communications of Ministry of Environmental Protection, said in Beijing on Nov. 3.</p> <p> Jia made the remarks at the 2017 China Paper Industry Sustainability Forum. According to him, China’s paper industry has experienced a make-over after two decades of development.</p> <p> Papermaking enterprises used to take environmental protection as an approach to meet regulations and consumers’ needs, Jia said. Nowadays, these enterprises see green development as important for the future of the industry.</p> <p> The emission of chemical oxygen demand (COD) per 10,000 RMB ($1,510) of paper productivity stood at 54 kilograms in 2006, said Zhao Wei, chief secretary of China Paper Association. By 2016, it dropped below 5 kilograms, a reduction of over 90%.</p> <p> “The paper industry accounted for more than 50% of China’s COD reduction, making a remarkable contribution to the country’s emission reduction,” the chief secretary noted.</p> <p> Given stricter environmental policies, raised emission standards, and enhanced environmental supervision, enterprises that failed to meet the national requirements have been shut down.</p> <p> In addition, the raised threshold of environmental protection is also forcing papermakers to change their production mode.</p> <p> APP-China, short for Sinar Mas Paper (China) Investment Co., Limited, is one of the largest papermakers in China, with over 30 pulp and paper enterprises and 18 forestry companies. According to Vice President Zhai Jingli, 40% of the company’s investment this year has been spent on environmental protection. The company has invested tens of billions of RMB on effective utilization and environmental innovation.</p> <p> Jia said that green manufacturing is a long path, adding that some small-scaled paper enterprises with outdated technologies and ideas still have to further accelerate their pace.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese electric vehicle market sees more investment ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288416</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288416.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 15:36:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1103/FOREIGN201711031006000576979755645.jpg" style="width: 550px; height: 413px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> File photo</p> <p> According to a latest report of International Energy Agency, more than 750,000 EVs were sold worldwide last year, compared to 547,220 sold in 2015. China has surpassed the US to become the largest market for electric vehicles, acquiring 40% of the world’s total, twice that of the US.</p> <p> China is witnessing consistent support for new energy vehicles, including EVs. By 2020, the number of new energy vehicles sales is expected to top 2 million in a single year, according to a blueprint issued by the State Council in October. The data last year was about 507,000, while it is expected to exceed 700,000 in 2017.</p> <p> More than 4.8 million charging piles will be erected across the nation, suggesting a charging infrastructure market of over 100 billion yuan, the blueprint added. Almost all provincial regions in China have made public their ambition to build charging station networks to support the booming sales of new energy cars.</p> <p> EVs, specifically, are increasingly popular under the policy support. In 2016, the number of EVs sold in China was 256,000, up 121 percent year on year.</p> <p> Being the world’s largest market for electric vehicles, China has welcomed a latest injection of investment, which is expected to further upgrade the nation’s new energy infrastructure.</p> <p> Chinese leading car-hailing service provider Didi Chuxing on Wed unveiled its new joint venture projects to set up its own nationwide charging network for electric vehicles.</p> <p> “We have started new joint venture projects to build our own EV charging systems. Didi’s charging networks will not only cover our own fleet, but also serve families and the public,” Cheng Wei, CEO of Didi Chuxing, revealed at a sustainable energy summit jointly sponsored by the United Nations and the Global Energy Interconnection Development and Cooperation Organization (GEIDCO) on Wednesday in the US.</p> <p> International brands like Tesla also have their eyes glued to the Chinese market.</p> <p> After unveiling the plan to set up a factory in Shanghai, Elon Musk on Wednesday reportedly revealed that Tesla is expected to launch manufacturing in China within three years.</p> <p> Together with GEIDCO, Didi has set up the Global New Energy Vehicle Service Co., Ltd, whose new EV infrastructure plan is codenamed Orange Energy.</p> <p> “The future of transport is new energy vehicles, and ridesharing will be a key to promoting new energy on the road.” Cheng said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ International business alliance set up to support Digital Silk Road ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288419</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288419.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 14:45:51 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1103/FOREIGN201711031009000199056746701.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <span style="font-size:8px;"><em>(Photo courtesy of Inspur)</em></span></p> <p> A Belt and Road Digital Economy Strategic Alliance on Thursday announced its establishment in Ji’nan, eastern China’s Shandong province, aiming to integrate world-class IT resources for the Digital Silk Road.</p> <p> The alliance was initiated by Shandong-based e-information technology company Inspur and co-founded by international big names including Cisco, IBM, Diebold Nixdorf, and Ericsson. The founders vowed to integrate their cutting-edge IT products, technologies, and solutions to accelerate the construction of the Digital Silk Road.</p> <p> Three Chinese national financial institutions are also members of the alliance, the Export-Import Bank of China, China Development Bank, and China Export &amp; Credit Insurance Corporation.</p> <p> It is reportedly the first platform set up by global technology giants to serve the Belt and Road Initiative.</p> <p> “Inspur hopes to partner with top technology companies in the world and China’s national financial institutions, help countries along the Belt and Road to solve their insufficient funding and technical problems in informatization construction, and bring the benefits of digital economy development to people there,” Peter Sun, Chairman and CEO of Inspur Group, said at the alliance launching ceremony.</p> <p> Countries along the Belt and Road will be able enjoy services provided by the alliance, including new datacenters, cloud services, smart finance, smart home, smart taxation, smart cities, and other total technology solutions. Projects will first be launched in South Asian and African countries, such as Thailand, Bangladesh, Malaysia, Nigeria, Ethiopia, Tunisia, Tanzania, Zambia, and Kenya.</p> <p> More companies with top informatization products and technologies from across the globe will be gradually invited to join the alliance together with more financial institutions.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Foreign investment law enactment progresses ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288172</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288172.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 10:10:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>Move bolsters market access modernization</strong></p> <p> The enactment of China's new foreign investment law is progressing well, as the draft has been submitted for further discussion by the central government, the Ministry of Commerce announced on Thursday.</p> <p> The move illustrated the country's desire to accelerate the modernization of its market access system, as well as strengthen the use of fair and transparent market principles.</p> <p> Gao Feng, spokesman for the ministry, said the law is expected to serve as a basic guideline for the reform of regulations on foreign direct investment.</p> <p> "The government will protect the legitimate rights of foreign investors and foster a stable, transparent and law-based business environment," Gao said at a regular news conference in Beijing.</p> <p> The ministry will collaborate with the Legislative Affairs Office of the State Council to speed up the lawmaking pace in the next stage, he added.</p> <p> For the past several years, China has been ramping up efforts to expand investment access and unify laws and regulations while applying stable, transparent and predictable policies to foreign investment.</p> <p> The government has already introduced a negative-list approach in 11 pilot free trade zones to simplify the process for foreign investors in setting up their business presence in China.</p> <p> The negative list specifies investment sectors that are off-limits to foreign investors and opens industries not on the list, providing equal treating to overseas and Chinese companies.</p> <p> Gao said the ministry will replicate nationwide the negative-list approach used in its free trade zones.</p> <p> The negative list covers 15 sectors such as mining, leasing and financing. Among the sectors, 40 categories and 95 special management measures are included.</p> <p> Wei Jianguo, vice-president of the China Center for International Economic Exchanges, said the move provides a consistent national treatment for market entrance and reflects a major step forward in liberalizing the Chinese market for overseas investors.</p> <p> Researchers at accounting firm PricewaterhouseCoopers said in a report that the adoption of a negative list in the market access system apparently makes it easy for companies to invest in businesses that are neither prohibited nor have limited access.</p> <p> "The approach also strengthens post-investment supervision and enables sharing and publication of information.... Not only those businesses in FTZs will be affected, companies from outside of FTZs will sooner or later be affected," said the report.</p> <p> In the first nine months, China's FDI inflows grew by 1.6 percent year-on-year, compared with a 0.2 percent drop between January and August, according to the Ministry of Commerce.</p> <p> Zhang Jianping, a senior researcher at the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation under the Ministry of Commerce, said while there were concerns about withdrawal of foreign investment in the past, the FDI structure has improved.</p> <p> "The FDI inflow is still growing, which can offset the outflows."</p> <p> <em>Liu Yukun contributed to this story.</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's State-owned railway company to help construct Moscow subway ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288389</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288389.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 10:10:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> China's State-owned railway company will participate in Moscow's subway construction, the first time Russia has entered into a joint venture with a foreign company in subway construction.</p> <p> China Railway Construction Corporation (CRCC) told the Global Times on Thursday that the subway's base is nearing completion, and five shield tunneling machines, mainly used for construction under extremely cold conditions, had recently arrived in Moscow.</p> <p> This portion of the subway, spanning 3.8 kilometers, is located at Moscow's southwest, which consists of three subway stations and four sections, the company said.</p> <p> It added this will be completed within two-and-a-half years, and will begin service in 2020.</p> <p> The contract is worth 2.29 billion yuan ($0.34 billion).</p> <p> Moscow vice mayor Marat Khusnullin said China will open the subway line, which runs from Prospekt Vernadskogo station to Aminyevskoye Shosse station, at the start of 2018, Russian media Sputnik reported on Monday.</p> <p> The report said approximately 500 Chinese workers and engineers will also come to Moscow for the project.</p> <p> This marks the first time Russia has invited a foreign company to participate in its subway construction. It's also China's first subway project in Europe.</p> <p> CRCC said Li Chude, a member of the Standing Committee and Secretary of the Commission for Discipline Inspection of the CRCC Party Committee, inspected the job site in October.</p> <p> Premier Li Keqiang and Russian Prime Minister Dmitry Medvedev signed a joint communiqué on Wednesday, stating that the two sides should enhance cooperation on high-speed rail, including the technology, equipment and investments so a date can be set to initiate the Moscow-Kazan high-speed rail project, the Xinhua News Agency reported.</p> <p> The 770-kilometer railway will cost 1.3 trillion rubles ($22.4 billion). The trains will run at a maximum speed of 400 kilometers per hour, and will cut travel time from 14 hours to 3.5 hours, Xinhua reported.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese cities, companies jump on bid to spur rental housing ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288158</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9288158.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 17:53:22 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Nov. 2 (Xinhua) -- Major Chinese cities, developers and the financial sector are moving quickly to join a government-led campaign to develop the rental housing market. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Nov. 2 (Xinhua) -- Major Chinese cities, developers and the financial sector are moving quickly to join a government-led campaign to develop the rental housing market.</p> <p> This comes as the country's top authorities aim to provide a long-term solution to an overheated real estate market by encouraging more people to rent rather than buy.</p> <p> For a long time, soaring property prices have put urban residents under pressure, making housing affordability a growing problem for policy makers.</p> <p> Now the government wants to further tap the rental market to stabilize home prices and curb speculation, and a key is providing tenants with the same access to public services and decent living conditions that owners enjoy.</p> <p> A new house rental policy in Beijing came into effect earlier this week, guaranteeing the education rights of tenants' children and allowing those renting government-subsidized housing to have their hukou (household registration) registered and transferred to their rented homes.</p> <p> In the southern city of Guangzhou, a policy released Monday made clear that the per capita residential area in a rented house should be no smaller than 5 square meters to ensure a healthy and safe environment for tenants.</p> <p> At least 10 cities have allocated land for rental housing construction, according to data from Centaline Property.</p> <p> In Beijing, authorities plan to supply 6,000 hectares of land for residential housing by 2021, 30 percent of which will be for rental houses.</p> <p> Market players are seeing opportunities.</p> <p> China Vanke, the country's top property developer, had offered 12,000-18,000 apartments for long-term leasing as of July, aiming to increase the number to 100,000 by the end of the year, according to company chairman and CEO Yu Liang.</p> <p> AliPay, the leading mobile payment platform, announced last month it would enable users in eight cities to rent houses through the platform without having to pay deposits, based on their credit records.</p> <p> Financial innovation is catching up to give rental property managers new access to funding. A "quasi" real estate investment trust was approved last month to allow a Beijing-based condominium manager to offer retail investors securities backed against income from rental apartments, the first financial product of its kind in China.</p> <p> All these new measures are part of a plan to improve affordability and stabilize home prices in the medium to long term, according to a report from global rating agency Moody's.</p> <p> Zhang Dawei, a Centaline Property analyst, said the development of rental housing could help "avert drastic ups and downs in the property market and reduce irrational demand."</p> <p> China's once-sizzling property market has shown signs of cooling as prices have faltered in major cities amid tough government curbs. Central authorities have reiterated on many occasions that "housing is for living in, not speculation."</p> <p> For many new settlers in the cities, owning a house is too expensive while renting means less comfort, frequent moving, lack of public services and dealing with dishonest agents.</p> <p> Moody's said the push to boost rental housing would unlikely affect sales for property developers over the next six to 12 months, citing "the general desire of the Chinese to own their homes."</p> <p> The long-term potential is there: China's rental housing market will reach 4.2 trillion yuan (about 637 billion U.S. dollars) in revenue by 2030, up from 1.3 trillion yuan now, according to a research report from Orient Securities.</p> <p> However, the development of the market will require "continued government support to ensure the long-term effectiveness of aims such as cheaper land prices, facilitating funding channels and investment capital recycling, and promoting equal rights for owners and tenants," the rating agency said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Alibaba’s logistics arm helps Beats improve sales during upcoming online shopping craze ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288154</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9288154.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 17:33:27 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ Beats audio products are likely to see bigger sales during the upcoming Chinese online shopping festival thanks to the company’s cooperation with Cainiao, the logistics arm of China’s e-commerce giant Alibaba. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711021728000146245844824.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 332px;" /></p> <p> Beats audio products are likely to see bigger sales during the upcoming Chinese online shopping festival thanks to the company’s cooperation with Cainiao, the logistics arm of China’s e-commerce giant Alibaba.</p> <p> Based on presale data and artificial intelligence prediction, Cainiao has transported the hottest products of the brand to warehouses in more than 20 major cities ahead of the shopping craze that begins on Nov. 11 in a bid to further shorten delivery time.</p> <p> Turnover of the Beats online store on Tmall, Alibaba’s e-commerce platform, is expected to increase during the shopping festival, but the operating officer of the store, Wu Miaoyu, does not see logistics as an issue.</p> <p> The pre-allocation of the Beats products covers all the first- and second-tier cities, said Sun Wei, an employee of the Beats Tmall store.</p> <p> According to Sun, Cainiao’s smart allocation system can realize a 99.99% accuracy rate this year, greatly reducing the number of mis-deliveries.</p> <p> In addition, through artificial intelligence, Cainiao will, for the first time, realize real-time prediction of total shipment and transport capacity in order to avoid the busiest express delivery companies and thus possible delays.</p> <p> After Beats’ cooperation with Cainiao, it only takes less than 24 hours for the customers to receive their orders.</p> <p> On a recent promotion day, sales of Beats headsets on the Tmall store were several times higher than normal. However, Cainiao helped the store send out 70% of the orders on the same day, and 80% of the orders were received within 2 days.</p> <p> “This was never imaginable before,” Wu said.</p> <p> Faster delivery will improve the shopping experience of Beats followers, Wu noted, adding that it also means lower cost and higher efficiency for the merchants.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Freight train carries China-made engines to France ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288085</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9288085.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:54:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> WUHAN, Nov. 2 (Xinhua) -- A freight train loaded with car engines produced in China left Wuhan, capital of central China's Hubei Province, bound for Dourges in FranceThursday.</p> <p> The 3,432 engines made by China's Dongfeng Peugeot Citroen Automobile Company were ordered by French car manufacturer, Groupe PSA.</p> <p> The engines were transported via the new direct China-Europe freight train route opened on Oct. 28.</p> <p> The train will pass through Kazakhstan, Russia, Belarus, Poland and Germany, reducing the transport time to France by nearly 20 days compared with ocean shipping. The journey will take about 18 days.</p> <p> The freight train is scheduled to send the engines to France every week until March 2018.</p> <p> About 16 Wuhan-Europe freight routes have been launched since 2012, linking Wuhan with more than 60 cities in Europe, Central Asia and West Asia.</p> <p> As of Oct. 20, 277 trains carrying a total of 25,000 containers had travelled the route this year.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Norway to expand seafood exports to China after normalization of bilateral ties ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288034</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9288034.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 15:05:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ Norway is set to expand seafood exports to China because of Chinese people's rising demand of marine products and the normalization of bilateral relations after a long hiatus, according to a market research report by Norway Seafood Council (NSC), Jiemian.com reported on Nov. 1. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711021455000323582604924.jpg" style="width: 530px; height: 301px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Photo from Jiemian.com</em></p> <p> Norway is set to expand seafood exports to China because of Chinese people's rising demand of marine products and the normalization of bilateral relations after a long hiatus, according to a market research report by Norway Seafood Council (NSC), Jiemian.com reported on Nov. 1.</p> <p> Statistics shows that the export volume of seafood from Norway to China reached 115,000 tons in the first three quarters of 2017, up 32 percent on a year-on-year basis.</p> <p> Apart from Norway’s salmon and clipfish which are popular among Chinese, Norway’s other 13 seafood species, including Halibut, mackerel, and capelin, also have promising market potential in China, said Sigmund Bjørgo, Director China of NSC.</p> <p> The report pointed out that Chinese people’s consumption of the 13 seafood species saw an average annual growth rate of 17 percent from 2012 to 2017. It reached 119,000 tons in 2016, almost doubling that of 62,600 tons in 2012.</p> <p> Since supply of seafood in China has not yet met the reported market demand, NSC released a plan early this year to increase its export sales of seafood to China to 10 billion RMB ($1.51 billion) by 2025.</p> <p> According to the plan, the export volume of salmon and clipfish from Norway to China is projected to reach 156,000 tons and 40,000 tons, respectively, by 2025, and other seafood will rise too, the director noted.</p> <p> He added that he is optimistic about achieving this plan, as Norway has always provided quality seafood products that are widely recognized and China’s online and offline shopping channels have greatly improved.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's AT200 cargo drone makes maiden flight ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288009</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9288009.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 14:09:02 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- China's heaviest cargo unmanned aerial vehicle (UAV) completed its maiden flight in northwest China's Shaanxi Province Thursday.</p> <p> The AT200 drone, jointly developed by several research institutes and companies, made a successful 26-minute maiden flight, according the Institute of Engineering Thermophysics.</p> <p> With a maximum take-off weight of around 3.4 tonnes and a payload of 1.5 tonnes, the AT200 could be one of the world's most powerful civilian UAVs, according to the institute.</p> <p> Developed on a P750XL utility aircraft, the UAV has a maximum flying speed of 313 km per hour, a flight range of 2,183 kilometers and a 6,098-meter service ceiling.</p> <p> Taking off and landing can be automatically completed within 200 meters.</p> <p> It could be used to conduct freight transport in mountainous regions and on islands, according to the institute.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Didi Chuxing lays out nationwide charging networks for electric vehicles ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288010</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9288010.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 14:08:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711021408000059115460980.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 335px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> (File photo of a charging station in Beijing)</p> <p> Chinese leading car-hailing service provider Didi Chuxing has stride out to set up its own charging network for electric vehicles (EV) nationwide.</p> <p> Over 260,000 EVs are running on DiDi’s network out of a global total of 2 million, making DiDi the world’s largest EV fleet operator. By 2020, Didi will be serving 1 million EVs on its platform, which will then be able to enjoy the charging network, Cheng Wei, CEO of Didi Chuxing, revealed at a sustainable energy summit jointly sponsored by the United Nations and the Global Energy Interconnection Development and Cooperation Organization (GEIDCO) on Wednesday local time in the US.</p> <p> “We have started new joint venture projects to build our own EV charging systems. DiDi’s charging networks will not only cover our own fleet. It will also serve families and the public.” Cheng noted.</p> <p> Together with GEIDCO, Didi has set up the Global New Energy Vehicle Service Co., Ltd, whose new EV infrastructure plan is coded as Orange Energy.</p> <p> “The future of transport is new energy vehicles, and ridesharing will be a key link in promoting new energy on the road.” Cheng said.</p> <p> According to International Energy Agency (IEA), more than 750,000 EVs were sold worldwide last year, compared to 547,220 sold in 2015. China has surpassed the US to be the largest carrier of electric vehicles, acquiring 40% of the EVs sold in the world, twice as big as the US.</p> <p> Besides its renewable energy projects, DiDi also invests heavily in environmentally-friendly mobility technologies, from carpooling to on-demand minibus service, to address urban congestion and pollution. In 2016, DiDi’s main carpooling services reduced road carbon emission by 1.44 million tons.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China expected to turn the tide of global car industry with AI technology ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287648</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c202936-9287648.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 08:37:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" desc="Experts discuss at a panel discussion at the Future Forum on Oct.29 in Beijing. (Photo courtesy of Future Forum)" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711020835000560128773542.jpg" style="width: 586px; height: 391px;" /></p> <p class="desc" style="text-align: center;"> Experts discuss at a panel discussion at the Future Forum on Oct.29 in Beijing. (Photo courtesy of Future Forum)</p> <p> After 60 years of development, the rapidly advancing AI industry has yet to usher in a modern age the way Isaac Newton did with physics, but this provides a good opportunity for countries like China to turn the tide.</p> <p> Addressing a panel discussion on Oct.29 at the Future Forum in Beijing, Wang Jin, founder of JingChi Corp, a self-driving technology company based in the US state of California, said he believes the global car industry now faces a chance to breakthrough, as competition heats up among several major players, namely the US, China, Germany, and Japan.</p> <p> China has poured huge investment into technology research and development. The time has come for China to join the competition over the leading role in the century-old automobile industry with its advantages in technology, noted Wang, who is also a former senior vice president of Baidu.</p> <p> Figures released at the forum show that China is taking over the US in the number of thesis papers published on AI. Some 43 percent are written by Chinese scholars.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" desc="Engineers test in a self-driving car at Jingchi Corp (Photo courtesy of Jinchi Corp)" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1102/FOREIGN201711020836000321865301513.jpg" style="width: 624px; height: 416px;" /></p> <p class="desc" style="text-align: center;"> Engineers test in a self-driving car at Jingchi Corp (Photo courtesy of Jinchi Corp)</p> <p> China’s outstanding performance on AI studies is not only demonstrated through the number of theses, but through many champion titles in international challenges.</p> <p> On Oct.29, a Chinese AI company for the first time claimed the top of the world’s computer vision competition of Microsoft Common Objects in Context (MS COCO) Challenge in Venice, Italy. The company, Megvii, beat Microsoft, Google, Facebook, and other global tech giants, as well as many top universities including Carnegie Mellon University.</p> <p> After its sweeping victory in the world’s only competition that gathers Google, Microsoft, and Facebook at the same time, Megvii announced on Oct.31 that it has completed a C-round financing of some $460 million, a world record in AI financing, Caijing Magazine reported.</p> <p> Meanwhile, experts at the forum pointed out that the world is craving for more AI talents, and China is one of the most eager ones.</p> <p> According to leading AI expert Li Feifei from Stanford University, the demands for AI talents across the globe greatly exceed the supply. The imbalance exists not only in academia, but also in business, requiring more AI education and research.</p> <p> “The situation is worse in China, as it only started to getting its hands on AI about 10 years ago, hence the inadequate talent pools,” Zhou Zhihua, vice dean of the Department of Computer Science and Technology at Nanjing University told the panel, adding that few companies seeking AI talents are willing to help with AI education, and are looking for talents from other companies and research institutes.</p> <p> Wang agreed that the scarcity of AI talents in China is greater than that in the US, taking the example of salary for AI-related employees. One tends to see up to 15 percent salary raise in China when transferred from the US, but it would be a decrease if one transferred from China to the US.</p> <p> Professor Dawn Song from the Department of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science at the University of California, Berkeley, said that the focus should be on fundamental research, even though companies want fast solutions rather than long-term cultivation, because this can beef up their problem-solving abilities when needed.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China acts to evaluate burden reduction measures for enterprises ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287622</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287622.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 07:51:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Nov. 1 (Xinhua) -- The State Council, China's cabinet, has started a nationwide overhaul of measures to ease the corporate burden.</p> <p> The items to be reviewed include cost reduction, arbitrary administrative charges and service mechanisms.</p> <p> Much emphasis is put on addressing problems that impede enterprises, according to the State Council.</p> <p> The inspection was divided into three phases -- self-inspection, field supervision and rectification -- at a joint inter-ministerial meeting of the State Council committee for reducing enterprise costs.</p> <p> The country is on the way reducing corporate costs by 1 trillion yuan (about 147 billion U.S. dollars) this year.</p> <p> A government report this year said multiple measures would cut costs for companies, the structural tax cut should pay off as much as possible and a straightforward, transparent and fairer tax regime was in the pipeline.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s VR market could reach 55 billion yuan by 2020: think tank ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287610</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287610.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 17:29:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The total value of China’s virtual reality market will likely exceed 55 billion yuan ($8.3 billion) by 2020, according to CCID, a Beijing-based think tank. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011726000596121055820.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 202px;" /></p> <p> The total value of China’s virtual reality market will likely exceed 55 billion yuan ($8.3 billion) by 2020, according to CCID, a Beijing-based think tank.</p> <p> With VR facilities reaching 8.2 million and the number of VR users surpassing 25 million, China’s VR market will account for 34.6 percent of the world’s total, CCID forecasted. The organization said that revenue in the sector will reach $10 billion globally this year.</p> <p> The VR industry began to grow in 2016, and has been applied to a wide range of areas, including military, space and aviation, equipment manufacturing, medical science, education, tourism, e-commerce, and other sectors close to people’s life, said Zhao Qinping from the Chinese Academy of Engineering and a member of the Industry of Virtual Reality Alliance, China’s first government-endorsed VR industry alliance.</p> <p> The government pays close attention to advancing VR technologies. In May 2016, the Central Committee of the Communist Party of China and the State Council released an innovation-driven development strategy to enhance research on VR technologies and apply VR to more industries.</p> <p> A document to promote the healthy and orderly development of the internet released in January also stressed to step up efforts to develop key technologies such as VR, artificial intelligence, and augmented reality.</p> <p> Talent shortages and lack of technologies for sustainable innovation are two difficulties to address, among others, Zhao said, adding that some start-ups are in need of policy and financial support from governments to attract more talents and investment and improve management.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai listed firms see double-digit earnings growth ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287582</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287582.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 16:47:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ SHANGHAI, Nov. 1 (Xinhua) -- Firms listed on the Shanghai stock exchange saw double-digit revenue and profit growth in the first nine months of the year, boosted by a resilient economy, the exchange said Wednesday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, Nov. 1 (Xinhua) -- Firms listed on the Shanghai stock exchange saw double-digit revenue and profit growth in the first nine months of the year, boosted by a resilient economy, the exchange said Wednesday.</p> <p> By the end of October, 1,368 firms had published their quarterly reports, with nearly 60 percent posting revenue and profit growth, it said.</p> <p> Statistics showed that the combined revenue reached 20.67 trillion yuan (3.1 trillion U.S. dollars) in the January-September period, up 17.7 percent year on year, the exchange said.</p> <p> Meanwhile, combined profit totalled 2.04 trillion yuan, up 16.7 percent year on year.</p> <p> China's supply-side structural reform has improved the earnings of traditional companies while firms from many new industries reported robust growth, a sign of improved economic growth, the bourse said.</p> <p> Non-financial companies reported a combined revenue of 16.08 trillion yuan, up 21.3 percent year on year. Their net earnings rose 39.5 percent to 760 billion yuan.</p> <p> During the period, China's four biggest state-owned banks saw non-performing loans ratios down by 0.02 to 0.4 percentage points from the end of last year.</p> <p> Meanwhile, the four leading insurance companies, namely China Life, Ping An Insurance, China Taiping and New China Insurance, saw net profits rise 30 percent year on year to 109.1 billion yuan.</p> <p> In the first three quarters, more than 180 new firms were listed on the Shanghai stock exchange. They posted 17.7 percent growth in revenue and 28.1 percent growth in net profit.</p> <p> China's benchmark Shanghai Composite Index closed 0.08 percent higher at 3,395.91 points Wednesday. It has gained 9.4 percent this year.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Economic Watch: Supply-side structural reform: next chapter in China's "new era" ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287559</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287559.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:57:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Nov. 1 (Xinhua) -- As China steps into a "new era" of development, the next chapter is beginning for the country's supply-side structural reform with a stronger focus on supply quality and economic rebalancing.</p> <p> The reform, initiated two years ago, was set as the main task for economic growth at the recent 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC), as the consensus was reached that China's economy has been transitioning from a phase of rapid growth to a stage of high-quality development, and more attention must be paid to quality and efficiency than speed.</p> <p> The past two years have been fruitful. Progress has being made on major tasks including cutting excess capacity, destocking, deleveraging, reducing costs and shoring up weak areas, laying the base for future reforms.</p> <p> The advancing of supply-side structural reform has improved the supply-demand structure, and companies have enjoyed better profitability and lower production costs, said He Ping, statistician with the National Bureau of Statistics (NBS).</p> <p> In the first three quarters on this year, industrial companies with annual revenue of more than 20 million yuan (about 3 million U.S. dollars) reported a 22.8 percent of profit growth, faster than the 21.6 percent recorded from January-August, NBS data showed.</p> <p> Efforts in supply-side structural reform have also lowered financial risks. At the end of September, the debt-asset ratio of large industrial companies had dropped 0.6 percentage points from a year ago to 55.7 percent.</p> <p> However, more needs to be done in a changing economic landscape. Given the solid progress, more focus will now be put onto improving the supply system quality, which will be a key direction for building a modernized economy for the following stage, according to economists.</p> <p> After a long period of breakneck growth, the Chinese market for major products has become oversupplied, and the demand steering the Chinese economy has shifted from product quantity to quality, according to Zhang Liqun with the State Council's Development Research Center.</p> <p> "It is the most important and necessary change for a new development stage," said Zhang.</p> <p> In the "new era," instead of high GDPgrowth, China will pursue fairness and common prosperity, support underdeveloped regions and speed up technological innovation and industrial upgrading, according to Jiang Chao, chief economist at Haitong Securities.</p> <p> China has previously set targets to double its economic size in the first two decades of this century, but no such targets were mentioned during the 19th CPC National Congress, which outlined a two-step approach to making China into a great modern socialist country.</p> <p> "For the economy, the most prominent problem now is growth quality, and we need to address unbalanced and inadequate development through changes in quality, efficiency and growth drivers," said Yang Weimin, deputy head of the Office of the Central Leading Group on Financial and Economic Affairs.</p> <p> China will accelerate the real economy, build itself into a manufacturer of quality products, while moving its industries toward the medium-high end of the global value chain and fostering a number of world-class advanced manufacturing clusters.</p> <p> To bring forward the supply-side structural reform, strides are expected in both the upgrading of traditional industries and the development of emerging and high-tech industries, said Lian Ping, an economist at the Bank of Communications.</p> <p> Industries like the internet, big data, and artificial intelligence will be further integrated with the real economy, with new growth areas and growth drivers to be fostered in medium-high end consumption, innovation-driven development, the green and low-carbon economy, the sharing economy and modern supply chains, Lian said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s nuclear power could see major progress in 10-15 years ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287542</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287542.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:51:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The next 10 to 15 years may be an important opportunity for the advancement of nuclear power in China, said a nuclear power official, news site thepaper.cn reported. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011549000446421794388.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 346px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Tianwan Nuclear Power Station in Jiangsu province. (File photo)</em></p> <p> The next 10 to 15 years may be an important opportunity for the advancement of nuclear power in China, said a nuclear power official, news site thepaper.cn reported.</p> <p> The Chinese mainland has 37 nuclear units in service with a capacity of 35.63 million kilowatts. They generated 182.9 billion kilowatt hours of electricity in the first nine months of this year, 4.2 percent of the country’s total power and an increase of 21.37 percent, Qin Zhijun, deputy director of the National Energy Administration’s nuclear power division, said at a press conference on October 31.</p> <p> Qin said China has 19 nuclear power reactors under construction, more than any other country, with a combined installed capacity of 21.87 million kilowatts.</p> <p> Over the past 10 years, the industry’s level of innovation has been improved markedly, driven and supported by major and special projects to advance nuclear power technologies, Qin said.</p> <p> China is now able to manufacture six to eight sets of nuclear power facilities per year, and some 85 percent of the third-generation reactors can be made domestically.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s “Double 11” online shopping day no longer restricted to Internet platform ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287529</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287529.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:47:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011540000340540450322.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Daniel Zhang, CEO of Alibaba</em></p> <p> China’s “Double 11” online shopping day is now offline too.</p> <p> “Double 11,” China’s annual online shopping spree that begins on Dec. 11, will no longer be restricted to the Internet starting this year, said a senior executive of the country’s e-commerce giant Alibaba during a recent interview.</p> <p> The online business has already evolved into a form of “new retail” that integrates both online and offline channels, said Chris Tung, chief marketing officer of Alibaba.</p> <p> Alibaba’s online shopping platform Tmall held a press conference on the “Double 11” global shopping festival on Tuesday.</p> <p> Daniel Zhang, CEO of the e-commerce titan, noted that a whole new shopping experience has been created through online and offline integrations.</p> <p> Zhang said over 1 million stores from home and abroad have integrated their online and offline services. This year, 52 core commercial circles, 100,000 smart stores, 600,000 retail shops, 50,000 reputable shops, and 30,000 rural service centers will be participating in the shopping craze.</p> <p> The shopping festival this year is a panorama of Alibaba’s economic ecology, covering physical commodities, digital products, entertainment, online-offline interaction, urban and rural services, as well as domestic and overseas business, said Zhang.</p> <p> Tung told thepaper.cn that instead of being a retailer, Alibaba places more importance on the establishment of data-driven retail models, hoping to inject impetus to offline stores with big data technology.</p> <p> He said Alibaba will record purchase information of offline customers and have it processed by the databank, allowing merchants to conduct their secondary operations for targeted consumers.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese bus maker Yutong launches new vehicles in Cuba ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287543</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287543.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:47:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Chinese bus maker Yutong on Tuesday presented to the Cuban market new models of buses, generating great expectations among locals and government officials at the 35th Havana International Trade Fair, the island's most important business event.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011546000010842775981.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 298px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> [File photo: yutongkeche.co.bokee.net]</p> <p> Dozens of people attending the fair, Yutong and Cuban government officials participated in the unveiling of the vehicles, which will soon be used in Havana to transport foreign visitors.</p> <p> "We brought to the fair six products and two of them are our major focus here. One is a high-end tourist bus and the other uses hybrid power which is a mix of electric energy and diesel," Hu Huaiban, Yutong's director of international business, told Xinhua.</p> <p> According to Hu, the six new models presented at the fair are adequate for the Cuban market and several technical designs have been updated.</p> <p> "With the high-end coach we hope to help upgrade tourist buses in Cuba and with the hybrid-powered one, we hope to make our contribution to energy saving and environmental protection in Cuba," he said.</p> <p> "The initial cost for a pure electric bus is relatively high and it does not suit Cuba specifically. Therefore, this year we've brought a hybrid bus for the Cuban market, the fuel-saving rate of which could reach between 25 and 35 percent," he added.</p> <p> Since the first batch of 12 buses in 2005, Yutong has sold more than 6,800 units in Cuba, occupying 70 percent of the local market.</p> <p> Yutong is a leading bus-maker in China. It exports products to over 190 countries. In 2015, it sold 67,000 buses with revenues that surpassed 500 million U.S. dollars.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Bitcoin platforms end services in China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287502</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287502.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:16:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Chinese Bitcoin trading platforms have stopped charging and cashing services today, following the government's suspension of Bitcoin trading in September as it clamped down on crypto-currencies.</p> <p> Although the platforms will stop all Bitcoin-related services in the domestic market, they will continue to run overseas platforms and operate blockchain, a key Bitcoin technology that is also used in various industries.</p> <p> Beijing-based Huobi, which used to be one of the top three Bitcoin trading platforms, has stopped all Bitcoin trading and charging business from today. Instead, they will continue operate the business in Singapore, Hong Kong and South Korea.</p> <p> Shanghai-based BTCC, China's former No. 2 Bitcoin platform, has stopped most Bitcoin-related services. It will charge users a service fee for withdrawal of existing assets from Friday as it embarks to close the trading platform quickly.</p> <p> Digital coins, including Bitcoin, are often described as finance innovation tools but they operate in a generally unregulated environment.</p> <p> The price of Bitcoin rose to US$6,300 yesterday, according to CoinDesk's Bitcoin Price Index, which offers an average of the various global platforms.</p> <p> In September, China announced a ban on individuals and organizations raising money through ICOs — a form of fundraising in which technology startups issue their own digital coins, or "tokens," to investors to access funds. The government has called ICOs "a kind of unauthorized and illegal public fundraising."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Shanghai Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Belt and Road countries eye Shaanxi FTZ ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287415</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287415.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 14:11:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011410000547898474204.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 350px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> A global promotion conference is held in the ITL section of the Shaanxi (China) Pilot Free Trade Zone on Oct 28. [Photo/itl.gov.cn]</p> <p> The Xi'an International Trade and Logistics (ITL) Park section of the Shaanxi (China) Pilot Free Trade Zone (FTZ) has attracted international attention after a global promotion conference was held in Xi'an, capital city of Shaanxi province, on Oct 28.</p> <p> A joint effort of the Xi'an ITL Park, China Council for the Promotion of International Trade and its Xi'an branch, the conference brought together 135 business representatives from 35 countries and regions involved in China's Belt and Road Initiative.</p> <p> Huang Yuhui, deputy director of the ITL administrative committee, briefed the participants on the latest developments.</p> <p> A booming e-commerce industry cluster has seen the park accommodate over 600 enterprises led by such brands as Alibaba's OneTouch, Jingdong and Suning. Online sales make up nearly 80 percent of Xi'an's total revenue.</p> <p> The new finance industry booming inside the park has become a notable new engine of further growth, owning 60 percent of the financial leasing companies in the province.</p> <p> Xi'an Deputy Mayor Dong Jinwei extended a warm welcome to attendees on behalf of the municipal government and the province's citizens.</p> <p> The establishment of the Shaanxi FTZ has strengthened Xi'an's role as an essential part of the Silk Road economic belt, while the recent 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC) announced promising prospects to Xi'an's development. The northwestern Chinese city is willing to embrace other cities, cooperating to deepen the Euro-Asia connection.</p> <p> After the conference, representatives were also shown around Xi'an Port, the Imported Wine Trading Base and the Xi'an Comprehensive Bonded Zone. Participants showed a keen interest in the ITL's inland port model, and were impressed that the international logistics system combining land, sea and air transport has dramatically reduced both time and cost.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011411000026412301479.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 350px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> A business official from the Republic of Ghana's Ministry of Trade and Industry addresses attendees. [Photo/itl.gov.cn]</p> <p> "I will share my experience of Xi'an Port with the minister back in Ghana and hope that further exchange can be enjoyed by both sides," noted a business official from the Republic of Ghana's Ministry of Trade and Industry.</p> <p> From its inauguration on April 1 to Oct 13, the Shaanxi FTZ had registered capital of 185.66 billion yuan ($27.94 billion) from 6,114 new enterprises.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011411000114813694627.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 350px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Representatives visit a product showroom in the Xi'an International Trade and Logistics Park. [Photo/itl.gov.cn]</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Big banks report higher growth in Q3 lending income ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287397</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287397.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:24:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="Big banks report higher growth in Q3 lending income" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/1/11133752632346665137.jpg" /></p> <p> An employee counts yuan banknotes at a bank in Huaibei, Anhui province, June 22, 2010. [Photo/Agencies]</p> <p> China's big four banks posted higher growth in lending income and improvements in profitability and asset quality, with average daily income of 2.5 billion yuan ($377.3 million) in the third quarter.</p> <p> The Industrial &amp;Commercial Bank of China Ltd (ICBC), the Agricultural Bank of China Ltd, the Bank of China Ltd and the China Construction Bank Corp, which had released their earnings reports by Tuesday, all saw double digit growth in net interest income, thanks to improving interest margins amid stable and healthy economic growth.</p> <p> In terms of net income growth, the Agricultural Bank of China posted 4.89 percent year-on-year growth, the highest among the big four. In terms of asset quality, the four lenders reported declining non-performing loan rates in the third quarter. The Agricultural Bank of China's NPL rate dropped, thanks to more efforts in risk management and the better macro economic environment, according to the bank.</p> <p> According to Yi Huiman, chairman of ICBC, banks are facing challenges on asset quality management, but the risks are likely to dissolve soon.</p> <p> "As economic growth enters the new normal, lenders will experience greater challenges for controlling the asset quality. But with strengthened risk management and credit quality controls, it is expected that the asset quality will improve steadily amid stable and improving macro economic conditions", said Yi during a recent conference.</p> <p> Share prices of China's biggest lenders have been rallying year-to-date despite fluctuations after profit-taking from time to time. Shares of Shanghai-listed ICBC rose from 4.4 yuan at the beginning of 2017 to 6.1 yuan at the end of October, a 38.6 percent growth. Shares of the Agricultural Bank of China rose from 3.1 yuan to 3.7 yuan during the same time, a 19.4 percent gain.</p> <p> Analysts said that as more lenders are refocusing on supporting real economy growth and meeting financing needs after market-oriented research and studies, banks are likely to become more quality-focused.</p> <p> "The performance of lenders is expected to further improve in the fourth quarter as profit margins recover and risks dissolve, with rising rate of return on equity (ROE) supporting valuation growth," said a research note from CITIC Securities.</p> <p> Investors can closely watch the fundamentals of banks, as most of the growth in the lending sector is driven by fundamentals, such as profitability in lending and intermediate business income such as commissions, said Ma Kunpeng, an analyst with China Merchants Securities in a research note.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China urges U.S. to abide by WTO rules in anti-dumping investigation ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287240</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287240.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:26:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The U.S. conclusion on anti-dumping of aluminum foil from China was "a serious distortion" of real situation, the Ministry of Commerce (MOC) said Tuesday.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711010924000024512942423.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 332px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> File photo</p> <p> The MOC made the statement in response to the U.S. decision on China's status as a non-market economy country and launching anti-dumping investigation against aluminum foil imports from China under the "analogue country methodology."</p> <p> The U.S. ignored China's achievements in building a market economy and the conclusion was a serious distortion of the real situation, the MOC said in an online statement.</p> <p> Since reform and opening up, China has established and been improving the socialist market economy, which has been widely recognized by the international community, said the MOC.</p> <p> China urged the U.S. to fulfill international obligations and take action to correct the wrong practice, while China will take measures to protect legal rights of Chinese companies, according to the MOC.</p> <p> According to WTO requirements, anti-dumping investigations against imports from China under the "analogue country methodology" ceased on Dec. 11, 2016. The method calculates the value of products from so-called "non-market economies" using costs of production in a third country. The concept of "non-market economy country" does not exist in WTO rules.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Officials deny Tibet-Xinjiang water diversion project exists ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287115</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287115.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:26:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> <strong>Yunnan water project designed to alleviate drought in province </strong></p> <p> China dismissed a report that the country is testing techniques in preparation for the building of a tunnel to carry water from Tibet to Xinjiang, which experts also say is unrealistic.</p> <p> "This is untrue," foreign ministry spokeswoman Hua Chunying said when asked to comment at a news conference in Beijing on Tuesday about the South China Morning Post (SCMP) report.</p> <p> The SCMP on Monday quoted "experts" as saying that the ongoing construction of a 600-kilometer-long water tunnel in Southwest China's Yunnan Province would be a "rehearsal" of new technology, engineering methods and equipment needed for the tunnel, which is expected to extend as long as 1,000 kilometers, and would divert the Yarlung Zangbo River in the southern Tibet Autonomous Region to the Taklamakan Desert in the Xinjiang Uyghur Autonomous Region.</p> <p> China was now taking a "quiet, step-by-step approach to bring it to life," the report quoted an expert surnamed Zhang, who "has played a key role in many major Chinese water tunnel projects," as saying.</p> <p> The chief engineer of the Yunnan water tunnel project dismissed the report when interviewed by the Global Times. "There is no such direction from the central government, and I've never heard of any plan laid out for a Tibet-Xinjiang tunnel project," said Zhao Shijie, chief engineer of the Dianzhong water diversion project, a scheme in central Yunnan.</p> <p> Zhao told the Global Times that it is not the first time he has heard rumors about a Tibet-Xinjiang tunnel, but they are baseless.</p> <p> The Yunnan water diversion project which involves tunnel construction works exceeding 600 kilometers is designed to address a severe water shortage in the province's central region. It began on August 4.</p> <p> According to the People's Daily on August 7, with a total length of 661.07 kilometers, the diversion project will bring water from the Jinsha River to cities including Lijiang and Kunming. The construction is expected to take 96 months.</p> <p> The total fund for the Yunnan water diversion project is estimated at more than 78 billion yuan ($11.8 billion), according to a budget released in the second quarter of 2016, reported Yunnan.cn.</p> <p> <strong>Huge cost</strong></p> <p> The idea of sending Tibetan water to Xinjiang dates back to the late 1950s. "March into the Desert," a famous article by meteorologist, geologist and educator Zhu Kezhen (1890-1974) that has long featured in Chinese schoolbooks, advises diverting water to Xinjiang's arid plains.</p> <p> A plan to divert water from Tibet to the northern parts of China was heatedly discussed in the 1990s. Over the decade, 208 lawmakers and 118 political advisers raised proposals and motions on the plan, according to a 2006 report by the Southern Weekly.</p> <p> However, the dream of massive water diversions has never been approved due to concerns of the huge cost and potential for damaging the landscape.</p> <p> "I firmly oppose the project, as Xinjiang cannot afford this project," said Mei Xinyu, an associate researcher at the Chinese Academy of International Trade and Economic Cooperation.</p> <p> The estimated cost of diverting water from Tibet to Xinjiang would be five times that of Xinjiang's annual GDP.</p> <p> It may depend massively on central government subsidies and the assistance of local governments in other regions, which likely would lead to social instability, Mei added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Changes weighed to help farmers keep land rights ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287117</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287117.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:26:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="Changes weighed to help farmers keep land rights" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/74/16620397100721286458.jpg" /></p> <p> Farmers of an agricultural cooperative in Liuzhou, Guangxi Zhuang autonomous region, walk back home after a day's work in October. LONG TAO/CHINA DAILY</p> <p> Draft submitted to lawmakers would extend rental contracts</p> <p> China will strengthen its protections of farmers' rights and interests by extending the current round of rural land contracts for another 30 years, if a draft revision of the Rural Land Contracting Law is passed by the nation's top legislature.</p> <p> The proposed change aims to maintain the long-term stability and consistency of rural land contracts. It was submitted at a bimonthly session of the Standing Committee of the National People's Congress for its first reading on Tuesday.</p> <p> The 30-year extension was mentioned in a report delivered by Xi Jinping, general secretary of the Communist Party of China, at the opening session of the 19th CPC National Congress on Oct 18.</p> <p> Liu Zhenwei, deputy director of the NPC's Agriculture and Rural Affairs Committee, said the current law has played a key role in rural economic development, keeping order in rural areas and increasing the incomes of farmers since it took effect in 2003.</p> <p> "But to meet higher requirements of rural development, it needs a revision," Liu said.</p> <p> The draft revision will better define the use rights of rural land, so that farmers can enjoy "sufficient and guaranteed protection of their land rights", he said.</p> <p> Since the country adopted the household responsibility system in the early 1980s, property rights associated with rural land have been divided into two layers: the ownership right, referring to its collective ownership by a rural community (normally a village), and the use right that is held by an individual household that contracts a piece of land from the village.</p> <p> The draft revision further separates the use right into the "contract right" and "management right", according to Liu, who regarded it as a positive innovation.</p> <p> The separation, as proposed by the draft, would allow farmers to retain contract right over their allowed land, and only transfer the management right if they choose to lease the land to others, mortgage it to banks or invest it in a cooperative in exchange for shares.</p> <p> More than 30 percent of rural households have transferred their contracted land, totaling 31.9 million hectares, Liu said.</p> <p> "In the past, we sometimes hesitated to rent more land out of concern that our business might suffer if the status of the land changed when the contract runs out. That's because the current law limits our leasing rights to 30 years," said Jin Weiran, who has rented rural land to plant vegetables in Rizhao, Shandong province, since 2007. "But now, I feel reassured."</p> <p> "Xi's report and the draft revision means that what I paid in the rented land in the first several years can be rewarded after the land contract is extended," he said.</p> <p> Yu Liufen, Party chief of Yanbo village in Guizhou province, said land is the farmers' lifeline, and they will no longer worry about uncertainties if the extension is approved.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Capital Airlines first Qingdao-Sydney direct flight touches down in Sydney ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287011</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1031/c90000-9287011.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 14:13:43 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311408000089142308650.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Capital Airlines first Qingdao-Sydney direct flight touches down in Sydney (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</em></p> <p> SYDNEY, Oct. 30 (People’s Daily Online) -- On 30 October 2017, Sydney International Airport celebrated its first direct flight between Qingdao and Sydney operated by Capital Airlines. As this year marks China-Australia Year of Tourism, this new route will further deepen the friendly relations between China and Australia and promote the two cities' direct business and tourism cooperation.</p> <p> Only two months after New South Wales announced its partnership with Capital Airlines, this new service will operate four times a week on an A330-200 aircraft with 222 seats.</p> <p> “It is against that big backdrop that we gather here to celebrate the opening of the new en route and the more efficient way to bring people together so that we can brainstorm and get down to business to make sure that in each and every area where China and New South Wales, China and Australia have the desire to collaborate, there are opportunities,” said Ms. Wang Hongbo, Commercial Counselor, the Economic and Commercial Section of the Chinese Consulate-General in Sydney.</p> <p> Parliamentary Secretary to the Premier and the Treasurer of NSW, Mr. Jonathan O’Dea, says that this opportunity is both a great win for Sydney’s tourism industry and also a great win for China’s Shandong province.</p> <p> “With a population of 9 million people, Qingdao is a key growth market for New South Wales, and today’s inaugural service with the Capital Airlines flight arriving more than on time and in great condition will be the first of many flights to come,” said Mr. O’Dea.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311409000020807503557.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Capital Airlines first Qingdao-Sydney direct flight touches down in Sydney (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</em></p> <p> The tourism market in Sydney and New South Wales as a whole is booming, and much of that is being driven by China.</p> <p> Mr. O’Dea is excited to see the many other potential opportunities the new Capital Airlines Service will bring “from what is no doubt [the] most valuable and fastest growing international market”.</p> <p> Ms Kerrie Mather, Managing Director and CEO of Sydney Airport, believes that this new airline will help boost tourism and business to Sydney. This service is expected to bring 24,000 additional Chinese visitors a year and generate 100 million AU dollars in additional visitor expenditure in New South Wales.</p> <p> As Sydney is the one of the world’s most famous and beautiful cities, Mr. Qu Tao, Vice President of Capital Airlines said that airline was excited to be launching its new service in such a city.</p> <p> “Australia is an important inbound source market for Shandong and one of the favourite tourism destinations for many Shandong tourists,” said Mr. Qu.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311409000391608053345.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Qu Tao, Vice President of Capital Airlines delivers a speech (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311410000103113233169.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Wang Hongbo, Commercial Counsellor of the Chinese Consulate-General in Sydney delivers a speech. (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311410000200643916891.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Jonathan O’Dea, Parliamentary Secretary to the Premier and the Treasurer of NSW delivers a speech. (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311410000291940987160.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Kerrie Mather, Managing Director and CEO of Sydney Airport delivers a speech. (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311410000380094607908.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Capital Airlines first Qingdao-Sydney direct flight touches down in Sydney (Photo by Chuyi Sheng, People's Daily Online)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Letter to Editor: American fast food hits a 30 year milestone in China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286925</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1031/c90000-9286925.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 13:20:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311319000371160591867.jpg" style="width: 732px; height: 508px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>（Photo: kfc.com.cn）</em></p> <p> It all began in Beijing. By November 1987, the city was already catering to this fast food phenomenon, which had gone worldwide since the 1960s.</p> <p> In the ancient Middle Kingdom, American fast food expanded in cities from north to south and east and west.</p> <p> People in China are crazy about KFC. It’s one of the most popular franchises to hit this country in three decades along with McDonalds, Pizza Hut, and Starbucks. These four fast food franchises are the top four in this nation of 1.4 billion people.</p> <p> Ah yes, fast food in China. It doesn’t only hold to a deeper meaning of quick, easy, and good. Fast food has become a symbol of prosperity and development for the millennial generation in the PRC (People’s Republic of China).</p> <p> Of course KFC, like the rest, are processed foods that will fatten the waistline if eaten constantly or more than once a week.</p> <p> The food is fattening, but who cares when KFC is about to hit its 30 year milestone.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1031/FOREIGN201710311320000086743558648.jpg" style="width: 732px; height: 329px;" /></p> <p> Think about it, the original menu in Beijing started with the original chicken recipe and a side of mash potatoes with gravy. As KFC came to China, in honor of and respect for Chinese culture, the menu evolved. “Lao Beijing-chicken wrap” was added to the menu, in the same fashion as Beijing-duck wrap. That menu item remains one of its most popular alongside the chicken burger. By the way, I love them too! And today, the menu has dozens of varieties to choose from, whether it’s morning or afternoon.</p> <p> KFC’s origins began simple enough, with a man from the US state of Kentucky called Colonel Sanders who never gave up on his dreams of selling his original recipe around the world. He persisted through constant rejection till he mastered his recipe after his 1,000th try. An investor converted his idea into a franchise. He made $2 million ($15 million in today’s money) from the deal. Considering what KFC has become, his idea was worth billions.</p> <p> KFC paved the way for markets like McDonalds, which entered the Chinese market in 1990 followed by Starbucks in 1999. Pizza Hut also entered China in 1990.</p> <p> In some major cities, you can easily find at least three KFCs sprawled within a four-block radius. That’s how popular this fast food chain has become.</p> <p> The top four franchises are favorites amongst Chinese elders, their children, and certainly their grandchildren. And truthfully, too much of it will expand the waistline, but what the heck...</p> <p> If a person has the means and the desire, then it’s best to enjoy during this third-decade anniversary.</p> <p> And in the meantime, while America’s fast-food culture is a symbol of cheap food, for Chinese, it’s a new measure of wealth, status, and success, which they’re enjoying throughout this land in the form of fast food.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to become top destination of LatAm exports in 2017: ECLAC ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286775</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1031/c90000-9286775.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 09:44:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SANTIAGO, Oct. 30 -- China will become the leading destination for exports from Latin America and the Caribbean in 2017, with growth of 23 percent this year, according to a new report by the UN Economic Commission for Latin America and the Caribbean (ECLAC).</p> <p> ECLAC's executive secretary, Alicia Barcena, unveiled the annual report on the region's trade on Monday in Santiago and said that exports would bounce back by 10 percent in 2017, after five years of slowdown.</p> <p> "I think there have been many important steps between China and Latin America and the Caribbean. Now, the most important (objective) is to diversify the basket of exports so Chinese companies invest in our region," Barcena told Xinhua during a press conference.</p> <p> According to Barcena, future increases can be seen between China and Latin America by adding value to agricultural goods, which are in high demand.</p> <p> "Foodstuffs are very important to China and what better than to produce them here, where agriculture must be a sector large enough to continuously be worked on," she said.</p> <p> Barcena also referred to technology, a sector which is booming in China, and called on countries to seek mutual benefits.</p> <p> "China has made great advances in this direction recently. Our task must be to seek cooperation plans in this area. We must take advantage of 'The Belt &amp; Road Initiative,' which must first connect Asia to Europe and then expand to us. We must continue with positive plans, such as the (undersea) cable that will unite China and Chile," she indicated.</p> <p> ECLAC pointed out that exports of Latin America and the Caribbean have increased all around the world, rising 17 percent to Asia and 9 percent to the U.S. However, the region's trade with Europe is not performing as well, only growing by 6 percent.</p> <p> Another positive mark is that imports also stopped a four-year fall and are set to rise by 7 percent in 2017, a good sign at a time of economic and geopolitical uncertainty, said the report.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China promotes internet plus manufacturing to boost innovation and competitiveness ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286631</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1031/c90000-9286631.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 07:32:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 30 (Xinhua) -- China will speed up the development of internet plus advanced manufacturing to boost innovation and entrepreneurship and integration between enterprises of various sizes to enable further upgrading of the economy.</p> <p> The decision was made at a State Council executive meeting chaired by Premier Li Keqiangon Monday.</p> <p> The integration between the internet and the real economy will be further deepened, and the development of the Industrial Internet will be accelerated through the implementation of the Made in China 2025 strategy in an effort to transform the nation into a global leader in the Industrial Internet, according to the decision made at the meeting.</p> <p> "Pushing forward the internet plus advanced manufacturing is an important measure to enable the transformation and upgrading of the real economy. China owes the fast development of its new growth engines to its abundant human resources and talents, vast market and the prudent yet accommodating government oversight," Li said.</p> <p> The meeting decided that the construction and upgrading of network infrastructure in industrial enterprises will be vigorously pursued to enable greater inter-connectivity within enterprises and between production equipment and information systems in different areas, both upstream and downstream. The integration and sharing of manufacturing resources and data will be promoted, while a coordinated manufacturing system linking all industries and businesses will be developed.</p> <p> The development and promotion of industrial cloud platforms will be boosted. Leading enterprises will be encouraged to develop enterprise-level cloud platforms. SMEs will receive support in uploading their business systems to cloud platforms. A public platform that supports mass entrepreneurship and innovation will be established. Technical support will be enhanced to develop a standard system of the Industrial Internet. The R&amp;D and promotion of intelligent, connected equipment will be promoted in such key areas as industrial robots and large power equipment. Emerging cutting-edge technologies such as artificial intelligence and blockchain will be more extensively applied.</p> <p> "We should create a vibrant and enabling environment for internet plus advanced manufacturing by further streamlining administration, enhancing compliance oversight and improving government services. This will enable the Industrial Internet to develop in a more open and integrated manner, and put China at the forefront of the new round of industrial revolution," Li said.</p> <p> The Monday meeting also decided to step up policy support to the industrial sector. The government will expand equal access of various market entities. The finance will allocate special funds to support the Industrial Internet drive. Companies will be encouraged to scale up financial input through bonds and stock rights.</p> <p> Cyber security will be enhanced as companies will be encouraged to build up capacity for cyber security. The management and technical systems for network and platform security will be built in key manufacturing sectors, including automobile, electronics, energy, aviation and aerospace.</p> <p> "We should give full play to the role of market and businesses and provide policy support as necessary. The government will help capable enterprises to establish major Industrial Internet platforms for the development of industrial intranet and internet. The government must step up the development of infrastructure to make internet services faster and cheaper for SMEs," Li said.</p> <p> "Regulations regarding identification systems should be formulated to ensure security," he added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s cross-border e-commerce reaches 6.7 trillion RMB in 2016 ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286607</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286607.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 17:12:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ China’s cross-border e-commerce reached 6.7 trillion RMB ($1 trillion) in 2016, a compound annual growth of 31.6%, said a report issued at a cross-border e-commerce forum held on Oct. 29 in Shanghai. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> China’s cross-border e-commerce reached 6.7 trillion RMB ($1 trillion) in 2016, a compound annual growth of 31.6%, said a report issued at a cross-border e-commerce forum held on Oct. 29 in Shanghai.</p> <p> According to the report, people born between 1980 and 1990 made 59% of the overseas orders in 2016, followed by the post-90s and post-70s generations who respectively placed 23.0% and 14.4% of the total orders.</p> <p> Online shoppers who buy products from overseas are generally older than the average online consumers with higher academic degrees and income. In addition, most of them have stable marriages and jobs and more purchasing power.</p> <p> Cosmetics and infant supplies were the most popular overseas products for Chinese online shoppers, since young people and new parents formed the majority of this group.</p> <p> As many as 11.9%, 11.1%, and 3.8% of the population in Beijing, Shanghai, and Hangzhou have placed orders from overseas in the past year, and the three cities topped the country in terms of this proportion.</p> <p> With implementation of the Internet+ strategy, cross-border e-commerce has kept an annual growth rate of 20-30% since 2015. The volume of the sector is expected to hit 8.8 trillion RMB in 2018.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Sharing economy in China sees more rational moves ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286518</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286518.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 14:35:16 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Just as almost everything in life is becoming sharable in China, the booming sharing economy is starting to see signs of slowdown and more rational thinking amid the frenzy.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301429000258695393555.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 310px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <span style="font-size:8px;"><em>File photo</em></span></p> <p> The latest one to give up its sharing goal was EZZY, a luxurious car sharing platform that halted operations on Oct.25. The company no longer exists. Since October, EZZY users began to notice the shrinking number of cars available and problems retrieving their 2,000 yuan deposit.</p> <p> Launched in March 2016, EZZY once boasted its ambition to become “The Hulk” in the car sharing business. It indeed caught many eyes – some 100,000 users, with fancy cars such as BMW and Audi. However, the company only rolled out some 500 cars for sharing, and users soon complained that the service was inconvenient because the number of cars was inadequate, Beijing Daily reported.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <span style="font-size:8px;"><em><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301430000541262994573.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 375px;" /></em></span></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <span style="font-size:8px;"><em>Cars owned by EZZY park outside a Hilton hotel in Beijing. Photo/China News Service</em></span></p> <p> Of course, shared cars can never cover as many users as shared bikes. The latter witnessed the first ever merger case in its exploding development on the same day of the collapse of EZZY, when Hellobike was purchased by Youon, a deal that is expected to provide Hellobike with more capital and stronger support.</p> <p> The merger aroused another round of gloomy pessimism over the bike sharing industry, especially after a series of dropouts of shared bikes companies including Wukong bike, which announced its bankruptcy in June as the first quitter in this new business.</p> <p> Quitters are also withdrawing on other fronts, from shared chargers to shared umbrellas. On Oct. 11, shared charger company Ledian announced the end of its charger sharing operation after only six months.</p> <p> But experts and observers remain optimistic about the sharing industry and see the slowdown as a move toward more rationality.</p> <p> The crises facing some sharing companies are not a result of poor market performance, but because they are unable to profit under their own management and operational problems, said Cheng Shidong, director of urban traffic at the Institute of Comprehensive Transportation of National Development and Reform Commission.</p> <p> “The massive market demand for the sharing economy still exists, especially in major cities like Beijing, since it fits the future consumption trend,” Cheng was quoted as saying by Beijing Daily.</p> <p> China currently leads the world in sharing economy. In 2016, the sharing economy topped 3.45 trillion yuan, up 103 percent year on year. The number of people involved in it exceeded 600 million. In transportation alone, the market reached over 200 billion yuan in 2016, doubling that of 2015, according to a February report by the State Information Center.</p> <p> The report also estimated that China’s sharing economy will maintain a fast 40 percent growth rate every year in the coming years. By 2020, the scale of economic transactions is expected to take up 10 percent of the nation’s GDP.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Economic Watch: Why is 6 pct growth achievable for China's economy? ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286501</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286501.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 14:20:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 30 (Xinhua) -- China is determined to put growth quality before pace, but that will not hold the economy back from growing faster than most of other countries in the coming decade, according to experts.</p> <p> In a report delivered to the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC), the country's leadership called it "a new historic juncture in China's development," as the economy has been transitioning from a phase of rapid growth to a stage of high-quality development.</p> <p> In the eyes of Chi Fulin, head of the China Institute for Reform and Development, that does not mean the growth rate will be mediocre.</p> <p> Over the next five to 10 years, China's economy will be able to achieve at least 6 percent of annual growth thanks to improvement in industrial structure, upgrading of consumer spending and progress of urbanization, he said.</p> <p> In the past five years, the global economy expanded at an average rate of 2.6 percent, while developing economies grew at 4 percent.</p> <p> China has set 2020 as the target to finish building a moderately prosperous society in all respects, just one year before the CPC celebrates its 100th anniversary.</p> <p> Chi estimated that by the end of 2020, China's economic rebalancing will yield eye-propping results.</p> <p> By then, the value of the country's service sector will increase to about 50 trillion yuan (7.58 trillion U.S. dollars) from 38.4 trillion yuan recorded in 2016. Retail sales of consumer goods will also expand to about 50 trillion yuan from 33 trillion yuan recorded in 2016.</p> <p> The integrated development of urban and rural areas is expected to generate investment and consumption of nearly 100 trillion yuan, which will be the most remarkable bonus for China's development in the medium to long run, he said.</p> <p> Over this period, China's contribution to global economic growth would remain at around 30 percent. More than half of its population would become middle-income earners.</p> <p> "A successful rebalancing of the world's second largest economy would not only upgrade China's economy, but also boost global economic recovery and growth," Chi said.</p> <p> In the future, China's economic restructuring will be advanced together with opening up, of which the Belt and Road Initiative and the development of service trade and free trade zones will be the focuses, he said.</p> <p> The IMF recently raised its forecast for China's economic growth in 2017 and 2018 to 6.8 percent and 6.5 percent respectively, both higher than the earlier forecast in July.</p> <p> For an economy with a total volume of over 11 trillion U.S. dollars, maintaining such high growth is not easy, Chinese Vice Finance Minister Zhu Guangyao said.</p> <p> China's stable economic growth mainly stems from major progress in economic reforms, particularly supply-side structural measures, and the government's ability to maintain a stable macroeconomic policy, he said.</p> <p> While gains from structural reforms will come with a time lag, they will have a positive impact on China's economic growth in the medium term, said Changyong Rhee, director of the Asia Pacific Department at the IMF, adding China's growth has also provided ample opportunities for Asia to maintain its growth over the last ten years.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Green companies set to soar on policy boost from Congress ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286464</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286464.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 11:22:57 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301121000253915826062.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Investors check stock prices at a brokerage in Fuyang, Anhui province. The top leadership's call for sustainable development and green economic growth has boosted investor sentiment toward companies involved in environmentally friendly businesses. [Photo/for China Daily]</p> <p> 'Lucid waters and lush mountains' speech gives some A shares fresh energy</p> <p> A-share companies that offer solutions for environment management, environment protection and pollution control are likely to benefit long-term from China's strengthened policies for "green development", said analysts.</p> <p> At the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China last fortnight, President Xi Jinping reaffirmed the country's commitment to push forward green development.</p> <p> On several occasions in recent months, Xi sought to underline the importance of green development, and that "lucid waters and lush mountains are invaluable assets".</p> <p> The top leadership's call for sustainable development and green economic growth has boosted investor sentiment toward companies involved in environmentally-friendly businesses.</p> <p> For instance, shares in Guangdong Liantai Environment Protection Co Ltd, a wastewater treatment solution provider, rose from 18.1 yuan ($2.73) by the end of September to 23.08 yuan on Friday, up 27.5 percent, on the Shanghai Stock Exchange.</p> <p> Shares in Shanghai Environment Group Co Ltd, an urban solid waste treatment services provider, rose from 24.1 yuan at September-end to 27.49 yuan on Friday, up 14 percent, on the Shanghai Stock Exchange.</p> <p> Shares in Beijing Qingxin Environment Co Ltd, an air treatment solutions provider, rose 8 percent from 21 yuan at September-end to 22.68 yuan on Friday on the Shenzhen Stock Exchange.</p> <p> China has launched a series of policies to improve management of water, air, soil and waste treatment.</p> <p> For improvement of water quality, the "River Chief" system requires supervision of each water body by a local official. He or she has to prevent any further harm to the water. This has entailed collaboration at various levels among multiple government departments.</p> <p> Water treatment technologies, solutions and innovative ideas are shared among localities, pushing up demand for quality solutions.</p> <p> Local government efforts for a healthy ecology are reviewed annually and nation-wide inspections are done every five years. The next such inspection will be in 2018.</p> <p> "Environment protection and improvement, as a sector, has been put in a significant position," said a research note from Sinolink Securities.</p> <p> The note said that from a policymaking perspective, the environment tax, which will be imposed in 2018, will strengthen inspections of local governments' efforts for environment improvement, spurring demand for related services and solutions.</p> <p> Jiang Chao, an analyst with Haitong Securities, said China's economic growth pattern is shifting from rapid pace to quality, with focus now more on sustainability, green development, balance and optimized structure of growth.</p> <p> Development in both rural and urban areas, and consumption upgrade will also increase demand for improved environment treatment solutions, said Huatai Securities.</p> <p> Water, waste and air treatment facilities are included in the blueprint for tens of industrial new cities across China. Environmentally-friendly solutions will be integral to the development of new cities that will be built from scratch.</p> <p> According to a brokerage's research note, consumers' preference for a better environment will spur service providers in both public and private sectors to consider such solutions.</p> <p> Developers of residential properties and facilities such as schools, parks and theaters will include more environmentally-friendly products than ever before while finalizing their procurement budgets.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China, Bangladesh sign framework agreement on oil pipeline project ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286393</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286393.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 10:52:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> DHAKA, Oct. 29 -- The Bangladeshi government signed a framework agreement with China on Sunday for construction of a 220-km pipeline to carry oil from tankers in the Bay of Bengal to storage plants on the mainland.</p> <p> Bangladesh's Economic Relations Department (ERD) Secretary Kazi Shofiqul Azam and Chinese Ambassador to Bangladesh Ma Mingqiang signed the framework agreement in the capital of Dhaka.</p> <p> The project is aimed to make a balance between the demand and supply of the country's energy need and ensure energy security of the country, they said, adding it will also reduce the system loss during import of refined and non-refined fuel.</p> <p> The ERD said this is one of the 27 projects for which memorandum of understandings were signed between the two governments in October last year.</p> <p> In December last year, Bangladesh reached an agreement with the state-owned China Petroleum Pipeline Bureau (CPP) for engineering, procurement, construction and commissioning for installation of single point mooring with 220-km double pipelines.</p> <p> Bangladeshi State Minister for Power and Energy, who witnessed the signing ceremony on Sunday, said the new infrastructure will help the country to expedite the entire process and save about 1 billion taka (about 12.5 million U.S. dollars) a year in reduced vessel fare and operational loss.</p> <p> According to project details, a diesel and crude oil storage tank will be set up at Moheshkhali Island on the Bay of Bengal in Bangladeshi Cox's Bazar district. Officials said the project cost stands at 54.26 billion taka (about 694 million U.S. dollars).</p> <p> The project is expected to have an annual unloading capacity of 9 million tonnes.</p> <p> Under the project, BPC officials said the Chinese firm will build 146-km offshore pipeline and 74-km onshore pipeline to carry imported oil from sea to a refinery in Chittagong district, some 242 km southeast of Dhaka, for processing.</p> <p> The project was launched as Bangladesh is not capable of handling large vessels carrying imported crude and finished oil, due to low navigability of a key river channel and constrained facilities at the main seaport in Chittagong.</p> <p> According to the officials, large tankers anchor at deep sea and smaller ships unload them, taking lots of time and causing systematic losses for the government.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Largest wind turbine vessel may boost intl cooperation in South China Sea ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286215</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286215.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 08:14:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" desc="(File Photo)" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710300813000508574585918.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /></p> <p class="desc" style="text-align: center;"> (File Photo)</p> <p> China's largest wind turbine installation vessel, the "Longyuan Zhenhua 3", could boost international cooperation in the South China Sea, experts said Sunday.</p> <p> The vessel, which went into trial service on Sunday in Nantong, East China's Jiangsu Province, has a lifting capacity of 2,000 tons, making it the largest of this kind in the world, currently, news site people.cn reported.</p> <p> "This is different from land operations, since offshore operations encounter tougher conditions, requiring higher standards for the equipment," Zhou Dadi, vice-director of the National Development and Reform Commission's China Energy Research Society, told the Global Times.</p> <p> "The 'Longyuan Zhenhua 3' has greater power than previous Chinese vessels, which means higher lifting and bigger capacity," Zhou explained.</p> <p> Offshore wind turbine installations are mature in China and the "Longyuan Zhenhua 3" can be used in the South China Sea, a region that has abundant wind resources, Chen Xiangmiao, a research fellow at the National Institute for the South China Sea, told the Global Times on Sunday.</p> <p> The vessel could provide energy supplies for vehicles passing by the region and boost international cooperation, Chen noted.</p> <p> Many of the Southeast Asian countries have abundant wind resources but lack the technology to make full use of that clean energy, and China could share the technology, he added.</p> <p> However, Zhou does not share the enthusiasm about the vessel's use in the South China Sea, saying that "various kinds of offshore vessels are available in the South China Sea and the 'Longyuan Zhenhua 3' is not the only wind turbine installation vessel."</p> <p> The vessel is a product of Shanghai Zhenhua Heavy Industries (ZPMC), specially designed for the high-power offshore wind-turbine market, reaching higher than 6 megawatts, according to people.cn.</p> <p> It is 100.8 meters long, 43.2 meters wide, and has a draft of 8.4 meters and it can work at depths of up to 50 meters, making it a leader in China at present, China Global Television Network (CGTN) reported on Saturday.</p> <p> Work on the new vessel began in 2016 and was completed in June 2017. It is ZPMC's third wind turbine installation vessel and their latest project was a two-turbine installation job at the Formosa 1 offshore wind farm, CGTN reported.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 28 Chinese telecom fraud suspects repatriated from Cambodia ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286190</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1029/c90000-9286190.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 29 Oct 2017 15:38:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> CHONGQING, Oct. 29 -- Twenty-eight telecom fraud suspects were repatriated from Cambodia to southwest China's Chongqing Municipality Sunday morning, according to a source with the Chinese police.</p> <p> The suspects are part of a group of 61 people caught in a China-Cambodia joint police operation earlier this month.</p> <p> China's Ministry of Public Security, along with police from Chongqing Municipality and Shandong Province, began investigating the telecom fraud cases in early September.</p> <p> The suspects allegedly made phone calls to people on the Chinese mainland cheating victims out of money by pretending to be law enforcement or with falsely promised high-return investments.</p> <p> Bank cards, computers, and mobile phones involved in the cases were also seized.</p> <p> In recent years, Chinese police have tracked down Chinese nationals hiding overseas who have participated in telecom fraud, mainly targeting victims on the mainland.</p> <p> The police also had 74 suspects caught and repatriated from Cambodia in another operation early October.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Bank of Communications profit up 3.5 percent ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286075</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1028/c90000-9286075.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 14:53:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 28 (Xinhua) -- China's state-owned Bank of Communications announced Saturday that its net profit rose 3.5 percent in the first three quarters of the year, to 54.42 billion yuan (8.2 billion U.S. dollars). ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 28 (Xinhua) -- China's state-owned Bank of Communications announced Saturday that its net profit rose 3.5 percent in the first three quarters of the year, to 54.42 billion yuan (8.2 billion U.S. dollars).</p> <p> Total assets rose 6.34 percent from the end of 2016, to 8.94 trillion yuan, according to its unaudited quarterly report filed with the Shanghai Stock Exchange.</p> <p> The bank said its main business indicators had realized steady growth as it worked to serve the real economy, continued reform and innovation, and improved risk management.</p> <p> Business revenue rose 1.64 percent year on year to 149.72 billion yuan in the same period.</p> <p> The non-performing loans ratio stood at 1.51 percent, slightly down from 1.52 percent at the end of last year. Earnings per share were 0.7 yuan.</p> <p> The bank is listed in both Shanghai and Hong Kong. Its shares rose 0.48 percent in Shanghai and 1.51 percent in Hong Kong Friday.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China has 950 mln 4G users: ministry ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285961</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1028/c90000-9285961.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 09:44:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- China had a total of 950 million 4G network users as of the end of September, figures from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) showed Friday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1028/FOREIGN201710280936000428078918912.png" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>(File photo)</em></p> <p> BEIJING, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- China had a total of 950 million 4G network users as of the end of September, figures from the Ministry of Industry and Information Technology (MIIT) showed Friday.</p> <p> Chinese mobile Internet subscribers have also increased their use of data services, with an average of 2 gigabytes of data consumed by each subscriber last month, up 140 percent from the same period last year, said MIIT spokesperson Zheng Lixin.</p> <p> Also by the end of Q3, China had 280 million users of fiber-optic broadband, accounting for 82.7 percent of fixed-line broadband network users.</p> <p> China has the world's largest 4G network and is aiming to add 2 million 4G base stations, mainly for townships and villages, by 2018.</p> <p> China began a campaign aimed at faster and more affordable Internet connection in 2015.</p> <p> Since September this year, fees for domestic roaming and long-distance calls have been waived as data services have become a major source of revenue for mobile service operators.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Alibaba promotes cashless society in Philippines ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285909</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1027/c90000-9285909.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 17:44:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ Alibaba is now stepping up efforts to promote building a cashless society in the Philippines, after the Chinese tech giant and Amazon dominated e-commerce in their home markets, Thepaper.cn reported on Oct. 26. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1027/FOREIGN201710271727000196070690874.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Jack Ma buys a cup of drink with mobile payment at a cinema in Manila.</em></p> <p> Alibaba is now stepping up efforts to promote building a cashless society in the Philippines, after the Chinese tech giant and Amazon dominated e-commerce in their home markets, Thepaper.cn reported on Oct. 26.</p> <p> Alibaba Group founder Jack Ma held a meeting with Alibaba staffs over how to develop e-commerce in the Philippines upon his arrival in Manila on Oct. 24. The meeting yielded plans on developing e-commerce infrastructure in the country, including building market places and strengthening logistics.</p> <p> In addition, the Alibaba founder was given a Doctor of Science in Technopreneurship Honoris Causa from De La Salle University (DLSU) for setting a good example for young people by establishing a science and technology business.</p> <p> During a roundtable discussion at the university, Jack Ma shared his thoughts on business opportunities, saying that the field with the most complaints is often full of opportunities.</p> <p> Jack Ma took the “not good” internet speed in the Philippines as an example, and stressed that providing the best service for consumers can help enterprises achieve a lot.</p> <p> As people in the Philippines are living on over 7,000 islands in the country and banks cannot be on every island, technology can be used to help them connect, Jack Ma noted.</p> <p> He also called upon Chinese people in the Philippines to contribute to building a cashless society for the country by selling Philippine products such as fruits to consumers in China through e-commerce, and introducing Chinese products, services, and technologies to the Philippines.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Tech breakthrough puts China among leading makers of tunnel borers ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285831</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1027/c90000-9285831.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 17:44:04 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The China Railway Group (CREC) on Thursday announced its completion of a huge tunnel boring machine (TBM) with advanced capabilities for drilling in wet conditions, a breakthrough which the company sees as a demonstration of its world-leading status.</p> <p> TBMs are tube-shaped monsters used to drill underground tunnels. They have massive blades on their shield-like fronts which can break through harder rocks compared with traditional drilling and bombing method.</p> <p> The newly-built TBM is 15.03 meters wide, about 4,000 tons in weight and 100 meters in length.</p> <p> According to a report on tunneltalk.com, there are only two TBMs in the world with a diameter larger than 17 meters. The size of all the other mega-TBMs is below 16 meters. The new TBM by the CREC ranks 10th in the world.</p> <p> "This TBM is a sign that our technology has already caught up with, if not surpassed, the world's best," said Liu Hui, chief engineer at the CREC.</p> <p> <strong>Slurry-balanced</strong></p> <p> The machine is also the largest TBM built by China with a feature called slurry-balancing.</p> <p> When using a TBM to drill a tunnel, the machine may turn away from its designed route because the material it is boring into is too soft compared to rock and mud.</p> <p> Modern TBMs use slurry to balance the pressure, and stabilize the machine. Slurry can also help flush out the drill cuttings.</p> <p> Developing countries like China have previously been unable to develop slurry-balancing borers, so have had to import expensive TBMs from the West. That's why China was highly motivated to develop its own technology.</p> <p> The new machine will be first used in an underwater tunnel project in south China's Shantou City.</p> <p> "The rocks in our tunnel are too hard, and composed of various materials," said Xiao Guanping, a major investor. "This machine is customized to deal with our problem."</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CNTV</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's central bank conducts first 63-day reverse repos ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285795</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1027/c90000-9285795.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 14:23:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> China's central bank for the first time used 63-day reverse repos to boost market liquidity before the end of the year, according to a statement released Friday.</p> <p> The People's Bank of China (PBOC) injected 50 billion yuan (about 7.5 billion U.S. dollars) through 63-day reverse repos, a process in which the central bank purchases securities from commercial banks with an agreement to sell them back in the future.</p> <p> With an interest rate of 2.9 percent, the operations will mature on Dec. 29, the last trading day of this year, meaning that the banking sector will see a steady liquidity boost during a relatively long period.</p> <p> Previously, the longest term for PBOC reverse repos was 28 days.</p> <p> On Friday, PBOC also boosted liquidity by 60 billion yuan through seven-day reverse repos and by 30 billion yuan with 14-day reverse repos.</p> <p> Offset by maturing reverse repos, net liquidity injection stood at 90 billion yuan on Friday and 390 billion yuan for this week.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Quality metrics set to transcend GDP goals ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285792</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1027/c90000-9285792.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 14:19:14 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1027/FOREIGN201710271418000457008914104.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 407px;" /></p> <p> <em>Yang Weimin, deputy director of the Office of the Central Leading Group on Financial and Economic Affairs, answers questions from journalists at the news conference, on Oct 26, 2017. [Photo by Feng Yongbin/China Daily]</em></p> <p> China will not set a target to double its gross domestic product from 2021 on, and it will put more emphasis on quality of growth, a senior official said on Thursday.</p> <p> Analysts said the country will deepen its supply-side structural reform, promote employment, increase incomes and strengthen environmental protection to improve the quality of economic development.</p> <p> "China's main social contradiction has changed and its economic development is moving to a stage of high-quality growth from a high-rate of expansion of the GDP," said Yang Weimin, deputy head of the Office of the Central Leading Group on Financial and Economic Affairs. "The biggest problem facing us now ... is the inadequate quality of development," he said at a news conference.</p> <p> In a speech at the start of the key National Congress of the Communist Party of China on Oct 18, Xi Jinping, CPC Central Committee general secretary, said China would deepen economic reforms as it transitions from high-speed to high-quality growth.</p> <p> China has put forward a target of doubling its GDP and per capita income in the decade leading up to 2020. Chances are good it will meet that target based on the current rate of growth. Economists estimate an annual GDP growth of 6.3 percent is needed in the coming three years to meet the goal. GDP growth is widely expected to come close to 7 percent this year.</p> <p> "It is not that we will no longer pursue (high) growth rates," Yang said. "What we want is ... to make efforts to solve the problem of unbalanced and inadequate development."</p> <p> Analysts said that by prioritizing quality, China is set to deepen structural reforms, promote the job market, raise people's incomes and enhance environmental protection to try to make growth more sustainable.</p> <p> "President Xi's opening speech at the 19th CPC National Congress was notable for the focus placed on quality and equality of development over the coming years, rather than specific growth targets," economists at UBS financial services group said in a research note.</p> <p> "The supply-side reforms will be deepened and implemented further," said a research note from Nomura financial group.</p> <p> The UBS economists expected China to implement tougher environmental regulations through production cuts and capacity closures this winter and push for faster State-owned enterprise consolidation and mixed-ownership reform next year.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China shifts to quality growth ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285698</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1027/c90000-9285698.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 10:12:29 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1027/FOREIGN201710271011000506859796760.png" style="width: 600px; height: 389px;" /></p> <p> China's focus has shifted to higher-quality growth and will no longer target doubling the country's GDP in its two-stage development plan from 2020-2050, a senior official said on Thursday.</p> <p> "The main consideration is that the major contradiction facing Chinese society has changed as the country's economic development has shifted from high-speed growth to a higher-quality development stage," Yang Weimin, deputy director of the Office of the Central Leading Group on Financial and Economic Affairs, told a press conference following the conclusion of the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China (CPC).</p> <p> The most prominent problem facing the country is not inadequate industrial capacity, but that the quality of economic growth is not good enough, Yang said.</p> <p> But he denied that the country has abandoned growth rates. The conspicuous break from past practices, Yang said, was taken by the Party Congress out of consideration to better implement the new vision for development.</p> <p> In his speech at the opening session of the 19th CPC National Congress, Xi Jinping, general secretary of the CPC Central Committee, said China will become a moderately prosperous country by 2020, and that the Party has drawn up a two-stage development plan from 2020 to the middle of the 21st century to develop China into a "great modern socialist country."</p> <p> In the first stage from 2020 to 2035, the CPC will build on the foundation created by the moderately prosperous society with a further 15 years of hard work to see that socialist modernization is basically realized. In the second stage from 2035 to the middle of the 21st century, the CPC will, building on having basically achieved modernization, work hard for a further 15 years and develop China into a great modern socialist country that is prosperous, strong, democratic, culturally advanced, harmonious and beautiful.</p> <p> Yang said that the vision shows that the economy will achieve socialist modernization 15 years ahead of schedule.</p> <p> "Modernization would be more multifaceted than just GDP growth, incorporating greater concern for social well-being, regional balance, national security and political cohesion, but done in a uniquely China way," Yukon Huang, a senior fellow at the Carnegie Endowment for International Peace and a former World Bank country director for China, told the Global Times.</p> <p> Overall, optimism prevails for the dividends the world's second-largest economy will receive from the key gathering held every five years.</p> <p> <strong>Financial sector uncertainties</strong></p> <p> China's economic policy will be more mature and steadier, not only more in line with the national conditions but will address the people's key concerns and will focus on their well-being, Liu Zhiqin, a senior fellow at Renmin University of China's Chongyang Institute for Financial Studies, told the Global Times.</p> <p> "There won't be dramatic fluctuations in economic growth in the coming periods," Liu said, adding the financial sector remains the only uncertainty.</p> <p> Analysts believe that China will face challenges from the financial sector in the coming decade, with the key issues to include how China will further open up its capital market.</p> <p> The international community also places high hopes on China to further liberalize its capital market, Liu said.</p> <p> But China has the confidence and ability to push ahead with financial reforms to further open up the capital market, as reflected by the country's latest transaction of dollar-denominated sovereign bonds in Hong Kong, he added. The Ministry of Finance has announced plans to issue US dollar-denominated sovereign bonds worth $2 billion in Hong Kong and has begun discussions with potential investors to further open up the country's financial sector.</p> <p> Huang said that the Party congress has called for more support for private firms, but also recommended stronger and bigger State firms. He added that the latter reinforces the view that many of the largest State-owned enterprises (SOEs) are considered China's "national champions."</p> <p> "Thus far, Beijing has been pushing for the 'soft' reform option in the form of diversifying SOE ownership. What is now needed is more clarity in sectors where there is no strong justification for continued State involvement while preserving or even enhancing the role of the State in other areas," he said.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China working on building free trade ports ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285445</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285445.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 18:05:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 26 (Xinhua) -- The Ministry of Commerce is working on the building of free trade ports in China's free trade zones (FTZs), a spokesman said Thursday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 26 (Xinhua) -- The Ministry of Commerce is working on the building of free trade ports in China's free trade zones (FTZs), a spokesman said Thursday.</p> <p> China will grant more power to pilot free trade zones and explore the opening of free trade ports, according to a key report delivered last week at the 19th National Congress of the Communist Party of China.</p> <p> The ministry should "follow higher standards and push for more comprehensive and deeper opening up," spokesman Gao Feng said at a press conference Thursday.</p> <p> "The ministry is currently working with Shanghai Municipality and other departments on making the plan [for building free trade ports]," Gao said.</p> <p> The Shanghai FTZ will build a top-level free trade port and implement trade supervision regulations in accordance with higher standards, according to a document made public in March by the State Council.</p> <p> The FTZ in east China's Zhejiang Province also aims to build a high-standard pilot free trade port to push international commodity trade liberalization with a focus on oil products.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to sell first dollar bond in 13 years on Thursday ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285188</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285188.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 10:05:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> HONG KONG, Oct. 25 -- China will issue 2 billion U.S. dollars worth of dollar-denominated sovereign bonds on Thursday, China's Ministry of Finance (MOF) said here on Wednesday.</p> <p> China will issue the sovereign bonds in the Hong Kong Special Administrative Region (HKSAR), including 1 billion U.S. dollars of five-year bonds and 1 billion U.S. dollars of 10-year bonds, according to a roadshow held here on Wednesday.</p> <p> Raising funds was not the main purpose of this issuance, but it will help guide markets and evaluate prospects in the future, said Wang Yi, director of the finance department of the Ministry of Finance.</p> <p> The outstanding sovereign external debt of China stood at 18.1 billion U.S. dollars at the end of 2016, accounting for 1.06 percent of its national debt and far below the international average, according to the ministry.</p> <p> The HKSAR government is planning to expand profits tax exemption to dollar-denominated sovereign bonds issued by the central government, said Chan Mo-po, financial secretary of the HKSAR government.</p> <p> Norman Chan, chief executive of the Hong Kong Monetary Authority, said the MOF's choice to issue this U.S. dollar sovereign bond to international investors in Hong Kong highlights the status of Hong Kong as a premier international financial center in Asia, as well as Hong Kong's strategic position as the natural gateway linking the mainland to the world.</p> <p> The previous such sales were made in October 2004, when the country raised a total of 1.7 billion U.S. dollars by issuing dollar- and euro-denominated bonds with maturities of five and 10 years.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Alipay introduces offline e-payment system into Philippine market ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285015</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9285015.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 21:45:59 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ MANILA, Oct. 25 (Xinhua) -- A new offline e-payment system supported by China's mobile payment platform Alipay was rolled out Wednesday in Manila, showing the the country's desire to accelerate the digitization to help facilitate the lives of Filipinos. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> MANILA, Oct. 25 (Xinhua) -- A new offline e-payment system supported by China's mobile payment platform Alipay was rolled out Wednesday in Manila, showing the the country's desire to accelerate the digitization to help facilitate the lives of Filipinos.</p> <p> At the launch ceremony, Philippine consumers experienced buying goods and services through scanning QR codes by a mobile phone app called GCash. Business owners also benefited from not having to install expensive machines as they only needed a QR code sticker which buyers can scan to pay.</p> <p> The offline e-payment technology of GCash mobile wallet app was shared by the Ant Financial Services Group, an affiliate company of China's Alibaba Group. The app is owned by the Globe Telecom, which is a major provider of telecommunications services in the Philippines. Another partner of Alibaba is the Philippine retail and real estate giant Ayala Group, which leads to the Ayala owned shopping malls to firstly use the offline e-payment system in many of its shops and restaurants as well as in its cinemas.</p> <p> Eric Jing, CEO of Ant Financial Services Group, said, "Ant Financial has actively worked with our global strategic partners to realize innovative and local solutions that cater to different markets. In the Philippines, we have been working closely with Globe Telecom and Ayala Corporation by sharing our e-payment technology know-how. The goal is to bring cost-effective, efficient and secure digital financial experiences to the local market. Beginning from Ayala Malls, we look forward to seeing even higher e-payment adoption so more Filipinos can enjoy the benefits of inclusive digital finance."</p> <p> "In this country, only 5 percent of the total population has credit cards, leaving most people to carry cash for payment. Today, we are introducing a 'third method of payment'," said Ernest Cu, Globe president and CEO.</p> <p> "Now that more people are using data on their smartphones, the time is ripe to enable digital payments using the smartphone and let this go mainstream. Our challenge today is to make digital payments the preferred choice among our customers instead of cash or credit cards," added Cu.</p> <p> GCash is mobile wallet service which can be used to pay bills, send money, and pay for goods and services whether online or offline. The platform is similar to that of China's Alipay.</p> <p> Mynt, the operator of GCash, is a joint venture innovating company owned by Ant Financial Services Group, Globe Telecom and Ayala Group.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 18,000 firms registered in Shanghai FTZ since establishment ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285012</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9285012.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 21:16:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ SHANGHAI, Oct. 25 (Xinhua) -- Nearly 18,000 firms have registered with the customs authorities in the Shanghai free trade zone (FTZ) since it was launched four years ago, Shanghai Customs said Wednesday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> SHANGHAI, Oct. 25 (Xinhua) -- Nearly 18,000 firms have registered with the customs authorities in the Shanghai free trade zone (FTZ) since it was launched four years ago, Shanghai Customs said Wednesday.</p> <p> The figure doubled the number of companies that were already operating in the four bonded zones that merged to become the Shanghai FTZ in September 2013, bringing the total now operating within the zone to more than 27,000, the customs said.</p> <p> Of the newly-registered companies, 13,600 are privately owned, more than 3,200 are wholly foreign-funded businesses, and 940 are Chinese-foreign joint ventures.</p> <p> The companies cover 54 industries. Some 94 percent are wholesale or retail firms, while 5 percent are financial enterprises. The rest mainly concern transportation, storage and postal businesses.</p> <p> The surge in company registrations has helped boost trade in Shanghai despite trade gloom nationwide.</p> <p> In the first three quarters this year, foreign trade in the Shanghai FTZ rose 16.2 percent year on year to 997.6 billion yuan (150.2 billion U.S. dollars).</p> <p> When the Shanghai FTZ was launched it streamlined procedures for business registration. Companies can obtain licenses to operate in the zone in three working days of applying, compared with 40 working days in the previous bonded zones.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ E-commerce platforms ready to battle on Singles Day ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284818</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284818.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 14:37:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251437000171267821460.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 361px;" /></p> <p> China's e-commerce platforms have announced their promotional policies before the annual shopping spree on Nov 11, known as "Singles Day".</p> <p> On Tuesday, Chinese online shopping mall Gome released a campaign that encourages customers to create their own online shops to help the company sell products on its shopping app.</p> <p> Gome will provide more than 1,000 products to these people as well as will give them a total of 300 million yuan ($45.23 million) in commissions, according to a campaign representative at the company.</p> <p> Gome's rivals, including Suning, JD.com, and Tmall, previously pushed out their operations to increase interaction with customers.</p> <p> Online shopping platform JD has cooperated with tech giant Tencent to publish a program utilizing big data to help offline retailers increase sales during the upcoming shopping event.</p> <p> Retail group Suning provides similar privileges to customers, no matter whether they buy goods at its online platform or offline shops. In addition, the company has launched a "big data sharing" program that will optimize data sharing with factories at every level of the supply chain, the Beijing Morning Post said, quoting Hou Enlong, president of Suning's e-commerce platform.</p> <p> Gome also promised customers the same products with the same prices and quality at its offline stores and online markets.</p> <p> As initiator of the shopping carnival, Tmall announced its pre-sell scheme early — last Thursday.</p> <p> However, some customers complained on social platforms, saying the pre-sell scheme is too complex to understand.</p> <p> "I need to re-study mathematics and reading skills to figure out Tmall's special offers this year", said one self-deprecating customer.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Chinadaily.com.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s postal service occupies nearly 20% global market share ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284732</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284732.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 13:36:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The market size of China’s postal service is approaching 1/5 of the world’s total market scale, the country’s State Postal Bureau (SPB) reported at a recent press conference. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251324000292198399636.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 510px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>JD.com announces its UAV at a drone conference in Xi’an, northwest China's Shaanxi Province. (Photo by People’s Daily Online)</em></p> <p> The market size of China’s postal service is approaching 1/5 of the world’s total market scale, the country’s State Postal Bureau (SPB) reported at a recent press conference.</p> <p> China now has the world’s fastest-growing postal business, with the largest potential, and it is the most-appealing place to invest and the most active business in terms of innovation, according to Shen Hongyan, the SPB spokesperson.</p> <p> The service covers more than 300 million people on a daily basis, handling more than 100 billion yuan ($15.1 billion) in agricultural exports and 120-billion-yuan worth of manufactured goods each year.</p> <p> In addition, it helped deliver more than 4-trillion-yuan($ 604.4 billion) worth of online purchases, or 12.5 percent of total retail consumer good sales in 2016 and, helped create 200,000 jobs each year.</p> <p> China accounted for 40% of global express deliveries in 2016, topping the global country list for 3 consecutive years. It has 20,000 express delivery companies with more than 2 million employees in all and the average cost of courier services dropped by 31% from 5 years ago, to 12.7 yuan ($1.9) per item.</p> <p> Currently, there are 6 express delivery companies in China that earn over 30 billion yuan annually and 10 companies that earn more than 10 billion yuan annually. In addition, there are 3 airline cargo services in operation with 93 cargo aircraft.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251324000400095993961.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 549px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Shaanxi provincial government and Xi’an municipal government representatives join JD.com personnel for the JD Drone Conference. (Photo by People’s Daily Online)</em></p> <p> China is seeing smart logistics emerge with more applications and newer technology in its postal service, for instance, its first smart logistics express system that went into operation this July in Maoming, south China's Guangdong Province.</p> <p> This past February, the northwest China Shaanxi Provincial government and the e-commerce giant JD.com signed a cooperation agreement on a smart logistics system, where they agreed to start cooperating on smart deliveries and an aviation logistics network for low-altitude unmanned aerial vehicles (UAV).</p> <p> JD also established China’s first drone logistics center, on June 6, and initiated the use of drones for deliveries in China’s Xi’an and some other places.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>