<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title> Life_Culture </title>
		<image>
			<title>People's Daily Online</title>
			<link>http://english.people.com.cn/</link>
			<url>http://english.people.com.cn/images/en/top_logo_e.gif</url>
		</image>
		<description>People's Daily Online</description>
		<link>http://english.people.com.cn/90782</link>
		<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Behold this futuristic and gorgeous Library in Tianjin ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288606</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288606.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 16:45:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/11/3/f6af08b0-be5e-43ef-8015-4ddbcda5767a.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1103/FOREIGN201711031639000146894379062.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 455px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Behold this futuristic and gorgeous Library in Tianjin</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Foreign models find themselves in demand as e-commerce grows in China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9288420</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1103/c90000-9288420.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 10:12:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Katty, a brown-haired university student from Russia, regularly finds work as a model in China, a career that doesn't even exist in her hometown.</p> <p> Clients in Vladivostok, Russia, don't pay models with money. Instead, they tend to work through barter, paying with certificates to buy clothes in their shops, Katty told the Global Times.</p> <p> For the last four summers, the 20-year-old has been busy travelling between Chinese cities for various shows, shoots for catalogues and TV commercials.</p> <p> With the surge in the number of e-commerce businesses, foreign models are becoming more popular in China, and tend to be seen as a symbol of all that is "international, exotic and charming."</p> <p> Katty's favorite place to work is Shanghai and the city is "one of the most expensive places in the Yangtze River Delta region to hire a foreign model," according to an agent based in Nanjing, surnamed Hu.</p> <p> "Customers can choose whoever they want, but the price is decided by where models will work," said Hu. "For example, the price of shopping promotions is about 1,500 yuan per hour in Hangzhou, a city in Zhejiang Province which is 80-minute drive south of Shanghai, but in Shanghai it goes up to around 2,000 yuan."</p> <p> <strong>High demand</strong></p> <p> The Yangtze River Delta region centering Shanghai is one of the areas where demand for models is highest. Hangzhou is home to Alibaba, the largest e-commerce website in China, Zheng Yi, CEO of ESEE Model Management, a model agency based in Shanghai, told the Global Times.</p> <p> About 80 percent of events in Hangzhou managed by Zheng Yi's company are photo shoots for local clothes businesses.</p> <p> The Pearl River Delta region in Southern China is also a popular place for foreign models, as it is famous for its clothing manufacturers, Zheng added.</p> <p> The trade volume from e-commerce in the Yangtze River Delta region had already reached 4 trillion yuan in 2013, nearly 40 per percent of the nationwide volume, China News Service reported, citing iResearch Consulting Group.</p> <p> Posing as a customer, the Global Times received more than 120 pictures of foreign models from Hu, mostly from Ukraine, Russia, Georgia and France, ranging in age from 14 to their 20s.</p> <p> Detailed personal information is written on their sample pictures, including name, hair color, breast, waist and hip size, and even shoe size.</p> <p> Hu said foreign models with a proper working visa come at an additional 500 yuan each. "Most of them are on a temporary travel visa," she explained.</p> <p> Many such small agencies can be found on social media websites, such as Baidu, Tianya and Douban, and most of their models are on a travel visa.</p> <p> These agencies help to find events for foreign models, who promote products online and in shopping malls, weddings, annual meetings and even work as foreign language teachers. Commission fees for models depend on the agencies, some of them coming with guaranteed paychecks, other earnings as they go, Katty said.</p> <p> Major model companies in China sign contracts with foreign models' home companies, giving them three-month legal working visas, Zheng added.</p> <p> Zheng said that models usually need to pass test shoots first. There are normally two categories of working days, either four hours or eight hours, and the job starts when they put on their makeup.</p> <p> <strong>Exotic cultures</strong></p> <p> Some agencies contacted by the Global Times said many foreign models are from Eastern Europe. Zhang Yiwu, a professor of culture at Peking University, said the economic situation in their home country forces them to travel to China in search of bigger opportunities.</p> <p> Unlike Chinese models, foreign models have very distinguished facial features and figures. They are a prominent sight on taobao store, at auto shows and professional meetings, representing a special brand culture. Businesses want to be international, exotic and popular, Zhang told the Global Times.</p> <p> Their image also meets the Chinese public's desire for exotic cultures, a way of life that ordinary Chinese can only experience through foreign books and movies, Zhang explained.</p> <p> Due to different aesthetic standards, foreign models distinguish themselves from Chinese models but do not compete with them, as they represent different fashion styles, Zheng noted.</p> <p> In addition to photography, video and live-streaming events tend to use more foreign models these days, according to Zheng.</p> <p> The huge market in China and Asia will continue to see a demand for foreign models, although compensation is still not competitive when compared with other mature markets like Japan, he added.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Hollywood scandals have Chinese uncomfortable ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287954</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287954.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 11:16:40 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> China's Hollywood fans have expressed concern over the sexual harassment scandals that have come into the spotlight recently, saying that they are shocked and worry that such scandals could ruin the reputation of the movie industry.</p> <p> Kevin Spacey, a 58-year-old double Oscar winner who has attracted a large audience in China for his role in the popular House of Cards, faces accusations from another actor, Anthony Rapp. Rapp claimed that Spacey "made a sexual advance" to him at a party 31 years ago while Rapp was 14 years old, AFP reported.</p> <p> Spacey apologized immediately for the incident and came out as gay, but his remarks have been blasted by others in Hollywood, which has been rocked to the foundation since movie mogul Harvey Weinstein was accused of sexual misconduct, including harassment and assault, by more than 50 women.</p> <p> Hollywood fans in China also expressed their concern about the evolving scandal.</p> <p> "The scandals have changed my impression of Hollywood, since no one knows how many other victims are there and it makes people question the fairness of the casting methods," said a Chinese entertainment company employee surnamed Shi.</p> <p> "It damaged the reputation of Hollywood so regulators need to strengthen efforts to ensure the fairness and professionalism [of the film industry]," Shi told the Global Times on Wednesday.</p> <p> "Now, the scandals will come to mind whenever I see a film or TV program with Spacey, and that makes me feel very uncomfortable," another Hollywood fan, Xiao Ba, told the Global Times.</p> <p> "However, the scandal hasn't changed my affection for the really good movies and actors in Hollywood, since many of them did bring positive things to my life," Xiao Ba said.</p> <p> In the eyes of those who are not so fond of Hollywood, the scandals serve as a lesson for the Chinese entertainment sector, which has seen rapid growth in recent years and also has a significant impact on youth.</p> <p> "The show business problem with power abuse and sexual harassment is not only in foreign countries. A supportive atmosphere is also needed in China's entertainment industry to encourage the victims to stand out and speak for themselves when treated unfairly," said a 45-year-old teacher, surnamed Zhang.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Expert slams UNESCO for giving in to Japan on ‘comfort women’ documents ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287922</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287922.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 10:37:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171102/70/16763329410375755566.jpg" /></p> <p> <strong>A "comfort women" monument is seen at St. Mary Square in San Francisco, the United States, on Sept. 22, 2017. Comfort Women Justice Coalition, a local grassroots advocacy group devoted to bring justice for the victims of Japanese military sexual slavery during the World War Two, unveiled a monument dedicated to the "comfort women" in San Francisco . (Xinhua/Ma Dan)</strong></p> <p> A Chinese scholar said Wednesday a UN agency "lost its moral compass" when it allegedly bowed to pressure from Japan and postponed nominations for comfort women-related documents for inclusion in the Memory of the World International Register.</p> <p> The UN Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO) failed to stick to its purpose of preserving the true voices in human history, and the postponement shows it shirked on its responsibility, Su Zhiliang, director of Shanghai Normal University's Research Center for Chinese Comfort Women and chief expert of the "Voices of the 'Comfort Women'" program, told the Global Times.</p> <p> The International Advisory Committee (IAC) of UNESCO's Memory of the World (MoW) Program recommended the postponement of nominations to "Voices of the 'Comfort Women'" and "Documentation on 'Comfort Women' and Japanese Army discipline" for the Memory of the World International Register, according to UNESCO's website.</p> <p> The IAC also recommended setting a convenient place and time for a meeting of nominators and concerned parties in hopes of unifying nominations to reflect all relevant documents, the UNESCO said Monday.</p> <p> Su published a statement Tuesday denouncing Japan's obstruction to the nominations and expressed regret over UNESCO's decision.</p> <p> In his statement, Su said that the IAC's decision was made after receiving pressure from the Japanese government, which is trying to improve its image.</p> <p> "Voices of the 'Comfort Women'," records on comfort women, sex slaves of Japanese soldiers during World War II, was endorsed by non-governmental organizations from eight countries and regions, including China, South Korea, the Philippines and Indonesia in 2016. At least 400,000 Asian women were forced to become sex slaves to Japanese soldiers.</p> <p> The other delayed nomination, "Documentation on 'Comfort Women' and Japanese Army discipline," endorsed by Japanese right-wing forces, was meant to ruin the nomination of "Voices of the 'Comfort Women,'" Su said.</p> <p> In September, Japanese right-wing forces threatened to withhold Japan's membership fees if UNESCO decides to include "Voices of the 'Comfort Women'" in its Memory of the World Register.</p> <p> Su said that scholars for the "Voices of the 'Comfort Women'" will meet in Seoul later this month to discuss their next action and whether to meet with the Japanese side.</p> <p> The UNESCO on Monday inscribed 78 new nominations to the Memory of the World International Register, but did not respond to a request for comment from the Global Times as of press time.</p> <p> Chinese Ministry of Foreign Affairsspokesperson Lu Kang said in September that the "Voices of the 'Comfort Women'" will help people around the world fully recognize the cruelty of war, remember the past, cherish peace and safeguard the dignity of mankind, and he urged Japan to treat it the correct way.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Alibaba's Jack Ma to star in short kung fu film ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287627</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1102/c90000-9287627.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 08:30:01 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="Alibaba's Jack Ma to star in short kung fu film" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171102/58/15837960687276993538.jpg" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　A poster of Gong Shou Dao [Photo/Sina Weibo]</p> <p> Chinese e-commerce tycoon Jack Ma has confirmed he is to make his debut next month in a kung fu film alongside action stars such as Jet Li and Donnie Yen.</p> <p> Titled Gong Shou Dao, which means the art of guard and defense, the 20-minute movie, which will not be seen in cinemas, is set to be released on November 11.</p> <p> "That night ... that dream," Ma wrote in a post attached the movie's poster on China's microblogging platform Weibo on Saturday, without giving any details of the plot.</p> <p> Jet Li, the movie's executive producer, told Sina, one of China's leading Internet-based media groups, "We all have the same dream to use the movie to promote traditional Chinese culture and pay a tribute to the predecessors in the field of Chinese kung fu."</p> <p> Other big names among the film's crew include action stars Jet Li, Donnie Yen, Wu Jing and Sammo Hung Kam-bo, boxing star Zou Shiming, Thai actor Tony Jaa and retired Mongolian sumo champion Asashoryu Akinori.</p> <p> Ma, the executive chairman of the Alibaba Group, has long expressed interest in traditional Chinese culture, especially kung fu, and has practiced tai chi for many years.</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="Alibaba's Jack Ma to star in short kung fu film" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171102/37/8836410759688549321.jpg" /></p> <p align="center" class="pictext"> 　　A poster of Gong Shou Dao [Photo/Sina Weibo]</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="Alibaba's Jack Ma to star in short kung fu film" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171102/4/5087564392778222936.jpg" /></p> <p> Jack Ma practices tai chi on M ay 10, 2013, in front of the tai chi house he set up with actor Jet Li. [File Photo/Sina Weibo]</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CRI Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ US man dedicates life to Chinese character study ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287608</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287608.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 17:29:30 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011722000500766640194.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 450px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Richard Sears</em></p> <p> Richard Sears from the U.S. is known in China as the founder of a website about Chinese etymology. Amazed with his two decades of effort researching Chinese characters, Chinese netizens gave him the nickname Hanzi Shushu, or Uncle Hanzi.</p> <p> A former programmer, Sears has already broken down 96,000 ancient characters and 8,000 commonly used Chinese characters through a computing algorithm and scanned them into his self-run chineseetymology.org.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011723000033519990320.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 450px;" /></p> <p> Deeply drawn by Chinese characters, Sears, with expertise in physics, left his hometown in the U.S. state of Tennessee for China to learn Chinese at age 22.</p> <p> Sears decided to establish a website about Chinese etymology in 1994 after he suffered a severe heart attack. In 2011, he rose to Internet fame and began receiving contributions to support the site from Chinese people.</p> <p> His fame even got him a job as a physics teacher at a university in Beijing, but he later left the city because of the high living cost. Now he lives in Huangshan, east China’s Anhui province.</p> <p> Sears claims to be the first man in the world to create a website about Chinese etymology. Now the website has become one of the most viewed sites of its kind across the world.</p> <p> Not everyone has been supportive of his passion. Sears has remained single after his wife left him 20 years ago because she thought he was wasting too much time and money studying Chinese characters.</p> <p> “I want to stay in China to learn more about Chinese characters,” Sears has been quoted as saying in numerous interviews.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011723000130400772355.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 418px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Sears' website about Chinese characters</em></p> <p> Sears hopes people talk more about his achievements than his life story. Although he is getting on in years, he isn’t letting his age keep him from his research. When he feels too tired to work, he will sleep for two to three hours, and then wake up and continue working.</p> <p> Sears became more widely known in China this March, when he shared his story with Chinese on Readers, a TV program aired on China Central Television (CCTV).</p> <p> “I work not to buy myself fancy cars or big houses,” Sears said. Though he has no savings, the 67-year-old said he will not consider publishing a book about his achievements to earn more money. Instead, he will feel happier seeing thousands of people visit his website every day.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011723000589679206190.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 450px;" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Play adaptation of Chinese classical novel makes debut in Vietnam ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287536</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287536.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 15:47:07 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011543000252932576057.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /></p> <p> A play called The Dream of the Red Chamber, adapted from one of China’s four great classical novels, was staged at the Vietnam National Drama Theater for the first time on October 29.</p> <p> The nearly-120-minute play, adapted by Singaporean director Chua Soo Pong, focuses on love and jealousy.</p> <p> The Dream of the Red Chamber depicts in painstaking detail the life and social structures typical of 18th-century Chinese society.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1101/FOREIGN201711011545000087525901497.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 334px;" /></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Halloween parade held in Manhattan, New York City ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287391</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287391.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 13:21:36 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/20/4744258114638859340.jpg" /></p> <p> People watch the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/31/4922253411152778215.jpg" /></p> <p> People participate in the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/61/7413871905954094393.jpg" /></p> <p> People watch the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/21/1783648828483511305.jpg" /></p> <p> A person participates in the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/43/9500738757028833167.jpg" /></p> <p> People participate in the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/31/12577104593674649003.jpg" /></p> <p> A person participates in the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/59/5515621145169516175.jpg" /></p> <p> People participate in the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="U.S.-NEW YORK-HALLOWEEN PARADE" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171101/4/12418138194126575272.jpg" /></p> <p> People participate in the annual Halloween parade in Manhattan, New York City, the United States, Oct. 31, 2017. (Xinhua/Li Muzi)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Halloween causes hassle for Chinese parents ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287126</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287126.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:26:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Chinese parents with children in kindergarten have been struggling with ways to make their pumpkins and costumes for Halloween more creative as their schools have been demanding that they do, which has provoked yet another public debate on celebrating western festivals in China.</p> <p> Several parents interviewed by the Global Times on Tuesday voiced their concerns over celebrating these alien holidays without explaining the history of them and the traditions to children, and over how kindergartens organizing these celebrations are helping a business that targets children.</p> <p> Yu Shengyuan, the father of a 5-year-old who is in a private kindergarten in Yizhuang, Beijing, said that his son's kindergarten celebrated Halloween by having its teachers in colorful clothing handing out candies to the kids.</p> <p> "The children were asked to bring a decorated pumpkin and to wear a costume so I bought my son a pumpkin lantern and an Ultraman costume online. Last year, I bought a Captain America," Yu told the Global Times.</p> <p> A search for Children's Halloween costumes on China's online shopping platform taobao.com resulted in nearly 5,000 items on Tuesday, with most costumes costing around 100 yuan ($15).</p> <p> But the business is not just limited to kindergartens, since Halloween celebrations are also spreading to residential communities.</p> <p> Zhou Taixi, the father of a 4-year-old, in Beijing, said that his community's property management company organized celebrations for families with kids, and even took the kids around to knock on the doors of their neighbors for a "trick-or-treat experience.</p> <p> "The children only knocked on the doors of families who had signed up for the celebration, so they didn't disturb other people," Zhou explained.</p> <p> The word "Halloween" on Sina Weibo had drawn over 1.7 billion hits and 2.8 million comments as of press times, with many posting selfies adorned with scary makeup.</p> <p> However, some netizens were calling for a boycott of all western festivals and saying that Chinese traditions have been dropping in popularity while western festivals get more popular.</p> <p> One serious response came in 2014, when education authorities in the city of Wenzhou, East China's Zhejiang Province called for a ban on any Christmas-related events at all the city's schools, the Beijing Times reported.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Global Times</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Cat out of hell! Feline 'vampire' with unusual fangs dresses up in a cape for Halloween ]]></title>
	<news_id>9287212</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1101/c90000-9287212.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 09:26:56 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> A cat with overgrown fangs is all set for Halloween after being dressed up in a vampire costume to match its unusual set of teeth.</p> <p> The seven-year-old cat called Monk was rescued by Nicole Rienzie's family in 2010.</p> <p> Nicole, 40, a volunteer worker, from Long Island, New York, took Monk to the vet several times but has never been diagnosed with a condition for his vampire-style fangs - so the family have decided to embrace its uniqueness.</p> <p> She said: 'Although Monk has seen a vet numerous times I have not been informed that his teeth are a 'condition'.</p> <p> 'He has had some dental issues and has had several teeth pulled but his fangs remain intact and healthy, to date.'</p> <p> Monk was rescued by the family along with another cat, six-year-old Bean, and the pair have amassed around 63,000 followers on Instagram.</p> <p> Nicole said: 'We rescued Monk in the fall of 2011 and about a year later Bean came along.</p> <p> 'They are now both the best of friends.'&nbsp;&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Mail Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ People of Miao ethnic group celebrate "Chixin" festival in SW China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286654</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1031/c90000-9286654.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 08:26:34 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Palace Museum academy planned to be set up in Xiamen ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286558</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286558.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 15:25:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The Palace Museum is planning to set up a branch institute in Xiamen, southeast China’s Fujian Province, said Shan Jixiang, director of the museum, xmnn.cn reported on Oct. 29. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301524000245374666350.jpg" style="width: 550px; height: 366px;" /></p> <p> The Palace Museum is planning to set up a branch institute in Xiamen, southeast China’s Fujian Province, said Shan Jixiang, director of the museum, xmnn.cn reported on Oct. 29.</p> <p> The institute will be committed to producing professionals for protection of the historical buildings and relics in the Palace Museum.</p> <p> The palace museum, also known as the Forbidden City, is the world’s largest and best preserved ancient wooden structure palace group. About 85 percent of the museum will be open to the public in 2020, according to the director.</p> <p> In addition, Shan disclosed that a “smart Palace Museum” will be built in 3 years, which will be the world’s best digital museum with advanced technologies, equipment and originality.</p> <p> The museum established its first research institute in 2013 as a way to boost the protection of antiques and raise people’s awareness of the cultural heritage, followed by others in Suzhou, Jingdezhen, Xi’an, and Shenzhen, Shan noted.</p> <p> Shan added that Xiamen plans to cooperate with China Poly Group Corporation on construction of the institute and the project is now in the stage of site selection.</p> <p> This May, a museum to exhibit foreign items on the scenic Gulangyu Island was built by the Palace Museum in Xiamen, which attracted crowds of visitors during the National Day Holiday from Oct. 1-8.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China’s “Game of Thrones” to be published in English ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286495</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286495.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 15:05:25 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301357000580262602699.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 954px;" /></p> <p> Sixty years after its first publication, The Legend of the Condor Heroes, a magnum opus that towers above any other wuxia novel in China, is expected to be translated and published in English in 2018.</p> <p> The book, which is the first part of the Condor Trilogy written by famous Chinese novelist Louis Cha Leung-yung, is widely considered as a crowning masterpiece of the wuxia genre and has a widespread following in many Chinese-speaking areas. The book has been hailed by fans as the Chinese version of Game of Thrones and is adapted into comics, TV series, and video games.</p> <p> The news has intrigued many Chinese fans, who worried that the translation may not fully demonstrate the depth and beauty of the wuxia novel.</p> <p> “The English title of the book seems to be a mistranslation to me, as condors are not native to China. If I were the translator, I would use eagle instead. Plus, I really doubt if the foreign readers can understand the book due to the lack of profound understanding of xia culture,” wrote a netizen on Sina Weibo.</p> <p> “Traditional Western literature shares many things in common with Chinese xia culture. [We] are optimistic about the book’s acceptability among English-speaking readers,” Anna Holmwood, the novel’s translator, told Thepaper.cn, adding that the copyright of the Condor Trilogy has already been acquired by a British publisher.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301358000342765758984.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 375px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>TV adaptation of&nbsp;The Legend of the Condor Heroes. [file photo]</em></p> <p> Deriving from China’s xia (heroic chivalry) culture, which emphasizes the importance of martial arts and individual morality in battles against evil and social injustice, the wuxia (wu refers to martial arts) genre of literature and drama is widely celebrated in Chinese popular culture, and has generated remarkable overseas influence in recent years.</p> <p> According to statistics from Novelupdates.com, a website that translates popular Asian novels for Western readers, Chinese wuxia web novels have created a reading frenzy among foreign readers. Among the site’s top 10 most popular web novels as of October, eight were written by Chinese authors.</p> <p> “I’m really looking forward to the book’s publication. As a huge fan of Chinese wuxia novels, I’m fascinated by the martial arts hero themes and Chinese traditional cultural elements. It’d be an honor to finally read the most famous wuxia novel in English,” Vegard Vagslid, a 24-year old Norwegian reader, told People Daily Online.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Party time: Dogs have fun during pet's Halloween parade in Peru ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286508</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286508.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 14:20:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="PERU-LIMA-SOCIETY-DOG-HALLOWEEN" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/20/3420899177099920392.jpg" /></p> <p> A dog participates in a pet's Halloween parade called "Canoween 2017" in Lima, Peru, on Oct. 29, 2017. Approximately 350 dogs participated with their owners in the 4th edition of the "Canoween". (Xinhua/Luis Camacho)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <br /> <img alt="PERU-LIMA-SOCIETY-DOG-HALLOWEEN" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/41/1709874460471170057.jpg" /></p> <p> A resident participates with her dog in a pet's Halloween parade called "Canoween 2017" in Lima, Peru, on Oct. 29, 2017. Approximately 350 dogs participated with their owners in the 4th edition of the "Canoween". (Xinhua/Luis Camacho)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <br /> <img alt="PERU-LIMA-SOCIETY-DOG-HALLOWEEN" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/61/15113966959380395041.jpg" /></p> <p> A man poses with his dog during a pet's Halloween parade called "Canoween 2017" in Lima, Peru, on Oct. 29, 2017. Approximately 350 dogs participated with their owners in the 4th edition of the "Canoween". (Xinhua/Luis Camacho)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <br /> <img alt="PERU-LIMA-SOCIETY-DOG-HALLOWEEN" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/11/5911252234026807663.jpg" /></p> <p> A dog participates in a pet's Halloween parade called "Canoween 2017" in Lima, Peru, on Oct. 29, 2017. Approximately 350 dogs participated with their owners in the 4th edition of the "Canoween". (Xinhua/Luis Camacho)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <br /> <img alt="PERU-LIMA-SOCIETY-DOG-HALLOWEEN" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/71/3462785945493800951.jpg" /></p> <p> A dog participates in a pet's Halloween parade called "Canoween 2017" in Lima, Peru, on Oct. 29, 2017. Approximately 350 dogs participated with their owners in the 4th edition of the "Canoween". (Xinhua/Luis Camacho)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Vintage car exhibition held in Indian-controlled Kashmir ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286509</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286509.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 14:20:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p align="center"> <img alt="INDIA-KASHMIR-SRINAGAR-VINTAGE CAR EXHIBITION" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/34/6249131972546957958.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on Oct. 29, 2017 shows a Morris Minor (front) vintage car on display during a vintage car exhibition in Srinagar, summer capital of Indian-controlled Kashmir.(Xinhua/Javed Dar)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <br /> <img alt="INDIA-KASHMIR-SRINAGAR-VINTAGE CAR EXHIBITION" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/49/5573330340233259789.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on Oct. 29, 2017 shows a Volkswagen Beetle vintage car on display during a vintage car exhibition in Srinagar, summer capital of Indian-controlled Kashmir. (Xinhua/Javed Dar)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p align="center"> <img alt="INDIA-KASHMIR-SRINAGAR-VINTAGE CAR EXHIBITION" src="http://www.people.com.cn/mediafile/pic/20171030/1/10251782231673918981.jpg" /></p> <p> Photo taken on Oct. 29, 2017 shows a vintage Chevrolet car (front) on display during a vintage car exhibition in Srinagar, summer capital of Indian-controlled Kashmir. (Xinhua/Javed Dar)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Digital technology helps recreate iconic cultural heritage ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286460</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1030/c90000-9286460.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 30 Oct 2017 11:16:20 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301114000224886983862.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 266px;" /></p> <p> HANGZHOU, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- About 2,000 km from a 1,500-year-old UNESCO World Heritage site, the Yungang Grottoes, 20 3D printers have been working around the clock.</p> <p> During the past five months, the machines at a workshop in China's southern Shenzhen city have been producing full-size replicas of three Buddhist statues from a cave of the Yungang Grottoes in northern China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The reproduced cave will be soon displayed in eastern coastal city of Qingdao.</p> <p> The grottoes contain more than 51,000 Buddha statues, with the largest 17 meters high and the smallest just two centimeters. However, the various works carved on loose rock will gradually disappear due to erosion.</p> <p> "Even today, scientists are unable to stop the aging of the grottoes using chemical or physical methods," said Li Zhirong, an associate professor with a cultural heritage institute at Zhejiang University.</p> <p> "Therefore, the best way to protect the grottoes is to preserve their information in a scientific, comprehensive and authentic way," said the archaeologist.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301114000404401845516.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 853px;" /></p> <p> Using 3D scanners, the institute provided all the data needed for reproduction of the cave. For a 10-meter-high statue, the error in formation between the original work and the replica is less than 5 millimeters.</p> <p> Digital technology has been implemented in other grotto and fresco projects of the institute.</p> <p> Researchers with the institute replicated the No. 220 cave of the world-renowned Mogao Grottoes in Dunhuang in northwestern Gansu Province.</p> <p> During the project, the team used newly-developed equipment to record every detail of the frescoes, which date back to the Tang Dynasty (618-907).</p> <p> With the high resolution images, the team used software that automatically stitches them together to obtain a whole picture with high precision, according to Diao Changyu, a computer specialist.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1030/FOREIGN201710301114000503495987954.jpg" style="width: 640px; height: 480px;" /></p> <p> Such technology can also solve many archeological mysteries.</p> <p> For example, the team helped identify a badly damaged stone tablet last year after collecting 3D images of it.</p> <p> The 2.8-meter-high and 1.3-meter-wide tablet is perched on the ridge of the Jushi Mountain of Xinzhou in Shanxi. The characters on it are illegible due to natural erosion.</p> <p> Using the high resolution images, researchers recognized the character "Jin." Later, they confirmed the tablet was constructed in the Western Jin Dynasty (265-316) to honor a general who pacified a group of rebels.</p> <p> "The new technology can help us 'see' many things that are invisible to the naked eye," said Qu Chuanfu, academic committee chairman of Shanxi Museum.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Beijing College Students Drama Festival opens ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286010</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1028/c90000-9286010.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 13:22:13 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> College students perform during the opening ceremony of the 6th Beijing College Students Drama Festival in Beijing, capital of China, Oct. 27, 2017. The festival opened here on Friday, and will last until Nov. 6. (Xinhua/Luo Xiaoguang)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Digital technology helps recreate iconic cultural heritage ]]></title>
	<news_id>9286000</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1028/c90000-9286000.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:51:11 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ About 2,000 km from a 1,500-year-old UNESCO World Heritage site, the Yungang Grottoes, 20 3D printers have been working around the clock. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1028/FOREIGN201710281049000230504044465.jpg" style="width: 400px; height: 266px;" /></p> <p> <em>Full-size replicas of Buddhist statues produced by 3D printers [File photo: Wuhan Evening News]</em></p> <p> About 2,000 km from a 1,500-year-old UNESCO World Heritage site, the Yungang Grottoes, 20 3D printers have been working around the clock.</p> <p> During the past five months, the machines at a workshop in China's southern Shenzhen city have been producing full-size replicas of three Buddhist statues from a cave of the Yungang Grottoes in northern China's Shanxi Province.</p> <p> The reproduced cave will be soon displayed in eastern coastal city of Qingdao.</p> <p> The grottoes contain more than 51,000 Buddha statues, with the largest 17 meters high and the smallest just two centimeters. However, the various works carved on loose rock will gradually disappear due to erosion.</p> <p> "Even today, scientists are unable to stop the aging of the grottoes using chemical or physical methods," said Li Zhirong, an associate professor with a cultural heritage institute at Zhejiang University.</p> <p> "Therefore, the best way to protect the grottoes is to preserve their information in a scientific, comprehensive and authentic way," said the archaeologist.</p> <p> Using 3D scanners, the institute provided all the data needed for reproduction of the cave. For a 10-meter-high statue, the error in formation between the original work and the replica is less than 5 millimeters.</p> <p> Digital technology has been implemented in other grotto and fresco projects of the institute.</p> <p> Researchers with the institute replicated the No. 220 cave of the world-renowned Mogao Grottoes in Dunhuang in northwestern Gansu Province.</p> <p> During the project, the team used newly-developed equipment to record every detail of the frescoes, which date back to the Tang Dynasty (618-907).</p> <p> With the high resolution images, the team used software that automatically stitches them together to obtain a whole picture with high precision, according to Diao Changyu, a computer specialist.</p> <p> Such technology can also solve many archeological mysteries.</p> <p> For example, the team helped identify a badly damaged stone tablet last year after collecting 3D images of it.</p> <p> The 2.8-meter-high and 1.3-meter-wide tablet is perched on the ridge of the Jushi Mountain of Xinzhou in Shanxi. The characters on it are illegible due to natural erosion.</p> <p> Using the high resolution images, researchers recognized the character "Jin." Later, they confirmed the tablet was constructed in the Western Jin Dynasty (265-316) to honor a general who pacified a group of rebels.</p> <p> "The new technology can help us 'see' many things that are invisible to the naked eye," said Qu Chuanfu, academic committee chairman of Shanxi Museum.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese film crowns at 54th International Antalya Film Festival ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285994</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1028/c90000-9285994.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 28 Oct 2017 10:50:58 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ ANKARA, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- Chinese film "Angels Wear White" won the Best Film Award late Friday at the 54th International Antalya Film Festival in Turkey's Mediterranean City of Antalya, the first time a Chinese film wins the highest award of this event. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1028/FOREIGN201710281024000295824607022.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 380px;" /></p> <p> <em>Actress Peng Jing attends the premiere of the movie "Angels Wear White" at the 74th Venice Film Festival in Venice, Italy, Sept. 7, 2017. [Photo: Xinhua]</em></p> <p> ANKARA, Oct. 27 (Xinhua) -- Chinese film "Angels Wear White" won the Best Film Award late Friday at the 54th International Antalya Film Festival in Turkey's Mediterranean City of Antalya, the first time a Chinese film wins the highest award of this event.</p> <p> The film, directed by Chinese female director Wen Yan (also known as Vivian Qu), tells a story that happens to two adolescent Chinese girls who are sexual assaulted by a middle-aged man at a hotel and feel helpless in seeking justice.</p> <p> "The film focuses on a worldwide social problem, and thus eventually calls up common awareness among audiences," Wen told Xinhua after the award ceremony.</p> <p> Moreover, the Best Actress Award was given to Wen Qi, a 14-year-old Chinese actress who roles a vital hotel waitress in "Angels Wear White".</p> <p> The Best Director Award was given to Iranian director Mohammad Rasoulof for his film "A Man of Integrity".</p> <p> The International Antalya Film Festival, one of the longest-running art events in Turkey, attracts 10 movies from different countries to participate in its competition section this year.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Children's hats exhibition displays traditional Shanxi culture ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285781</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1027/c90000-9285781.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Oct 2017 14:02:24 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1027/FOREIGN201710271401000333438614084.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 800px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>A Jin-style hat for children. [Photo by Liu Xing/DNKB.com.cn]</em></p> <p> 230 hats for children, from the Qing Dynasty (1644-1911) to the present, went on show at the Shanxi Arts Museum in Shanxi province on Tuesday.</p> <p> Being showed in Shanxi for the first time, the hats were all in Jin-style, as "Jin" is the abbreviation of the province.</p> <p> There are four units at the exhibition, presenting the crafting, function, and cultural value of the children's Jin-style hats.</p> <p> Multiple hats were featured, including tiger-head hats with colorful embroidery from the Qing Dynasty. The exhibition also displayed decorations on children's hats, such as a child made of agate.</p> <p> Jin-style children's hats are often made by women farmers, and embedded with strong local features.</p> <p> Through exchanges between different families, the crafts have been kept and passed down by generations.</p> <p> "The embroidery on Jin-style hats for children is typical Jin-style embroidery on hard materials," Li Li, a staff member at the museum, said. "There are many kinds of children's hats in Shanxi. They are made to protect children from being hurt by the changes of four distinctive seasons."</p> <p> The event, running until Nov 10, took the museum two years to prepare. It is being simultaneously showed in another city in Shanxi, Jincheng, as well as Fuzhou in Fujian province.</p> <p> "The exhibition shows childhood memories of the locals. We intend to let more people know about this traditional folk craft in Shanxi", Li said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Chinadaily.com.cn</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese movie relives WWII China-Myanmar supply lifeline construction ]]></title>
	<news_id>9285421</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1026/c90000-9285421.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Oct 2017 17:56:53 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ A recent film release, “Road to the Sky”, got a screening on Tuesday as a tribute to Chinese villagers who supported a lifeline that connected China with the outside world, during World War II. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1026/FOREIGN201710261655000507565109531.jpg" style="width: 500px; height: 333px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Stage photo of the movie “Road to the Sky”.</em></p> <p> A recent film release, “Road to the Sky”, got a screening on Tuesday as a tribute to Chinese villagers who supported a lifeline that connected China with the outside world, during World War II.</p> <p> The film is based on the real-life story of people in southwest China’s Yunnan Province who strived to build a military supply road in just nine months during the Chinese People's War of Resistance Against Japanese Aggression, and created a miracle in the process.</p> <p> The Burma Road, the name given to it by the Allies, was once</p> <p> the only transportation line China had with the outside world, and was dubbed a “blood transfusion” and “transport artery”, to highlight the important role it played in the Chinese fight against fascist forces.</p> <p> Work on the road started in December 1937 as an international aid and military supply line, after the Japanese invaded China in 1937.</p> <p> The road runs between Kunming, capital of Yunnan Province and Lashio, in Myanmar (Burma) for 1,146 kilometers, 959.4 kilometers of that in Yunnan.</p> <p> Numerous people voluntarily joined the massive effort, including the Han, and the Yi, Bai, Dai, Hui, Jingpo, Achang, Miao, Lisu and De’ang ethnic groups. The Chinese section of the Burma Road opened to traffic on August 31, 1938, more than two years earlier than many engineers had expected, making it a marvel of construction work at that time.</p> <p> After the rail line between Yunnan and Vietnam was blocked by the Japanese after they occupied Vietnam, this road became the main transportation link China had with the outside world.</p> <p> From 1938 to 1942, hundreds of thousands of tons of military supplies were transported to China to help in the fight against the Japanese invaders. At the same time, a large quantity of nonferrous metals, such as tungsten, copper and tin, and tung oil were delivered to Britain and the US to fuel their fight against fascist forces.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ The 4th Tianfu Old Town International Arts Festival Held in Chengdu ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284856</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1025/c90000-9284856.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Oct 2017 20:24:32 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ From August to November, the 4th Tianfu Old Town International Arts Festival is held in Huanglongxi, an old town in Chengdu’s Shuangliu District, under the theme of "Tianfu old towns radiate beauty to the world. See the dreamscape of the water towns and enjoy the music of Huanglongxi." ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251526000154505365826.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 502px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>The 4th Tianfu Old Town International Arts Festival</em></p> <p> From August to November, the 4th Tianfu Old Town International Arts Festival is held in Huanglongxi, an old town in Chengdu’s Shuangliu District, under the theme of "Tianfu old towns radiate beauty to the world. See the dreamscape of the water towns and enjoy the music of Huanglongxi."</p> <p> The festival will showcase original songs and music. It aims to excavate the cultural layer of Huanglongxi as an old town, and to make the old town known worldwide as "Huanglongxi— World’s Leading Millennium Pier." The original songs and music include the folk-music suite "Jincheng String and Wind Instruments: Dreamscape Water Town," the musicals "Tianfu Water Town: Huanglongxi," the theme songs "Splendid Pearl" and "New Song of the Old Town," and an exhibition of traditional and modern Chinese paintings of the town.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251526000411181608996.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Chuangonghaozi performed by boatmen</em></p> <p> In a next step, Shuangliu District will start to focus on two features: history and water, to create a new layout called the Ten-Li (mile) River with Eight Bays, so that each traveler can experience the history of this millennium pier and the leisure lifestyle of Chengdu’s Liujiang Old Town.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251527000119314158198.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Cheongsam Fashion Show in Huanglongxi</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251527000365084150022.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Fire Dragon Dance in Huanglongxi</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251528000020112742079.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Paddlers in Huanglongxi</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251528000280520730074.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 450px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>The 4th Tianfu Old Town International Arts FestivalInaugurated in Chengdu Huanglongxi</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em style="text-align: center;"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1025/FOREIGN201710251528000536678089392.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 533px;" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>An Internet celebrity chef performs while making hand-pulled noodles&nbsp;in Huanglongxi</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ 2017 Chinese Language Spectacular showcases talents of Australian students ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284261</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284261.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 15:39:52 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241526000492639360876.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Rouse Hill Public School students perform music ensemble Yin and Ynag in Motion. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <p> SYDNEY, Oct. 24 (People’s Daily Online) -- On Monday October 23, the 2017 Chinese Language Spectacular at Sydney Town Hall showcased the talents of Chinese language students across New South Wales, Australia.</p> <p> Organized by the Confucius Institute at University of New South Wales and the Chinese Language Teachers Association of NSW, this year’s event coincides with the 45th anniversary of the establishment of Australian-Chinese diplomatic relations.</p> <p> “I hope that with events like tonight’s Spectacular, we continue to build stronger bridges of friendship between our two countries. It is exciting to see young people engage with Chinese language and culture, as they are our future,” said&nbsp;Niu Wenqi,&nbsp;Education Counselor of the Chinese Consulate General in Sydney.</p> <p> Dr. Emma Junfang Xi, the Chinese director of the Confucius Institute at UNSW, stated that this event is to provide a platform for students studying Chinese to express their interest in Chinese language and culture.</p> <p> This year, approximately 800 students from 36 local schools and universities participated in the Spectacular.</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241527000538696546386.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Senior School boys perform choir A Man Must Strengthen Himself. Photo by Ji He</em></p> <p> The program incorporated both well-known Chinese and Australian songs, a symbol of the celebration of the cultural bridges and educational ties between the two countries.</p> <p> “It is through their [students] efforts and understanding that the China-Australian connection will continue to flourish,” said Mr. Niu.</p> <p> “[It is] exciting to see Chinese language education thriving so well in our schools … At UNSW, we are seeing growing interest in Chinese Studies,” said Professor Les Field, Senior Deputy Vice-Chancellor at UNSW. “These days, savvy students know the value of speaking Mandarin.”</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241536000547067360740.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Mr. Niu Wenqi, Education Counsellor, Consulate General of the PRC in Sydney speaks at the Spectacular. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <p> There were traditional Australian bush ballads, such as “Waltzing Maltida” and “Click Go the Shears,” as well as Chinese pop classics, such as “Friends” and “Singing and Smiling.” The night concluded with students performing an English and Chinese rendition of “Auld Lang Syne,” the famous folk song that illustrates sentiments of friendship as old as time.</p> <p> By bringing together talented students from across New South Wales, the Spectacular has established itself as one of the most prominent Chinese language and culture events of 2017.</p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241528000348653583998.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Interview with Rhys Palmer, Director, International Development UNSW Sydney. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241529000250119461460.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Rouse Hill Public School student performs music ensemble Yin and Ynag in Motion. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241530000128137956712.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>All Schools perform joint choir Sydney Welcomes You. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241530000473574988478.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Audience enjoy students' performances. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241531000216863219327.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Carlingford West Public School perform dance Give You a Rose. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241532000358053443315.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Macquarie University students perform comedy sketch Chinese is Too Easy. Photo by Ji He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241533000171875052170.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Pennant Hills High School performs song and dance Moonlight Over the Lotus Pond. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241534000021431833864.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Professor Les Field, Senior Deputy Vice-Chancellor, UNSW Sydney speaks at the Spectacular. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241534000435318199134.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Senior School boys perform choir A Man Must trengthen Himself. Photo by Ji He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241535000237763721955.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Ravenswood School for Girls perform music ensemble Full of Joy. Photo by Yuchen He</em></p> <div style="page-break-after: always"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center"> <em style="text-align: center"><img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241536000028305163751.jpg" style="height: 533px; width: 800px" /></em></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>St. Andrew's Cathedral School performs song Little Dragon. Photo taken by Ji He</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Collective history of China's libraries ]]></title>
	<news_id>9284093</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1024/c90000-9284093.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2017 10:48:28 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1024/FOREIGN201710241043000400662359868.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Tianyige, in Ningbo, Zhejiang province, is believed to be the country's oldest surviving library. [Photo provided to China Daily]</em></p> <p> After seven years' preparation, the first comprehensive history of the nation's libraries was published by the National Library of China earlier this month.</p> <p> The 2-million-character-long A History of Chinese Libraries travels back more than 3,000 years to discover the origins of Chinese book collections and follows the development of libraries throughout the centuries right up until 2009.</p> <p> The new book comes in four volumes covering the ancient, modern and contemporary eras, and an additional appendix.</p> <p> "Uniquely, the book guides readers from ancient times through the ages to the present day using an abundance of references," Han Yongjin, director of the NLC and editor-in-chief of the book, said at its launch at the Beijing institution earlier this month. "It aims to present a fair and panoramic record of how libraries developed in China."</p> <p> Han says the reason why studies of Chinese libraries in ancient and modern times remained separate for so long was because many scholars considered the notion of a library Western, and ancient Chinese institutions housing books should not be included in the term.</p> <p> The major argument for this supposition is that while modern libraries have mainly been established to serve the public, ancient Chinese cangshulou (which literally means a building to store books) functioned instead as private study rooms, with their doors firmly closed to the outside.</p> <p> Royal families, private schools, individual collectors and temples were the four pillars behind developing book collections in ancient China.</p> <p> This opinion in academia thus attributed the appearance of Chinese libraries in the late Qing Dynasty (1644-1911), with the birth of Western-style public libraries in the country.</p> <p> "However, many concepts relating to libraries are also applicable to ancient cangshulou, which also collected used books," Han says. "The modern development of Chinese libraries inherits their spirit, just in another form."</p> <p> Wang Yuguang, a Peking University professor in charge of the volume on libraries in ancient China, admitted that the publishing of this book would not end academic disputes. Nevertheless, he says the contributions made by book collectors on the inheritance of Chinese civilization cannot be doubted.</p> <p> "Some scholars used to criticize ancient book collectors for being too conservative and not allowing more people exposure to their books, but we generally hold a more positive opinion of them now," Wang says. "Thanks to their efforts, we have a better understanding of these books today."</p> <p> He also points out that affording more respect to individual collectors serves a more practical purpose these days.</p> <p> "We still need studies at home to create a relaxed atmosphere conducive to reading," he says. "These will never be replaced by digital books."</p> <p> As for the volume covering the modern era spanning the mid-19th century to the founding of New China in 1949, its lead editor Cheng Huanwen, a professor at the Sun Yat-sen University in Guangzhou, described it as a crucial period in the formation of the library system.</p> <p> Cheng says his panel steered away from making political judgements and maintained a balanced tone in order not to compromise historical accuracy.</p> <p> For example, early Western contribution to modern Chinese libraries, like those from Christian churches, are also listed in the new book. The volume also outlines the development of libraries in Hong Kong, Macao and Taiwan during their years under foreign rule, something mostly absent from previous academic works on similar topics.</p> <p> "However, sometimes it's difficult not to get emotional, especially considering that so many libraries were destroyed by enemy forces during the War of Resistance Against Japanese Aggression (1931-45)," Cheng says. "Yet, the choice of some words may still reflect our stance."</p> <p> The volume on the contemporary era of post-1949 outlines the key achievements made by libraries all over the country in recent decades.</p> <p> Xiao Ximing, a professor from Wuhan University in Hubei province, says many libraries provided vast numbers of submissions during the writing of this volume, but he adds rigid standards were maintained during the selection process to avoid instances of self-promotion.</p> <p> Rather than focus on major libraries, more attention was given to showing the history of smaller, lesser-known yet still crucial institutions to help fill in the gaps in other studies, Xiao says.</p> <p> "This book has monumental significance," says Chen Binbin, deputy director of the public cultural institution department at the Ministry of Culture.</p> <p> "Through interdisciplinary studies, the book also reflects social changes across China as a whole. The history of libraries is a microcosm of the history of Chinese civilization."</p> <p> Xiao also hopes the book will help raise public awareness of the need to care for ancient books just as the draft of a new national public library law is about to be submitted for deliberation at next year's National People's Congress, China's top legislature.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese college offers traditional lion and dragon dance courses ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283632</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1023/c90000-9283632.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 14:17:06 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1023/FOREIGN201710231338000011551499774.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 371px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Students at Zhejiang University perform a dragon dance at a training stadium on campus. [Photo: qjwb.com.cn ]</em></p> <p> Traditional Chinese lion and dragon dance has become popular at Zhejiang University, one of China's top colleges, since it was added into elective sports courses for the first time at the beginning of the new semester.</p> <p> A total of 170 students, both male and female, from various majors have applied for the course.</p> <p> Jiang Kai, the sole teacher, said the courses he offers at the college are actually competitive lion and dragon dance, a style which can usually be seen as a professional sports event.</p> <p> "Compared with traditional folk lion and dragon dance, the competitive style is much more standardized and generally performed indoors. Every movement has strict standards for judging," Jiang added.</p> <p> In the beginning, Jiang was concerned that not many students would apply for his class. "It is a very traditional sport and not fashionable like tennis and golf, which attract more young people."</p> <p> His concern came from the current situation of traditional Chinese sports, which require laborious training sessions and thus are less attractive to young people.</p> <p> "When I first started to study this at Beijing Sports University, there were 30 students in the class, but at graduation, only eight remained," said Jiang.</p> <p> However, the class has exceeded Jiang's expectations.</p> <p> "The reason I chose the course was because I have been interested in traditional Chinese culture for a long time," said freshman Li Qingyan who attends the class,</p> <p> "I am now a junior student at college and just want to select some special and fun courses, dragon dance is definitely one," said another student, Xu Jinyan.</p> <p> Many of his students now have completely thrown themselves into the class, and some even post their daily study on social media.</p> <p> Early in 2003, a campaign to "bring lion and dragon dance classes to 100 universities" was launched by the Federation of University Sports of China Loong-Lion Dance Branch, in a bid to promote the Chinese traditions in colleges. A total of 92 universities have participated in the program.</p> <p> It is expected that more and more Chinese universities will make the lion and dragon dance classes available to their students.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CRI Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China names 10 national cultural demonstration zones ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283627</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1023/c90000-9283627.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 13:35:09 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1023/FOREIGN201710231334000209506743016.jpeg" style="width: 600px; height: 361px;" /></p> <p> China announced on Friday the first batch of 10 national cultural demonstration zones in a bid to boost the country's cultural development, according to the Ministry of Culture.</p> <p> The list includes three zones from the east, middle and west part of the country respectively, and one in the northeast.</p> <p> The 10 zones include the Chengde Mountain Resort in North China's Hebei province, Beijing Road Culture-Oriented Core Area in southern Guangdong province and Whitehorse Lake Creative Eco-City in Zhejiang province.</p> <p> The zones will be named "national cultural demonstration zones" after examinations in three years' time, said the ministry.</p> <p> The zones feature industries ranging from tourism, fine arts and entertainment to design and animation.</p> <p> The ministry will ensure the zones are influential platforms for cultural, scientific and technological innovation.</p> <p> Full list of the 10 national cultural demonstration zones:</p> <p> Chengde Mountain Resort, Chengde city, Hebei province</p> <p> Northeast Asian Cultural Creative Technology Zone, Changchun city, Jilin province</p> <p> Whitehorse Lake Creative Eco-City, Hangzhou city, Zhejiang province</p> <p> Taoxichuan Cultural and Creative Block, Jingdezhen city, Jiangxi province</p> <p> Tai'erzhuang Ancient-City Cultural Industry Park, Taierzhuang city, Shandong province</p> <p> Zhaoshan Mountain Cultural Industry Park, Xiangtan city, Hunan province</p> <p> Beijing Road Culture-Oriented Core Area, Guangzhou city, Guangdong province</p> <p> Nanbin Road Cultural Industry Park, Chongqing city</p> <p> Purple Pottery Cultural Industry Park, Jianshui city, Yunan province</p> <p> Lanzhou Creative Culture Industry Park, Lanzhou city, Gansu province</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China's Peking Opera troupe returns to London with fine productions ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283621</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1023/c90000-9283621.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 23 Oct 2017 13:26:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1023/FOREIGN201710231325000013422736192.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 375px;" /></p> <p> <em>Performers from China National Peking Opera Company are pictured on stage during the classic opera The General and the Prime Minister at the Peacock Theatre in London, Britain, on Oct. 13, 2016.[File Photo: Xinhua]</em></p> <p> The China National Peking Opera Company (CNPOC) returns to Britain for the fourth time when it brings four performances to London's Sadler's Wells this weekend, with the debut of "A River All Red" on Saturday night attracting over 1,000 Chinese nationals and Londoners alike.</p> <p> This is the fourth time the CNPOC has brought productions to Britain, following its tours in 2005, 2015 and 2016.</p> <p> This year marks the 45th anniversary of the establishment of the China-UK ambassadorial diplomatic relations. With the troupe's first three tours well received by British audience and critics, Chinese Ambassador to the UK Liu Xiaoming called the troupe "a golden brand" for China and UK cultural exchange.</p> <p> The performance of "A River All Red" in London is a reproduction of the classic. The opera is a show presenting all four fundamental elements of this performing art -- singing, speaking, acting and fighting.</p> <p> The company has also made improvements on the original production by fine-tuning the tempo, adding more stage imagery effects with modern multimedia technology.</p> <p> British audience Dylan Dryden told Xinhua that the performance of Chinese opera is extraordinary.</p> <p> "It is very very good, very classic -- the costumes and the fashion expressions and the make up and the singing and story -- it's very good, I don't understand the mandarin but I read the story and it's very touching," he said.</p> <p> The opera's leading actor Yu Kuizhi said in an interview with Xinhua that after three times of touring in the UK, the passionate engagement of the audience and the wide attention of the mainstream media have shown the cultural literacy and appreciation of the British audience and their strong interests in Chinese traditional culture.</p> <p> As China's premier Peking Opera organization, the CNPOC comprises celebrated performers, playwrights, directors, composers and stage designers, and has accumulated some of the finest repertoire of productions ranging over the wide diversity of Peking Opera performance styles as well as innovative pioneering works.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Damage assessed at Buddhist grottoes in NW China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283401</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1022/c90000-9283401.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Oct 2017 19:57:19 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ LANZHOU, Oct. 22 (Xinhua) -- A systematic assessment for damage to caves at Maijishan Grottoes in northwest China's Gansu Province has been conducted for restoration work, according to local authorities. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> LANZHOU, Oct. 22 (Xinhua) -- A systematic assessment for damage to caves at Maijishan Grottoes in northwest China's Gansu Province has been conducted for restoration work, according to local authorities.</p> <p> The Maijishan Grottoes are a 1,600-year-old UNESCO World Heritage site consisting of about 200 caves and more than 10,000 Buddhist sculptures.</p> <p> The assessment has classified the 221 caves in the grottoes into three risk levels, with 32 caves among the most severe facing risks such as collapse and murals falling off.</p> <p> The general assessment is for the preparation of our protection and restoration work, said Yue Yongqiang, deputy director of Maijishan Grottoes art institute preservation division.</p> <p> Due to natural humidity and erosion, cracks have appeared on some caves and some sculptures and murals are in a state of decay.</p> <p> Maijishan Grottoes is one of China's four largest Buddhist cave complexes, along with Mogao, Yungang and Longmen grottoes in Gansu, Shanxi and Henan provinces, respectively.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China National Peking Opera Company lands in London for dramatic encore ]]></title>
	<news_id>9283063</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1021/c90000-9283063.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 14:38:47 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1021/FOREIGN201710211437000590817509281.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Peking Opera [File Photo: pconline.com.cn]</em></p> <p> The China National Peking Opera Company will return to the UK for the third time when it brings four performances to London's Sadler's Wells this weekend.</p> <p> Romantic comedy The Phoenix Returns Home and tragic military drama A River All Red will open at renowned dance venue Sadler’s Wells on October 21.</p> <p> This is the third time the National Peking Opera Company has brought productions to the UK, following tours in 2015 and 2016.</p> <p> In an interview with SINO radio, director Kevin Zhang said audiences attending the performances could expect a combination of music, acrobatics, drama and dance drawing on traditional and modern influences. “This is a very unique performing art,” he told listeners.</p> <p> Zhang also told audiences to look out for the distinctive use of makeup and costume in the operas. “Each color on (the actor’s) face and costume can tell us something about the story,” he added.</p> <p> Jin Xu, chancellor from the Chinese Embassy in the UK, said that the visit represented a wider trend of the UK paying greater attention to Chinese culture.</p> <p> Peking Opera, one of China’s most influential styles of stage art, has been around for over 200 years in China. Performers often train from a young age in a wide range of stage arts including singing, dancing, acting, mime and acrobatics.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CRI Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Meet ‘Monkey King on monocycle,’ a monocycle fanatic by the West Lake ]]></title>
	<news_id>9282777</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1020/c90000-9282777.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2017 17:32:48 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/10/20/6ff036f3-5f1a-4539-b4d7-be5b7a555bbf.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1020/FOREIGN201710201730000545704197015.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 458px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Meet ‘Monkey King on monocycle,’ a monocycle fanatic by the West Lake</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Old Summer Palace marks 157th anniversary of massive loot ]]></title>
	<news_id>9282042</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1019/c90000-9282042.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 13:12:21 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1019/FOREIGN201710191310000380983892123.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> Dashuifa site in Yuanmingyuan [Photo/CGTN]</p> <p> Beijing’s Old Summer Palace is marking the 157th anniversary of a massive sack during the Second Opium War, when thousands of Chinese cultural relics were either ruined or removed.</p> <p> Located in the northwestern part of China’s capital city, the exquisite palace, known in Chinese as Yuanmingyuan, was extolled as the "Garden of Gardens" and the "Versailles of the East" during its heyday. It is renowned throughout the world for its grand and elegant landscape, with outstanding construction skills and extensive collection of gardens, architecture, art and historical treasures.</p> <p> With a floor area of 350 hectares and building area of almost 200,000 square meters, Yuanmingyuan is composed of three gardens: Yuanmingyuan, Changchunyuan and Qichunyuan. In January 1988, it was named as a key national cultural relic protection site. And in the same year, the palace was officially opened to the public, who were able to visit free on Wednesday to mark the anniversary.</p> <p> They had the opportunity to watch on-site excavation work conducted by professional archaeologists as well as attend experts' and scholars’ lectures on the park's history and cultural relics – all for free.</p> <p> The initial construction of the palace began in 1707 during reign of Emperor Kangxi, and the expansion continued for next 150 years in the Qing Dynasty (1636-1912 AD). It was used to serve emperors as an imperial garden to take a rest or handle state affairs during the hot summer months.</p> <p> However, Anglo-French forces sacked and looted Yuanmingyuan and burned it to the ground on October 18, 1860 during the Second Opium War. The garden subsequently suffered continual damage at the hands of warlords, bandits, and the Eight-Power Allied Forces.</p> <p> Since 1996, a total of three excavations have been conducted in the palace resulting in the discovery of more than 50,000 pieces of relics so far. The most recent excavation began in 2013 and will last until 2020, making it the largest excavation project in Yuanmingyuan.</p> <p> But numerous relics remain overseas. UNESCO estimated in 2006 that about 1.6 million Chinese relics were in the possession of 47 museums worldwide, including one million from the Old Summer Palace alone.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1019/FOREIGN201710191311000226634287624.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> The reinforced historical site at the Old Summer Palace, also known as Yuanmingyuan, Beijing, capital of China. [Photo/CGTN]</p> <p> Chinese government and civic individuals have been working hard to bring the pieces back home during the past years through purchasing, donations, auctions and other means. In 2006, a new strategy was put into action to collect and request their return. Despite the park’s hard work, fewer than 100, mainly stone sculptures, have been repatriated so far.</p> <p> In late October, Yuanmingyuan will jointly hold the first-ever movie season with the Beijing Film Academy, including a series of interactive film-watching sessions.</p> <p> The film season is expected to last a week, showcasing various classic and patriotic films to citizens for free – in an effort to remind Chinese people of the unfortunate past while looking to a bright future at the same time.&nbsp;</p> <p> &nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Street food culture explored in Tianjin ]]></title>
	<news_id>9281968</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1019/c90000-9281968.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 19 Oct 2017 10:02:45 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1019/FOREIGN201710191001000062732943744.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> Street food is an indispensable part of Chinese cuisine culture. With the zeal for Chinese baozi and jianbing waxing overseas, street food maintains its long-lasting popularity among people at home.</p> <p> Last weekend, a group of street vendors in Tianjin was invited into the courtyard of the Ritz-Carlton Tianjin for its first Street Food Festival.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1019/FOREIGN201710191001000234660305713.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> It became a lively fair with peddlers in food carts bringing their signature dishes from street corners or night markets. Most of these businesses are run by local families.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1019/FOREIGN201710191001000405509267939.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> The event featured not only traditional Tianjin snacks, which are famous nationwide, such as jianbingguozi (pancake and fried dough sticks) and shuligao (steamed rice cake with condiments), but also dozens of street snacks popular in Tianjin, including seafood noodle, steamed rice rolls, green bean jelly and fried yogurt, to name just a few.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1019/FOREIGN201710191002000002777040990.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> All the food comes from independent street vendors instead of big restaurant chains. To guarantee hygiene and safety, the hotel made contractual regulations with every participating vendor at the festival.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Movie collaboration by BRICS directors to be released in China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9280445</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1016/c90000-9280445.html</link>
	<pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2017 20:54:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 16 (Xinhua) -- An anthology of short films, jointly made by directors from each of the BRICS countries, will be released nationwide in China Thursday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 16 (Xinhua) -- An anthology of short films, jointly made by directors from each of the BRICS countries, will be released nationwide in China Thursday.</p> <p> The feature, named Where Has Time Gone, consists of five parts, each by a different director, said the Chinese director Jia Zhangke in Beijing Monday.</p> <p> The four directors working alongside Jia were Walter Salles from Brazil, Aleksey Fedorchenko from Russia, Madhur Bhandarkar from India, and Jahmil X.T. Qubeka from South Africa.</p> <p> In the anthology, Jia's story is about a couple who want a second child. Salles shows the aftermath of a dam collapse. Bhandarkar tells the friendship between an old man and an orphan. Fedorchenko depicts a couple living in a valley. Qubeka sets his part in the future.</p> <p> "The emotions from all five stories can be shared by anyone in any country," said Jia, adding that the film would be a successful demonstration of the deep communication and cooperation in the film industry among BRICS countries.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Lanzhou beef noodle soup set to reach Italy ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279739</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1014/c90000-9279739.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 11:42:39 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1014/FOREIGN201710141141000150698384923.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Veteran chef Ma Wenbin from Lanzhou, the capital of Gansu province, demonstrates the skill to make lanzhou lamian. [Photo provided to China Daily]</em></p> <p> The beef noodle soup in Lanzhou in northwestern China has a history that goes back more than 100 years ago.</p> <p> Now the typical Chinese dish has an ambition to get into Italy, a country known for its pasta.</p> <p> In a recent culinary event jointly held by Lanzhou, the capital of Gansu province, and Italy embassy in Beijing, a veteran Chinese chef showed off the dazzling skills of turning a dough into diverse sizes of noodles.</p> <p> Besides, an Italian chef also showcased the complicated process of cooking pasta.</p> <p> Organizers say the event wants to exchange culinary cultures between the two countries, and to raise the reputation of Lanzhou noodle soup to Italians.</p> <p> So far, the Lanzhou beef noodle soup has been reaching out to more than 20 countries, such as the United States, France and South Korea, and is expected to reach more like Italy, according to the Chinese organizers.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: China Daily</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Confucius Institute provides platform between China, Fiji ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279731</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1014/c90000-9279731.html</link>
	<pubDate>Sat, 14 Oct 2017 10:50:15 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> The Confucius Institute at the University of the South Pacific (CI-USP), headquartered in the Fijian capital of Suva has been well received for its great success over the past five years and for providing a platform for promoting friendship and cooperation between China and Fiji, and the Pacific region.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1014/FOREIGN201710141040000503117759419.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 333px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Participants of a Qigong exercise with instructor Xiaoning Lu (second from left) at the University of the South Pacific’s (USP) Cook Islands Campus on Oct 4, 2017. [Photo: USP]</em></p> <p> The CI-USP, which became fully operational in 2012, was established between the University of the South Pacific (USP) and Beijing University of Posts and Telecommunications (BUPT).</p> <p> Currently, it comprises 15 staff members and in March 2014, due to the high demand for Chinese language learning and teaching in the western part of Fiji, CI-USP opened a Teaching Point at USP's Lautoka Campus. In 2015 a Confucius Classroom soon followed in the Emalus Campus in Vanuatu, and another Confucius Classroom opened in the Cook Islands Campus.</p> <p> The successes of the Confucius Institute at USP have been recognised and the institute was rewarded as the Model CI Project by the Confucius Institute Headquarters in 2016.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1014/FOREIGN201710141041000119444734002.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 451px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>An isntructor teaches how is the “Chi” running in the body at the University of the South Pacific’s (USP) on Sept 18, 2017. [Photo: USP]</em></p> <p> The award enables USP to make a substantial investment in improved learning and teaching facilities for the Confucius Institute at USP.</p> <p> The extension of the Model Confucius Institute at USP will facilitate Chinese language learning and teaching and culture promotion across all the USP campuses, as it will have state-of-the-art technology that will complement the online facilities available at USP.</p> <p> Speaking at a groundbreaking ceremony for the extension of the Model Confucius Institute at USP on Friday, Fijian President Jioji Konousi Konrote praised the CI-USP for providing a platform for building friendship and cooperation between China and Fiji, and the Pacific region.</p> <p> "The Confucius Institute is providing a platform for building friendship and cooperation between China and Fiji, and the Pacific region. We hope that this will further pave the way for deeper cooperation based on mutual trust, which is necessary for the delivery of the social and economic benefits that we all desire," Konrote said.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1014/FOREIGN201710141041000273806096543.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 450px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Students try Chinese calligraphy at the University of the South Pacific’s (USP) on Sept 11, 2017. [Photo: USP]</em></p> <p> He said that the learning and teaching of the Chinese language and culture is crucial and should be seen as one of the main tools for the development of the relationship between Fiji and China.</p> <p> "Effective communication is the key to increasing our understanding of each other. Learning each other's languages will lead to a better appreciation of each other's cultures and traditions," he said. "The fact that the institute has brought the opportunity to learn right to our doorstep is very encouraging. I urge young and willing students not to miss this opportunity."</p> <p> From a Fiji perspective, the president continued, it is part of their ultimate aim to create a knowledge-based society where their people could learn more about the world, about the global community and about different nations and their respective peoples, cultures and traditions. And he believed that all the other Pacific Island countries that have part of USP desire for the same outcomes.</p> <p> He believed that the groundbreaking ceremony not only marks the beginning of the renovation and extension of the Model CI-USP building, but it also extends the opportunity for improved relations between China and their Pacific Island countries.</p> <p> For his part, Rajesh Chandra, vice-chancellor and president of USP, expressed his satisfaction with the development of the CI-USP.</p> <p> The Confucius Institute at USP provides a unique avenue to introduce Chinese language and culture to the general public and to carry out China-related activities within USP, he said, adding that it not only engages in extending development and cooperation in education but also engages in extending the friendly cooperation in Sino-Pacific cultural communication, economics and technology communication, information communication, among others.</p> <p> Meanwhile, Chinese Ambassador to Fiji Zhang Ping said that the groundbreaking ceremony marks an important milestone and a new beginning in the course of development of the Confucius Institute. It is a testament of the remarkable accomplishments that CI-USP has achieved over the past years. The new classroom and office building will provide a much bigger space and better work environment for students and teachers. It will bring the development of the Confucius Institute to a new level.</p> <p> On behalf of BUPT President Qiao Jianyong, Ren Chunxia, director of BUPT international office, said that as an important platform and window of Chinese teaching, cultural exchange and understanding of China for people of Fiji and the South Pacific Islands, CI-USP will play a more significant role in increasing the understanding and friendship between Chinese people and peoples from the South Pacific Island countries.</p> <p> "Today's groundbreaking ceremony means so much for CI-USP. It signifies that CI-USP has gone through five years of early stage and is stepping forward to a new development stage," she said. "CI-USP will step to a new high for Chinese teaching and cultural exchange, and make greater contribution to the friendly relationship between BUPT and USP."&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China to continue cooperation with UNESCO: FM ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279727</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1013/c90000-9279727.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 20:36:54 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ BEIJING, Oct. 13 (Xinhua) -- China will continue to actively participate in and support the work of UNESCO, a Foreign Ministry spokesperson said Friday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> BEIJING, Oct. 13 (Xinhua) -- China will continue to actively participate in and support the work of UNESCO, a Foreign Ministry spokesperson said Friday.</p> <p> Spokesperson Hua Chunying made the remarks when asked to comment on the decisions of the United States and Israel to withdraw from the United Nations Educational, Scientific and Cultural Organization (UNESCO).</p> <p> Hua said that the principle of UNESCO is to boost international cooperation in education, science and culture, promote mutual understanding and integration between different cultures, and maintain world peace in order to achieve common development.</p> <p> "We hope all countries can contribute to this aim," said the spokesperson, adding China is willing to cooperate with other countries in this regard.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ French painter donates "comfort women" paintings to Nanjing Massacre Museum ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278954</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1012/c90000-9278954.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 16:14:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ Renowned French painter Christian Poirot has decided to donate a series of paintings he's produced to the Nanjing Massacre Museum which are meant to highlight the plight of "comfort women" during the War, reports Chinanews.com. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Renowned French painter Christian Poirot has decided to donate a series of paintings he's produced to the Nanjing Massacre Museum which are meant to highlight the plight of "comfort women" during the War, reports Chinanews.com.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120925000259212588258.jpg" style="width: 540px; height: 359px;" /></p> <p> <em>French painter Christian Poirot donates works he's completed depicting the Nanjing Massacre. [Photo: Chinanews.com]</em></p> <p> Poirot says he became inspired after travelling to Nanjing recently and learning about the "Rape of Nanjing."</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120925000591726125200.jpg" style="width: 540px; height: 405px;" /></p> <p> <em>Christian Poirot's "Physical examination," one of three paintings the renowned French artist has donated to the Nanjing Massacre Museum [Photo: Chinanews.com]</em></p> <p> It took Poirot around a month to create the three works, entitled "The eyes of hell," "Physical examination" and "The woman say 'no'"</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120926000225634740659.jpg" style="width: 540px; height: 405px;" /></p> <p> <em>Christian Poirot's "The Eyes of Hell," one of three paintings the renowned French artist has donated to the Nanjing Massacre Museum [Photo: Chinanews.com]</em></p> <p> "The photos of the victims that I saw in Nanjing made a deep impression on me," said Poirot.</p> <p> The paintings themselves are meant to depict scenes in Nanjing in late 1937, when Japanese forces overran the then-Chinese capital, systematically murdering and raping over 200,000 people.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120926000415283669639.jpg" style="width: 540px; height: 360px;" /></p> <p> <em>Christian Poirot presents flowers at a former site where so-called "comfort women" were housed by Japanese troops in Nanjing in December, 1937. [Photo: Chinanews.com]</em></p> <p> In announcing the donation of the three paintings, Poirot says he intends to create more works ahead of National Memorial Day for the Nanjing Massacre Victims, which falls on December 13th.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CRI Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Shanghai Fashion Week Spring/Summer 2018 opens ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278846</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1012/c90000-9278846.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 16:14:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120843000462465414442.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 900px;" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation during the Shanghai Fashion Week Spring/Summer 2018 in Shanghai, east China, Oct. 11, 2017. Shanghai Fashion Week kicked off here on Wednesday. (Xinhua/Du Xiaoyi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120844000148977980689.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> Models present creations during the Shanghai Fashion Week Spring/Summer 2018 in Shanghai, east China, Oct. 11, 2017. Shanghai Fashion Week kicked off here on Wednesday. (Xinhua/Du Xiaoyi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120844000489658792106.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation during the Shanghai Fashion Week Spring/Summer 2018 in Shanghai, east China, Oct. 11, 2017. Shanghai Fashion Week kicked off here on Wednesday. (Xinhua/Du Xiaoyi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120845000074604121515.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p> A model presents a creation during the Shanghai Fashion Week Spring/Summer 2018 in Shanghai, east China, Oct. 11, 2017. Shanghai Fashion Week kicked off here on Wednesday. (Xinhua/Du Xiaoyi)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chef cuts noodles while riding on a monocycle at People's Daily's HQ canteen ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279553</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1013/c90000-9279553.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 14:06:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/10/13/d7fb4850-892c-4517-bf4f-33fe9653569b.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1013/FOREIGN201710131402000431753768827.jpg" style="width: 720px; height: 720px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Chef cuts noodles while riding on a monocycle at People's Daily's HQ canteen</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Yummy! A bite of Portugal in China ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279547</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1013/c90000-9279547.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 13:58:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/10/13/693c35e6-9ffb-4ad0-872d-24f8dc0e1945.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1013/FOREIGN201710131351000316115055472.jpg" style="width: 800px; height: 461px" /></p> <p style="text-align: center"> <em>Yummy! A bite of Portugal in China</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ China remains top destination of foreign capital for 25 years ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279481</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1013/c90000-9279481.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 09:44:26 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1013/FOREIGN201710130942000291833630350.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 372px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>(File Photo)</em></p> <p> The Chinese authorities say the country is attracting the most foreign investment among developing countries as it eases access for foreign capital.</p> <p> It's also reported that a growing number of Chinese enterprises are going out as China deepens reform and promotes overseas trade and economic cooperation.</p> <p> Official data shows that China's actual use of foreign direct investment amounted to over 489-billion US dollars between 2013 and 2016.</p> <p> That marked an annual growth of 3-percent.</p> <p> Speaking at a news conference, a spokesperson from the Ministry of Commerce, Gao Feng, said that foreign capital inflow has been climbing steadily in China.</p> <p> "As global transnational direct investment dropped 2-percent, China's actual use of foreign investment reached over 864-billion yuan, a year-on-year growth of 3-percent. Between 2013 and 2016, the number of China's newly-added foreign entities accumulated to over 100-thousand. China attracted over 521-billion US dollars of foreign capital in the same period ranking the top among developing countries for 25 years."</p> <p> The spokesperson added that foreign investment in China has seen improvement, both in quantity and quality, with growing foreign capital flowing into hi-tech industry.</p> <p> Data suggests the hi-tech sector attracted 2-percent of the total foreign investment in 2016, while the number of R&amp;D centers of multinational companies also exceeded 2400.</p> <p> "In 2016, the fixed asset investment of foreign entities grew at a rate higher than the 7.5-percent of national average. Foreign entities also accounted for about 44-percent of the countries' exports and contributed to 18-percent of tax revenue. The foreign entities, less than 3-percent of China's total companies, also created almost half of trade revenue and one fifth of fiscal revenue."</p> <p> Meanwhile, Chinese investments overseas are also improving in amount and quality, as China increases services and provides guarantee to innovation and overseas cooperation.</p> <p> As Gao Feng said, China's investment overseas ranked second in the world in 2015 and 2016; by the end of last year, China's investment overseas totaled 5-trillion US dollars.</p> <p> "From 2012 to 2016, China's contracted engineering projects overseas achieved a total turnover of 710-billion US dollars, marking an annual average growth of 9-percent. China has become a major engineering contractor in the world."</p> <p> It is said Chinese enterprises from sectors including steel, cement, and automobiles are accelerating pace in building manufacturing bases overseas, spreading Chinese equipment, standards, and services to the world.</p> <p> The Ministry of Commerce said they also have plans to further expand the effort to other sectors.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CRI Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Chinese portrait painting exhibition unveiled in Berlin ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279460</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1013/c90000-9279460.html</link>
	<pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 09:18:03 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p> Visitors look on exhibits during the Chinese portrait painting exhibition "Faces of China, Portrait Painting of the Ming and Qing Dynasties (1368-1912)" in Berlin, capital of Germany, on Oct. 11, 2017. Europe's first-ever grand exhibition explicitly dedicated to Chinese portrait paintings was unveiled in Berlin in the evening of Wednesday, the day China and Germany celebrated the 45th anniversary of the establishment of diplomatic ties. (Xinhua/Shan Yuqi)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Mandarin fever indicates bullish bet on China’s future: People's Daily ]]></title>
	<news_id>9279274</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1012/c90000-9279274.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 21:12:50 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710122056000274989748726.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>(File photo)</em></p> <p> The first bilingual Chinese-English school in Europe, Kensington Wade, recently opened in London, which is an epitome of the Mandarin fever among people around the world, indicating their bullish bet on China’s future, People’s Daily reported on Oct. 12.</p> <p> The parents who send their children to the school believe that mastering Chinese will bring more opportunities for their children’s development.</p> <p> People around the world hope to know about China and Chinese civilization through learning Chinese language with the continuous improvement of China’s international influence over the years.</p> <p> Statistics shows that the number of people learning Mandarin worldwide has surged from 30 to 100 million since 2004.</p> <p> The US-based nonprofit organization American Councils for International Education says that the number of primary and secondary students who learn Mandarin in the US doubled from 2009 to 2015. French media also noted that the number in France quadrupled in the past decade.</p> <p> In addition, South Africa, Mauritius, Tanzania, Cameroon, and Zambia have all included Chinese in their national education system since 2016.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Tai Chi shows promise as cardiac rehab exercise: study ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278798</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1012/c90000-9278798.html</link>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 08:46:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ WASHINGTON, Oct. 11 (Xinhua) -- Tai Chi, a traditional Chinese practice involving slow and gentle movements, may help heart disease patients who decline traditional cardiac rehabilitation, according to preliminary research published Wednesday. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1012/FOREIGN201710120828000485585545851.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 400px;" /></p> <p> <em>Jose de Jesus Martinez, 71, exercises Tai Chi in Mexico City, capital of Mexico, Nov. 14, 2015. [Photo: Xinhua]</em></p> <p> WASHINGTON, Oct. 11 (Xinhua) -- Tai Chi, a traditional Chinese practice involving slow and gentle movements, may help heart disease patients who decline traditional cardiac rehabilitation, according to preliminary research published Wednesday.</p> <p> In a small study of 29 physically inactive heart disease patients, researchers found that Tai Chi may improve exercise behaviors in this high-risk population with no observable adverse events except for minor muscular pain at the beginning of training.</p> <p> After a heart attack, more than 60 percent of patients decline participation in cardiac rehabilitation, often because they perceive physical exercise as unpleasant, painful or impossible given their current physical condition, according to the study published in the Journal of the American Heart Association.</p> <p> "We thought that Tai Chi might be a good option for these people because you can start very slowly and simply and, as their confidence increases, the pace and movements can be modified to increase intensity," lead author Elena Salmoirago-Blotcher, assistant professor of medicine at the Warren Alpert School of Medicine at Brown University, said in a statement.</p> <p> "Tai Chi exercise can reach low-to-moderate intensity levels. The emphasis on breathing and relaxation can also help with stress reduction and psychological distress," she said.</p> <p> The study, conducted at The Miriam Hospital in Providence, Rhode Island, involved eight women and 21 men, whose average age was 67.9 years.</p> <p> Most of them had experienced a previous heart attack or procedure to open a blocked artery, and all had declined cardiac rehabilitation and continued to have many high-risk characteristics, including current smoker, diabetes, high cholesterol, and being overweight or obese.</p> <p> For the study, they took part in a shorter program with 24 classes over 12 weeks or a longer program with 52 classes over 24 weeks. All participants received a DVD so that they could practice Tai Chi at home.</p> <p> In addition to establishing safety, the results showed that Tai Chi was well liked by participants, who all said they would recommend it to a friend.</p> <p> The exercise intervention was also proved feasible, with patients attending about 66 percent of scheduled classes.</p> <p> The results also showed that while Tai Chi did not raise aerobic fitness on standard tests after three months of either the programs, it did raise the weekly amount of moderate to vigorous physical activity after three and six months in the group participating in the longer program.</p> <p> Salmoirago-Blotcher said in an email to Xinhua that there is a fair amount of literature supporting the benefit of Tai Chi for patients with heart disease.</p> <p> For example, a recent meta-analysis published in 2016 showed that Tai Chi exercise can improve physical functioning, quality of life, depression, and blood pressure in patients with heart disease, she said.</p> <p> But Salmoirago-Blotcher noted that her study was only designed to study the feasibility and safety of Tai Chi, not the efficacy, as an exercise alternative for patients that don't attend cardiac rehabilitation.</p> <p> A yoga practitioner, Salmoirago-Blotcher said she had tried Tai Chi herself to get a sense of how it feels before she designed this study and proposed it to her patients.</p> <p> "On its own, Tai Chi wouldn't obviously replace other components of traditional cardiac rehabilitation, such as education on risk factors, diet and adherence to needed medications," she said.</p> <p> "If proven effective in larger studies, it might be possible to offer it as an exercise option within a rehab center as a bridge to more strenuous exercise, or in a community setting with the educational components of rehab delivered outside of a medical setting," she said.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Dispersed relics return to Beijing’s Old Summer Palace ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278698</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1011/c90000-9278698.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 17:25:05 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ More than 80,000 pieces of stones and bricks have returned to Beijing’s Yuanmingyuan, known as the Old Summer Palace, Beijing Morning News reported on Oct. 11. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111720000446253404406.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p> More than 80,000 pieces of stones and bricks have returned to Beijing’s Yuanmingyuan, known as the Old Summer Palace, Beijing Morning News reported on Oct. 11.</p> <p> The palace park was used as a royal garden during the Qing Dynasty (1644-1911) and was known for its exquisite architecture and many works of art. Unfortunately, it was destroyed and many treasures were looted during the Second Opium War (1856-60).</p> <p> A massive archaeological excavation has uncovered more than 50,000 cultural relics so far. All of the excavated relics are exhibited in the park so that the public can learn more about the park and its history.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111720000547379664008.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p> In 2015, a working group responsible for recovering lost relics was set up. Over 80 thousand relics have been recovered to date, including lost bricks, tiles, and stone sculptures.</p> <p> Over 50 million yuan (around $7.6 million) has been used to preserve Yuanmingyuan. There are now 1,100 surveillance cameras, and the remaining architecture has been reinforced.</p> <p> Every brick and tile is a cultural relic of the palace, said Chen Hui, director of the park’s department for the protection of cultural relics.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111721000043817686630.jpg" style="width: 300px; height: 399px;" /></p> <p> Though the stone pieces are less valuable compared with some renowned pieces of art from the garden, they are still parts of the garden and should go back home, said Chen.</p> <p> The returned stones have been placed near the south wall, creating a 20-meter long “Great Wall.” Visitors will be able to appreciate the dispersed relics this year.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Another 3 Chinese ancient water conservancy projects included on World Heritage list ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278651</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1011/c90000-9278651.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 16:13:37 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111611000573202613469.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 348px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111612000120365168905.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 331px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>The&nbsp;irrigation projects in Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region</em></p> <p> Another three Chinese ancient water conservancy projects were included on the world irrigation engineering project heritage list at a meeting of the International Commission on Irrigation and Drainage (ICID) held in Mexico City on Oct. 10, CCTV.com reported.</p> <p> The three irrigation projects in Shaanxi Province, Ningxia Hui Autonomous Region, and Fujian Province bring the total of such projects included on the list in China to 13.</p> <p> Since 2014, ICID has chosen irrigation engineering projects that are better than others of the same era in terms of engineering design and construction technology and which have more than 100 years of history.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Symphony concert titled "China Story: the Songs of the Earth" held in Berlin ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278484</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1011/c90000-9278484.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 13:21:38 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111318000201208047041.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 603px;" /></p> <p> Photo taken on Oct. 10, 2017 shows a view of the symphony concert titled "China Story: the Songs of the Earth" at the Konzerthaus Berlin in Berlin, Germany. (Xinhua/Shan Yuqi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111318000455707163992.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 594px;" /></p> <p> Photo taken on Oct. 10, 2017 shows a view of the symphony concert titled "China Story: the Songs of the Earth" at the Konzerthaus Berlin in Berlin, Germany. (Xinhua/Shan Yuqi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111319000075247483461.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 670px;" /></p> <p> Conductor Hu Yongyan (front) is seen at the symphony concert titled "China Story: the Songs of the Earth" held at the Konzerthaus Berlin in Berlin, Germany, on Oct. 10, 2017. (Xinhua/Shan Yuqi)</p> <div style="page-break-after: always;"> <span style="display: none;">&nbsp;</span></div> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111319000317711523964.jpg" style="width: 899px; height: 658px;" /></p> <p> Soprano Luan Yitian (front) performs during the symphony concert titled "China Story: the Songs of the Earth" held at the Konzerthaus Berlin in Berlin, Germany, on Oct. 10, 2017. (Xinhua/Shan Yuqi)</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: Xinhua</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Ballet drama highlights Dunhuang cave art and its protectors ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278452</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1011/c90000-9278452.html</link>
	<pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 10:21:01 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[ The ancient ballet drama "Dunhuang" in northwestern China's Gansu Province is one of the must-see treasures of the world. ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111018000255743720432.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 600px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>(Photo/CGTN)</em></p> <p> The ancient ballet drama "Dunhuang" in northwestern China's Gansu Province is one of the must-see treasures of the world.</p> <p> It annually attracts numerous tourists and casts a magic spell over artists, many of whom have spent their lives protecting and preserving the artwork. A ballet drama dedicated to the charm of Dunhuang's cave art and its protectors' devotion was recently staged in Beijing to much praise.</p> <p> The show premiered at Beijing's Tianqiao Art Center in late September. Presented by dancers of the National Ballet of China, it tells the story of a romance between an overseas Chinese violinist Nian Yu and a Dunhuang art protector called Wu Ming.</p> <p> Nian Yu first came across a book of paintings about the Dunhuang cave art in Paris, which seduced her into coming to the Mogao Grottoes, also known as the Thousand Buddha Grottoes, in the southeast of the center of Dunhuang.</p> <p> There she met and fell in love with Wu Ming, who protected the murals by copying them.</p> <p> Their love bloomed in the wild desert, charmed by the beauty of the flying Apsaras portrayed in the caves. But when Nian Yu had to leave for Paris, Wu would not follow her because he couldn't afford to leave his beloved Dunhuang.</p> <p> After their heart-breaking separation, Wu threw himself into saving the grotto murals but fell ill from overwork.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1011/FOREIGN201710111018000575721470239.jpg" style="width: 900px; height: 602px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>(Photo/CGTN)</em></p> <p> "There are many artists like Wu Ming working in Dunhuang, some of them (are) outstanding painters. They gave up their personal advancement and came here to copy and guard the Dunhuang art. What they have achieved will be part of Dunhuang's glory. They have gone from selfishness to selflessness," Fei Bo, the director and choreographer of ballet drama "Dunhuang" said.</p> <p> Fei Bo is a young choreographer with the National Ballet of China. He and his teams visited Dunhuang six times during the course of creating the drama. They stayed there for over three months and were deeply touched by the sacrifices of the artists working there. These include the founder of the Dunhuang Academy Chang Shuhong, and his successors Duan Wenjie, Fan Jinshi and Wang Xudong. All of them have spent much of their lives and conquered great difficulties to preserve the Dunhuang art.</p> <p> "I hope this drama would not only expose to the audiences the beauty of the ancient Dunhuang art, but also the devotion of generations of artists and protectors working there. The thousand-year mural paintings will come alive with through human beings' devotion," Fei explained.</p> <p> The choreographers carefully studied the Dunhuang art and consulted with the staff of the academy. They altered the ballet 28 times before everyone was happy with the final version.</p> <p> Music is an integral part of the ballet drama. Guo Wenjing is the composer behind the solemn and stirring melodies tailor-made for the play. Performed by an orchestra, the music is drips with historical thickness as well as sentimental romance.</p> <p> "This work is my most romantic one. The audience might feel the powerful presentation of the folk instrument, the panpipes. It combines well with the western instruments and the orchestra as a whole. It brings the alive images of the flying Apsaras. I hope the music expresses the beauty of the art and the dreams of its protectors. I composed the work with great zeal," Guo said.</p> <p> After the show's debut, the National Ballet of China collected suggestions and opinions from both the audience and experts. It intends to make any necessary changes before a world tour next year, offering people across the globe a chance to enjoy the unique charm of the Dunhuang art in the style of ballet.&nbsp;</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: CNTV</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ BRICS nations to release first coproduced movie ]]></title>
	<news_id>9278068</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1010/c90000-9278068.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 15:48:46 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1010/FOREIGN201710101534000133001765208.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 338px;" /></p> <p> Jointly produced by directors from five BRICS nations, Where Has Time Gone, a movie that ponders the eternal puzzle of time, is expected to be a smash hit in China’s box office on Oct. 19.</p> <p> The 110-minute anthology of five short films is the first coproduced artwork by BRICS nations. The directors, including Jia Zhangke from China, Aleksey Fedorchenko from Russia, Walter Salles from Brazil, Jahmil X.T. Qubeka from South Africa, and Madhur Bhandarkar from India, have created an unprecedented masterpiece that demonstrates the deep communication and cooperation in the film industry among BRICS countries.</p> <p> “Time appears to be a common theme for the five nations, as all of them are experiencing fast economic development and enormous social change. By discussing the theme of time, we want to focus on the change of individual’s emotions and social groups’ living conditions,” Jia told Guangming Daily.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1010/FOREIGN201710101534000283877781737.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 392px;" /></p> <p> Heated topics concerning the countries’ different national conditions have also been discussed in the anthology. In the Chinese short film Revive, the country’s second child phenomenon has been highlighted, while in the Brazilian clip, When the Earth Trembles, the collapse of a dam ignites human’s reverence to life and hope to future.</p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1010/FOREIGN201710101534000444297351196.jpeg" style="width: 600px; height: 325px;" /></p> <p> “Though we are different from each other, we still share many things in common. We all follow the steps of time, and this is something that all humans can understand,” said Jahmil.</p> <p> According to Guangming Daily, the coproduced film has provided a new chance for the BRICS nations’ cultural exchange and cooperation. China plans to coproduce a movie with other BRICS nations annually until 2021, making art coproduction a critical cultural activity of the BRICS cooperative mechanism.</p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
<item>
	<title><![CDATA[ Farmer loves performing acrobatics using common tools and objects ]]></title>
	<news_id>9277955</news_id>
	<link>http://english.people.com.cn/n3/2017/1010/c90000-9277955.html</link>
	<pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 14:41:12 +0800</pubDate>
	<description><![CDATA[  ...]]></description>
	<full-text><![CDATA[ <p style="text-align: center;"> <script src="http://tv.people.com.cn/img/player/v.js"></script><script>showPlayer({id:"/pvservice/xml/2017/10/10/3f6a310c-5520-4cca-99c1-23e99a74a16a.xml",width:800,height:495});</script></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <img alt="" src="/NMediaFile/2017/1010/FOREIGN201710101432000571940107097.jpg" style="width: 600px; height: 358px;" /></p> <p style="text-align: center;"> <em>Farmer loves performing acrobatics using common tools and objects</em></p> <p id='org_name'>Source: People's Daily Online</p> ]]></full-text>
</item>
	</channel>
</rss>